<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Hello World</title>
    <link>/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Hello World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 16:56:21 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Angular 9 CRM Starter Project</title>
      <link>/projects/angular-crm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 16:56:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/angular-crm/</guid>
      <description>Key Takeaways  Angular 9 is here now. Angular Material 9 is ready as well. Reusable starter project  Summary Ng-Crm &amp;gt; A reusable CRM starter project for real-world business based on Angular 9, Angular-Material 9.x.
This project was generated with Angular CLI version 9.x. The goal of this project is to create reusable project for real-world business. To achieve this target, we need a solution which includes simple authentication process, restful API feature with token support and simple but elegant UI design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Docker Kits</title>
      <link>/projects/docker-toolkits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 16:56:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/docker-toolkits/</guid>
      <description>Docker Kits The repository is the collection of kits built on the top of docker image. At the very begiinning, the repository was built for kits used for infrastructure. It is about to expand the scope from infrastructure to simplify the integration test, even build for speical development.
Repository name in Docker Hub: harryh00/docker-kits
Why chooses docker Docker is a tool designed to make it easier to create, deploy, and run applications by using containers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FlatApi - Restful API for python dev</title>
      <link>/projects/python-flat-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 16:56:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/python-flat-api/</guid>
      <description>Summary FlatApi is a zero coding and zero configuration restful API server inspired by Json-Server_ and Eve_. It is designed to be used as fake restful api for development, especially for people want to use Python stack. Setup process is less than 10 seconds.
FlatApi  Zero coding and configuration to setup Restful API FlatApi is designed to use without coding and configuration by default. You just need one config to setup all endpoints you need, then you can use it immediately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angular 4 CRM Project</title>
      <link>/projects/angular4-crm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 16:56:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/angular4-crm/</guid>
      <description>Summary Ng4Crm is reusable CRM project for real-world business based on Angular 4, Angular-Material &amp;amp; Bootstrap 3.
This project starts from a popular starter project AngularClass/AngularStarter. The goal of this project is to create reusable project for real-world business. To achieve this target, we need a solution which should include authentication process, restful API feature with token support and simple but elegant UI design.
Features  This project is built on the top of AngularClass/Angular-Starter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laravel MVC Starter</title>
      <link>/projects/laravel-mvc-starter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 16:56:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/laravel-mvc-starter/</guid>
      <description> Summary This starter is the starting point of laravel 5 MVC project. This application is meant to be used as a starting place for those looking to get their feet wet with laravel.
Overview of project BDD ( Business domain design) +-------+ 0...* 0...* +--------+ 1 0...* +---------+ | tag | --------------- | post | ----- ----- | comment | +-------+ +--------+ +---------+ | 1...* | | 0...* +--------+ | like | +--------+  Structure of starter \path\to\lara-mvc-starter +---app &amp;lt;-// Customized PHP application code | +---Console | +---Exceptions | +---Http | | +---Controllers | | | \---Auth | | \---Middleware | \---Providers +---bootstrap &amp;lt;-// bootstrap the framework and configure autoloading | \---cache +---config &amp;lt;-// application configuration +---database &amp;lt;-// database migration files | +---factories | +---migrations | \---seeds +---public &amp;lt;-// Distributed website folder including Style sheet +---resources &amp;lt;-// View files, Javascripts, localization setting | +---assets | +---lang | \---views | +---admin | +---blog | +---errors | +---layouts | +---other | +---partials | \---vendor | \---pagination +---routes &amp;lt;-// Route definitions and setting +---storage &amp;lt;-//Blade templates, file based sessions, file caches | +---app | | \---public | +---framework | | +---cache | | +---sessions | | \---views | \---logs +---tests \---vendor &amp;lt;-// Laravel framework  Screenshots   Browse Repository </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>React Redux CRM Project</title>
      <link>/projects/react-crm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 16:56:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/react-crm/</guid>
      <description>Summary React-Crm is reusable CRM starter project for real-world business based on React 15.4, React-Redux &amp;amp; Material-UI.
The goal of this starter project is to create reusable project for real-world business. To achieve this target, we need a solution which should include authentication process, restful API feature with token support and simple but elegant UI design.
Features  This project is built on the top of React/Redux.
 The UI part of this project uses Material-UI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vue 2 Admin Project</title>
      <link>/projects/vue2-admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 16:56:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/vue2-admin/</guid>
      <description>Summary Vue2Admin is a fully responsive admin template that is inspired by AdminLTE.
Features  This template is built-in with Vue 2 at the start. It include Vue Resource, Vuex as well. The plugins for this project are loaded with script loader.  Structure of Reetek Vue2Admin path\to\vue2admin +---build &amp;lt;-// webpack files +---config &amp;lt;-// configuration of dev or prod environment +---screenshots +---src &amp;lt;-// vue components | +---components | | +---charts | | +---dashboard | | +---forms | | +---mailbox | | +---misc | | +---pages | | +---tables | | +---ui | | \---widget | \---filters +---static &amp;lt;-// css, dump data, fonts, image files and plugins | +---css | +---data | +---fonts | +---img | | +---credit | | \---stock | \---js | \---plugins &amp;lt;-// plugins for admin dashboard | +---AdminLTE | +---bootstrap | +---bootstrap-slider | +---bootstrap-wysihtml5 | +---chartjs | +---ckeditor | + .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vue 2 CRM Project</title>
      <link>/projects/vue2-crm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 16:56:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/vue2-crm/</guid>
      <description>Summary Vue2Crm is a reusable Vue.js CRM starter project for real-world business based on Vue 2 PWA template with Vuetify.
The goal of this project is to create a reusable project for real-world business. To achieve this target, we need a solution which includes authentication process, restful API feature and simple but elegant UI design.
Features  This starter project is built-in with Vue 2 PWA from scratch. The whole UI is built on the Vuetify It includes Vuex, Axios as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angularjs Webpack ES6 Starter</title>
      <link>/projects/angularjs-webpack-es6-starter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 16:56:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/angularjs-webpack-es6-starter/</guid>
      <description>Summary It simply includes font-awesome, bootstrap for the people who don&amp;rsquo;t want to use boostrap-webpack, font-awesome-webpack. I find it saves us so much effort to create prototype, since we don&amp;rsquo;t need spectacular UI.
 This starter uses angular 1.5 for someone want to build component. This repo follows mvc patterns instead of component pattern. ES6, and ES7 support with babel. Development server with live reload. Production builds with cache busting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zend Framework 2 MVC Starter</title>
      <link>/projects/zf2-mvc-starter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 16:56:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/zf2-mvc-starter/</guid>
      <description>Summary This starter is the starting point of zend framework 2 MVC project. This application is meant to be used as a starting place for those looking to get their feet wet with ZF2.
Features  This starter was built on the zend framework 2.x. This starter uses mysql as database setting by default. Include digest authentication by default. Include font-awesome files. Include Bootstrap 3 without bootstrap-loader. Include html5shiiv.js to support older IE browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Cluster in 5min</title>
      <link>/projects/kube-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/kube-cluster/</guid>
      <description>Kubernetes  Kubernetes (K8s) is an open-source system for automating deployment, scaling, and management of containerized applications.
It groups containers that make up an application into logical units for easy management and discovery. Kubernetes builds upon 15 years of experience of running production workloads at Google, combined with best-of-breed ideas and practices from the community.
 Purpose This project focuses on the training and demonstration. Please DO NOT use it in production environment.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>