<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cloud on Hello World</title>
    <link>/cloud/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cloud on Hello World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Note - 1</title>
      <link>/cloud/aws-note-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/aws-note-1/</guid>
      <description>Root User  Every account has a root user in AWS. A root user is something that&amp;rsquo;s created automatically for you whenever you create an AWS account. Every single AWS account has a root user. The trouble is that root users have unrestricted access to every service and resource that is in AWS inside of your account. The permissions of root user can&amp;rsquo;t be restricted in any way.  Dos and Don&amp;rsquo;ts  You should not be accessing the root account on a regular basis, whether that&amp;rsquo;s daily, weekly, or whatever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Note - 2</title>
      <link>/cloud/aws-note-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/aws-note-2/</guid>
      <description>VPC Amazon Virtual Private Cloud (Amazon VPC) enables you to launch AWS resources into a virtual network that you&amp;rsquo;ve defined. This virtual network closely resembles a traditional network that you&amp;rsquo;d operate in your own data center, with the benefits of using the scalable infrastructure of AWS.
Key concepts  A virtual private cloud (VPC) is a virtual network dedicated to your AWS account. A subnet is a range of IP addresses in your VPC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Note - 3</title>
      <link>/cloud/aws-note-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/aws-note-3/</guid>
      <description>AWS CLI Amazon Virtual Private Cloud (Amazon VPC) enables you to launch AWS resources into a virtual network that you&amp;rsquo;ve defined. This virtual network closely resembles a traditional network that you&amp;rsquo;d operate in your own data center, with the benefits of using the scalable infrastructure of AWS.
Profile Setup A named profile is a collection of settings and credentials that you can apply to a AWS CLI command. When you specify a profile to run a command, the settings and credentials are used to run that command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DigitialOcean Note - 1</title>
      <link>/cloud/digito-note-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/digito-note-1/</guid>
      <description>Droplet DigitalOcean Droplets are Linux-based virtual machines (VMs) that run on top of virtualized hardware. Each Droplet you create is a new server you can use, either standalone or as part of a larger, cloud-based infrastructure.
Prerequisite  Prepare a bank account or credit card Signup DigitalOcean account and activate it Create a new prject  OS Options  Ubuntu FreeBSD Fedora Debian CentOS  Plans and Pricing We offer four different kinds of Droplet plans: one shared CPU plan and three dedicated CPU plans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DigitialOcean Note - 2</title>
      <link>/cloud/digito-note-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/digito-note-2/</guid>
      <description>User Setup Create a new admin user Add a new user # Add new user # set password adduser &amp;lt;admin_user&amp;gt; # user to sudo group usermod -aG sudo &amp;lt;admin_user&amp;gt;  Set SSH access for new user # Switch session to new user su - &amp;lt;admin_user&amp;gt; # navigate to user home cd # Prepare ssh directory mkdir .ssh chmod 700 ~/.ssh # Copy root key sudo cp /root/.ssh/authorized_keys ~/.ssh/authorized_keys chmod 644 /home/&amp;lt;admin_user&amp;gt;/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DigitialOcean Note - 3</title>
      <link>/cloud/digito-note-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/digito-note-3/</guid>
      <description>Here I contineu to setup SSL certificates for all sites on my web host
 UFW UFW, or Uncomplicated Firewall, is a front-end to iptables. Its main goal is to make managing your firewall drop-dead simple and to provide an easy-to-use interface.
DO NOT Enable UFW
 DO NOT enable UFW without reading through the instructions
 Enable IP V6  Open the UFW configuration with vi:
sudo vi /etc/default/ufw  Make sure &amp;ldquo;IPV6&amp;rdquo; is set to &amp;ldquo;yes&amp;rdquo;, like so:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DigitialOcean Note - 4</title>
      <link>/cloud/digito-note-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/digito-note-4/</guid>
      <description>Here I continue to finish the web host setup. The last step of web host setup is to add SSL certificate for each site
 Lets Encrypt To enable HTTPS on your website, you need to get a certificate (a type of file) from a Certificate Authority (CA). Let’s Encrypt is a CA. In order to get a certificate for your website’s domain from Let’s Encrypt, you have to demonstrate control over the domain.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>