<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cloud on Hello World</title>
    <link>/cloud/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cloud on Hello World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Note - 1</title>
      <link>/cloud/aws-note-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/aws-note-1/</guid>
      <description>Root User  Every account has a root user in AWS. A root user is something that&amp;rsquo;s created automatically for you whenever you create an AWS account. Every single AWS account has a root user. The trouble is that root users have unrestricted access to every service and resource that is in AWS inside of your account. The permissions of root user can&amp;rsquo;t be restricted in any way.  Dos and Don&amp;rsquo;ts  You should not be accessing the root account on a regular basis, whether that&amp;rsquo;s daily, weekly, or whatever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Note - 2</title>
      <link>/cloud/aws-note-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/aws-note-2/</guid>
      <description>VPC Amazon Virtual Private Cloud (Amazon VPC) enables you to launch AWS resources into a virtual network that you&amp;rsquo;ve defined. This virtual network closely resembles a traditional network that you&amp;rsquo;d operate in your own data center, with the benefits of using the scalable infrastructure of AWS.
Key concepts  A virtual private cloud (VPC) is a virtual network dedicated to your AWS account. A subnet is a range of IP addresses in your VPC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digitial Ocean Note - 1</title>
      <link>/cloud/digito-note-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/digito-note-1/</guid>
      <description>Droplet DigitalOcean Droplets are Linux-based virtual machines (VMs) that run on top of virtualized hardware. Each Droplet you create is a new server you can use, either standalone or as part of a larger, cloud-based infrastructure.
Prerequisite  Prepare a bank account or credit card Signup DigitalOcean account and activate it Create a new prject  OS Options  Ubuntu FreeBSD Fedora Debian CentOS  Plans and Pricing We offer four different kinds of Droplet plans: one shared CPU plan and three dedicated CPU plans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digitial Ocean Note - 2</title>
      <link>/cloud/digito-note-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/digito-note-2/</guid>
      <description>User Setup Create a new admin user Add a new user # Add new user # set password adduser &amp;lt;admin_user&amp;gt; # user to sudo group usermod -aG sudo &amp;lt;admin_user&amp;gt;  Set SSH access for new user # Switch session to new user su - &amp;lt;admin_user&amp;gt; # navigate to user home cd # Prepare ssh directory mkdir .ssh chmod 700 ~/.ssh # Copy root key sudo cp /root/.ssh/authorized_keys ~/.ssh/authorized_keys chmod 644 /home/&amp;lt;admin_user&amp;gt;/.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>