<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Frameworks on Hello World</title>
    <link>/frameworks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Frameworks on Hello World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 16:56:21 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/frameworks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CNTK Note - 1</title>
      <link>/frameworks/cntk-notes-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 16:56:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/frameworks/cntk-notes-1/</guid>
      <description> Prerequisites  You are using Windows 7 or higher version You are using Anaconda to setup the environment  Create CNTK virtual environment use follow command to remove existing virtual environment  conda remove -n cntk --all conda create -n cntk  Activate virtual environment and install CNTK activate cntk pip install https://cntk.ai/PythonWheel/CPU-Only/cntk-2.0rc3-cp36-cp36m-win_amd64.whl  Test CNTK python &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; import cntk &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; cntk.__version__ &#39;2.0rc3&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tensorflow Note - 1</title>
      <link>/frameworks/tensorflow-notes-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 16:56:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/frameworks/tensorflow-notes-1/</guid>
      <description>TensorFlow is an end-to-end open source platform for machine learning. It has a comprehensive, flexible ecosystem of tools, libraries and community resources that lets researchers push the state-of-the-art in ML and developers easily build and deploy ML powered applications.
 Prerequisites  You are using Ubuntu 16 Your machine has Nvidia GPU card installed If you are using Ubuntu 14, the installation of CUDA and cuDNN will be a bit different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tensorflow Note - 2</title>
      <link>/frameworks/tensorflow-notes-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 16:56:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/frameworks/tensorflow-notes-2/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites  You are using Windows 7 or higher version You are using Anaconda to setup the environment  Install Anaconda  Anaconda® is a package manager, an environment manager, a Python/R data science distribution, and a collection of over 1,500+ open source packages. Anaconda is free and easy to install, and it offers free community support.
  Please download Anaconda from the official site   Create tensorflow virtualenv with python 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Web Framework</title>
      <link>/frameworks/php-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 11:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/frameworks/php-web/</guid>
      <description>Here we are going to explore some PHP web frameworks.
 PHP development environment setup Install PHP 5.6.x  Please find the instruction from home page  Composer Linux  Use curl -s https://getcomposer.org/installer | php -- to install composer on Linux use &amp;lsquo;composer -v &amp;rsquo; to verify.  Windows  Download the composer and install php on your PC Use composer -v to verify the composer is ready.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Web Framework</title>
      <link>/frameworks/python-django/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/frameworks/python-django/</guid>
      <description>Django is a high-level Python Web framework that encourages rapid development and clean, pragmatic design. Built by experienced developers, it takes care of much of the hassle of Web development, so you can focus on writing your app without needing to reinvent the wheel. It’s free and open source.
 Install Python, pip and virtualenv  Windows: Please find in from Home Page
 Ubuntu: Please find it from Ubuntu setup</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>