<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hello World</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Hello World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 14:59:31 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Golang Note - 1</title>
      <link>/coding/golang/go-note-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/golang/go-note-1/</guid>
      <description>Go Introduction  Golang&amp;rsquo;s popularity is skyrocketing. The thriving of Docker and Kubernetes push the Golang to a higher level.
Go is easy to become functional with and appropriate for junior developers to work on. Also, having a language that encourages readability and comprehension is extremely useful. The mixture of duck typing (via interfaces) and convenience features such as &amp;ldquo;:=&amp;rdquo; for short variable declarations give Go the feel of a dynamically typed language while retaining the positives of a strongly typed one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Note 1</title>
      <link>/coding/python/python-note-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/python/python-note-1/</guid>
      <description>Package &amp;amp; Module  Packages are modules that contain other modules. Packages are generally implemented as directories containing a special __init__.py file. The __init__.py file is executed when the package is imported. Packages can contain sub packages which themselves are implemented with __init__.py files in directories. The module objects for packages have a __path__ attribute.  sys.path  List of directories which Python searches for modules.
# list directories &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;import sys &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;sys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golang Note - 2</title>
      <link>/coding/golang/go-note-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/golang/go-note-2/</guid>
      <description>Map  Maps are a special kind of data structure: an unordered collection of pairs of items, where one element of the pair is the key, and the other element, associated with the key, is the data or the value, hence they are also called associative arrays or dictionaries.
 The key type can be any type for which the operations == and != are defined, like string, int, float.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Note 2</title>
      <link>/coding/python/python-note-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/python/python-note-2/</guid>
      <description>Closure &amp;amp; Decorator LEGB rules  Local, Enclosing, Gloable, Built-in  Local function  Useful for specialized, one-off functions Aid in code organization and readability Similar to lambdas, but more general May contain multiple expressions May contain statements  Closure  Closure maintain references to objects from earlier scopes LEGB does not apply when making new bindings Usage of nonlocal
 Example
def make_timer(): last_called = None def elapsed(): nonlocal last_called now = time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golang Note - 3</title>
      <link>/coding/golang/go-note-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/golang/go-note-3/</guid>
      <description>Struct  Go supports user-defined or custom types in the form of alias types or structs. A struct tries to represent a real-world entity with its properties. Structs are composite types, to use when you want to define a type which consist of a number of properties, each having their own type and value, grouping pieces of data together.
 Struct with tags  A field in a struct can, apart from a name and a type, also optionally have a tag: this is a string attached to the field, which could be documentation or some other important label.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Note 3</title>
      <link>/coding/python/python-note-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/python/python-note-3/</guid>
      <description>String &amp;amp; Representation str()  print() -&amp;gt; str() -&amp;gt; __str(self)__ Fallback to repr(). By default, str() simply calls repr() Produces a readable, human-friendly representation of an object It is also the string constructor  repr()  Exactness is more important than human-friendliness Suited for debugging. Unambiguous, precise, include type Includes identifying information. Generally best for logging and developers The default repr() is not very helpful As a rule, you should always write a repr() for your classes standard library reprlib.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golang Note - 4</title>
      <link>/coding/golang/go-note-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/golang/go-note-4/</guid>
      <description>IO - Read &amp;amp; Write Read from user input var ( firstName, lastName, s string i int f float32 input = &amp;quot;56.12 / 5212 / Go&amp;quot; format = &amp;quot;%f / %d / %s&amp;quot; ) func main() { fmt.Println(&amp;quot;Please enter your full name: &amp;quot;) fmt.Scanln(&amp;amp;firstName, &amp;amp;lastName) // fmt.Scanf(&amp;quot;%s %s&amp;quot;, &amp;amp;firstName, &amp;amp;lastName) fmt.Printf(&amp;quot;Hi %s %s!\n&amp;quot;, firstName, lastName) // Hi Chris Naegels fmt.Sscanf(input, format, &amp;amp;f, &amp;amp;i, &amp;amp;s) fmt.Println(&amp;quot;From the string we read: &amp;quot;, f, i, s) // ouwtput: From the string we read: 56.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Note 4</title>
      <link>/coding/python/python-note-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/python/python-note-4/</guid>
      <description>Iterables &amp;amp; Iteration Comprehensions  Comprehensions can process more than one input sequence Multiple input sequences in comprehensions work like nested for-loops Comprehensions can also have multiple if-clauses interspersed with the for-clauses Later clauses in a comprehension can reference variables bound in earlier clauses Comprehension can also appear in the result expression of a comprehension, resulting in nested sequences  Example ## Comprehensions &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; points [(0, 0), (0, 1), (0, 2), (0, 3), (1, 0), (1, 1), (1, 2), (1, 3), (2, 0), (2, 1), (2, 2), (2, 3)] &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; points_c=[(x,y) for x in range(3) for y in range(4) ] &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; points_c [(0, 0), (0, 1), (0, 2), (0, 3), (1, 0), (1, 1), (1, 2), (1, 3), (2, 0), (2, 1), (2, 2), (2, 3)] &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; points_d=[(x,y) .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golang Note - 5</title>
      <link>/coding/golang/go-note-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/golang/go-note-5/</guid>
      <description>Error handling  Go does not have an exception mechanism, like the try/catch in Java or .NET for instance: you cannot throw exceptions. Instead it has a defer-panic-and-recover mechanism.
 The Go way to handle errors is for functions and methods to return an error object as their only or last return value—or nil if no error occurred—and for calling functions to always check the error they receive.
 Handle the errors and return from the function in which the error occurred with an error message to the user: that way if something does go wrong, your program will continue to function and the user will be notified.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Note 5</title>
      <link>/coding/python/python-note-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/python/python-note-5/</guid>
      <description>Inheritance &amp;amp; Polymorphism  Specify single inheritance by putting a base class in parentheses after defining a class&amp;rsquo;s name Subclasses have all of the methods of their base class It&amp;rsquo;s often best to explicitly call a base class initializer from a subclass&amp;rsquo;s initializer If a class with a single base class doesn&amp;rsquo;t define an initializer, the base class&amp;rsquo;s initializer will be called automatically on construction Python treats __init__() like any other method Base class __init__() is not called if overridden Use super() to call base class __init__() isinstance() takes an object as its first argument and a type as its second isinstance() determines if its first argument is an instance of the second argument, or any subclass of the second argument isinstance() can accept a tuple of types as its second argument, in which it returns True if the first argument is of any of those types Checking for specific types is rare in Python and is sometimes regarded as bad design isinstance() determines if its first argument is a direct or indirect subclass of, or the same type as, the second argument Multiple inheritance means having more than one direct base class You declare multiple base classes with a comma-separated list of class names in parentheses after a class&amp;rsquo;s name in a class definition A class can have as many base classes as you want Python uses a well-defined &amp;ldquo;method resolution order&amp;rdquo; to resolve methods at runtime If a multiply-inheriting class defines no initializer, Python will automatically call the initializer of its first base class on construction __bases__ is a tuple of types on a class object which defines the base classes for the class __bases__ is in the same order as in the class definition __bases__ is populated for both single and multiple inheritance Method resolution order defines the order in which Python will search an inheritance graph for methods MRO is short for Method Resolution Order MRO is stored as a tuple of types in the __mro__ attribute of a class The mro() method on type objects returns the contents of __mro__ as a list To resolve a method, Python uses the first entry in a class&amp;rsquo;s MRO which has the requested method MRO is dependent on base class declaration order MRO is calculated by Python using the C3 algorithm MRO honors base-class ordering from class definitions MRO puts subclasses before base classes The relative order of classes in an MRO is consistent across all classes It is possible to specify an inconsistent base class ordering, in which case Python will raise a TypeError when the class definition is reached super() operates by using the elements in an MRO that come after some specified type super() returns a proxy object which forwards calls to the correct objects There are two distinct types of super() proxies, bound and unbound Unbound super() proxies are primarily used for implementing other Python features Bound proxies can be bound to either class objects or instances Calling super() with a base-class and derived-class argument returns a proxy bound to a class Calling super() with a class and an instance of that class returns a proxy bound to an instance A super() proxy takes the MRO of its second argument (or the type of its second argument), finds the first argument in that MRO, and uses everything after it in the MRO for method resolution Since class-bound proxies aren&amp;rsquo;t bound to an instance, you can’t directly call instance methods that they resolve for you However, classmethods resolved by class-bound proxies can be called directly Python will raise a TypeError if the second argument is not a subclass or instance of the first argument Inappropriate use of super() can violate some design constraints * Calling super() with no arguments inside an instance method produces an instance-bound proxy Calling super() with no arguments inside a classmethod produces a class-bound proxy In both cases, the no-argument form of super() is the same as calling super() with the method&amp;rsquo;s class as the first argument and the method&amp;rsquo;s first argument as the second Since super() works on MROs and not just a class&amp;rsquo;s base classes, class can be designed to cooperate without prior knowledge of one another The class object is at the core of Python&amp;rsquo;s object model object is the ultimate base class for all other classes in Python If you don&amp;rsquo;t specify a base class for a class, Python automatically uses object as the base Because object is in every class&amp;rsquo;s inheritance graph, it shows up in every MRO.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golang Note - 6</title>
      <link>/coding/golang/go-note-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/golang/go-note-6/</guid>
      <description>Goroutine  A goroutine is implemented as a function or method (this can also be an anonymous or lambda function) and called (invoked) with the keyword go. This starts the function running in parallel with the current computation but in the same address space and with its own stack.
 Go’s concurrency primitives provide the basis for a good concurrency program design: expressing program structure so as to represent independently executing actions; so Go’s emphasis is not in the 1 st place on parallelism: concurrent programs may or may not be parallel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Note 6</title>
      <link>/coding/python/python-note-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/python/python-note-6/</guid>
      <description>Collection Collection protocols  To implement a protocol, objects must support certain operations. Most collections implement container, sized and iterable. All except dict and set are sequences Container: membership testing using in and not in Sized: Determine number of elements with len(s) Iterable: Can produce an iterator with iter(s), e.g.
 for item in iterable: do_something(item) `len(s)`  Sequence:
 Retrieve elements by index, e.g. item = seq[index] Find items by value index = seq.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golang Note - 7</title>
      <link>/coding/golang/go-note-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/golang/go-note-7/</guid>
      <description>Channel directionality  A channel type may be annotated to specify that it may only send or only receive
var send_only chan&amp;lt;- int // channel can only receive data var recv_only &amp;lt;-chan int // channel can only send data  Receive-only channels ( &amp;lt;-chan T ) cannot be closed, because closing a channel is intended as a way for a sender to signal that no more values will be sent to the channel, so it has no meaning for receive-only channels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Note 7</title>
      <link>/coding/python/python-note-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/python/python-note-7/</guid>
      <description>Exception &amp;amp; Assertion  Avoid bad practices in Python exception handling. Always specify an exception type with except, but don&amp;rsquo;t be too general.
 Don&amp;rsquo;t Use Assertions for checking arguments EXamples
 lookup exception
def lookups(): s = [1, 4, 6] try: item = s[5] except LookupError: print(&amp;quot;Handled IndexError&amp;quot;) d = dict(a=65, b=66, c=67) try: value = d[&#39;x&#39;] except LookupError: print(&amp;quot;Handled KeyError&amp;quot;) if __name__ == &#39;__main__&#39;: lookups() ## test result ## Handled IndexError ## Handled KeyError  unicode exception</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golang Note - 8</title>
      <link>/coding/golang/go-note-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/golang/go-note-8/</guid>
      <description>Package  Package is a way to structure code: a program is constructed as a “package” (often abbreviated as pkg), which may use facilities from other packages. Every go-file belongs to one (and only one) package (like a library or namespace in other languages). Many different .go files can belong to one package, so the filename(s) and package name are generally not the same.
 The package to which the code-file belongs must be indicated on the first line, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Note 8</title>
      <link>/coding/python/python-note-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/python/python-note-8/</guid>
      <description>Context managers context manager  context manager an object designed to be used in a with-statement
with context-manager: body with context-manager: context-manager.begin() body context-manager.end() with context-manager: setup() body teardown() with context-manager: context-manager.begin() body context-manager.end() with context-manager: allocation() body deallocation() with context-manager: enter() body exit()  A context-manager ensures that resources are properly and automatically managed
 enter() prepares the manager for use exit() cleans it up  Context-manager Protocol</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golang Note - 9</title>
      <link>/coding/golang/go-note-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/golang/go-note-9/</guid>
      <description>Shadowing  Hiding (shadowing) a variable by misusing short declaration.
 Such mistakes occur mostly inside the if-body or for-loop
var remember bool = false if something { remember := true // Wrong. } // use remember func shadow() (err error) { x, err := check1() // x is created; err is assigned to if err != nil { return // err correctly returned } if y, err := check2(x); err !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Note 9</title>
      <link>/coding/python/python-note-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/python/python-note-9/</guid>
      <description>ABC - Abstract Base Classes Abstract base classes complement duck-typing by providing a way to define interfaces when other techniques like hasattr() would be clumsy or subtly wrong (for example with magic methods). ABCs introduce virtual subclasses, which are classes that don’t inherit from a class but are still recognized by isinstance() and issubclass(); see the abc module documentation. Python comes with many built-in ABCs for data structures (in the collections module), numbers (in the numbers module), and streams (in the io module).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Console App</title>
      <link>/coding/c-sharp/csharp-note-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/c-sharp/csharp-note-1/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites  .Net Framework has been install to your PC or laptop
 Create simple .net project without Visual Studio Prerequisites  The version of .Net Framework on your PC is 2.0+ or later Assume the path of .Net Frameowork is c:\Windows\Microsfot.Net\Frameowork\v2.0.50727  Simple C# project Create a proejct named csharp-project md csharp-project cd csharp-project md bin src echo.&amp;gt;csharp-project.proj echo.&amp;gt;src\helloworld.cs   Update config file csharp-project.proj as below
&amp;lt;Project DefaultTargets = &amp;quot;Compile&amp;quot; xmlns=&amp;quot;http://schemas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golang Note - 10</title>
      <link>/coding/golang/go-note-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/golang/go-note-10/</guid>
      <description>Template  Package template implements data-driven templates for generating textual output. Templates are executed by applying them to a data structure. Annotations in the template refer to elements of the data structure (typically a field of a struct or a key in a map) to control execution and derive values to be displayed. Execution of the template walks the structure and sets the cursor, represented by a period &amp;lsquo;.&amp;rsquo; and called &amp;ldquo;dot&amp;rdquo;, to the value at the current location in the structure as execution proceeds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golang Note - 20</title>
      <link>/coding/golang/go-note-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/golang/go-note-20/</guid>
      <description>Strings Change a character  How to change a character in a string
str:=&amp;quot;hello&amp;quot; c:=[]byte(s) c[0]=’c’ s2:= string(c) // s2 == &amp;quot;cello&amp;quot;   Substring  How to take a part(substring) of a string str
substr := str[n:m]   for-loop  How to loop over a string str with for or for-range:
// gives only the bytes: for i:=0; i &amp;lt; len(str); i++ { … = str[i] } // gives the Unicode characters: for ix, ch := range str { // … }   bytes of str  Number of bytes in a string str</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golang Note - 21</title>
      <link>/coding/golang/go-note-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/golang/go-note-21/</guid>
      <description>Goroutines and channels  Performance advice:   A rule of thumb if you use parallelism to gain efficiency over serial computation: the amount of work done inside goroutine has to be much higher than the costs associated with creating goroutines and sending data back and forth between them.
 Using buffered channels  Using buffered channels for performance:
A buffered channel can easily double its throughput, depending on the context the performance gain can be 10x or more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golang Note - 22</title>
      <link>/coding/golang/go-note-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/golang/go-note-22/</guid>
      <description>Error  How to stop a program when an error occurs:
if err != nil { fmt.Printf(&amp;quot;Program stopping with error %v&amp;quot;, err) os.Exit(1) } // OR : if err != nil { panic(&amp;quot;ERROR occurred: &amp;quot; + err.Error()) }   Performance best practices and advice  Use the initializing declaration form := wherever possible (in functions). Use bytes if possible instead of strings Use slices instead of arrays. Use arrays or slices instead of a map where possible (see ref.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golang snippets</title>
      <link>/coding/golang/go-note-99/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/golang/go-note-99/</guid>
      <description>Convenient logging methods Stringer package main import ( &amp;quot;fmt&amp;quot; ) // Animal has a Name and an Age to represent an animal. type Animal struct { Name string Age uint } // String makes Animal satisfy the Stringer interface. func (a Animal) String() string { return fmt.Sprintf(&amp;quot;%v (%d)&amp;quot;, a.Name, a.Age) } func main() { a := Animal{ Name: &amp;quot;Gopher&amp;quot;, Age: 2, } fmt.Println(a) // Gopher (2) }  GoStringer package main import ( &amp;quot;fmt&amp;quot; ) // Address has a City, State and a Country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dual Boot Windows 10 &amp; Ubuntu 18</title>
      <link>/os/dual-boot-win10-ubuntu18/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/dual-boot-win10-ubuntu18/</guid>
      <description>Dual boot Ubuntu 18 with Windows 10  I have a couple Linux workstations, but all of them are old PC or laptop. Today I get a chance to test Ubuntu on a brand new laptop. Here I are going to write down all I did to create this dual boot laptop
 Caution The laptop I worked on is Lenovo IdeaPad S model with UEFI firmware, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean all Lenovo laptops will work in the same way, not to mention other brand&amp;rsquo;s laptop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu Desktop 18 LTS note</title>
      <link>/os/ubuntu-desktop-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/ubuntu-desktop-18/</guid>
      <description>Prelude  This article is mainly to record the stuff to do post Ubuntu Desktop 18.04 Installation.
 Purpose All actions post installation is to make the Ubuntu Desktop a wonderful toolkit for developer.
Prerequisite  Install all essentials
sudo apt install -y git curl sudo apt-get install -y apt-transport-https ca-certificates gnupg-agent sudo apt install -y software-properties-common   Install &amp;amp; Setup Zsh  Install Zsh
sudo apt install -y zsh  Setup Zsh</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi setup</title>
      <link>/os/raspberrypi-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/raspberrypi-notes/</guid>
      <description>Prelude
 *This note is mainly to record how to setup Raspberry Pi as file server.
 Prerequisites  You have a Raspberry Pi with pre-installed raspbian SD card You are happy to get your hands dirty You have some basic computer concept. RPi is short for Raspberry Pi
  My Raspberry Pi is a bit old I only have the RPi 1 model B with pre-installed raspbian SD card in place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lubuntu 16 desktop</title>
      <link>/os/lubuntu16-desktop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 13:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/lubuntu16-desktop/</guid>
      <description>Prelude
 There is no big difference against setup between Lubuntu and Ubuntu. I just want to keep a latest version of setup for myself as reference
 Prerequisites  You have Lubuntu 16 in place Internet is available  UFW setup sudo ufw enable sudo ufw allow 80/tcp sudo ufw allow ssh sudo ufw allow 443/tcp sudo ufw allow 8000/tcp  SSH server setup !!! For production environment, SSH should be secured by the CA</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Practices</title>
      <link>/blogs/k8s-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 11:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/k8s-notes/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites Install KVM or VirtualBox Install Ubuntu / Debian on KVM or VirtualBox Install Minikube Check K8s version and config kubectl version kubectl config kubectl cluster-info  Get / Describe command kubectl get ndoes kubectl get pods kubectl get deployments kubectl get services kubectl describe pods  Deploy hello-world node demo app  Deploy a demo app
kubectl run kubernetes-bootcamp --image=gcr.io/google-samples/kubernetes-bootcamp:v1 --port=8080 # View deployments and pods kubectl get deployments kubectl get pods  Pods that are running inside Kubernetes are running on a private, isolated network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grub Trouble Shooting</title>
      <link>/os/grub-trouble-shooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/grub-trouble-shooting/</guid>
      <description>Update Grub Menu for dual OS boot Change BIOS * Start your PC by pressing a pressing a special function key (usually F12, F10 or F2 depending on the vendor specifications). * Some PC&amp;rsquo;s BIOS has BOOT tab option, open the BOOT tab, you will find the OS Boot Manager. It is the simplest way to fix the issue. If your PC&amp;rsquo;s BIOS has no such setting feature, you need to check the next section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FlatApi - Restful API for python dev</title>
      <link>/projects/python-flat-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 16:56:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/python-flat-api/</guid>
      <description>Summary FlatApi is a zero coding and zero configuration restful API server inspired by Json-Server_ and Eve_. It is designed to be used as fake restful api for development, especially for people want to use Python stack. Setup process is less than 10 seconds.
FlatApi  Zero coding and configuration to setup Restful API FlatApi is designed to use without coding and configuration by default. You just need one config to setup all endpoints you need, then you can use it immediately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angular vs React vs Vue</title>
      <link>/blogs/vue-ng-react/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 16:56:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/vue-ng-react/</guid>
      <description>Angular, React, Vue as most popular JavaScript frameworks at present, we just discuss Angular 1.x, Angular 2 / 4, React 15+ (Redux), and Vue 2+ here. There is no Angular 3, if you have not noticed before.
 Client side is a battle field In past 6–8 years, the Restful API has been accepted as one of standard web interfaces for most web applications, solution architect can simply add REST API on the top of existing web layer or business layer to provide REST API and support multiple client devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu 16 server note</title>
      <link>/os/ubuntu-server-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/ubuntu-server-16/</guid>
      <description>Prelude
 This article is mainly to help experienced user install and setup Ubuntu 16 LTS Server. If you are looking for the information for Ubuntu 14, please go to the page Ubuntu 14 server setup
 Prerequisites  You are familiar with Ubuntu, at least you have some experience working on Linux system. You are familiar with basic bash/shell command  Wireless Setup  If you install ubuntu server on a laptop, you might end up to setup the wifi first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a blog site on GitHub Pages</title>
      <link>/blogs/create-a-blog-on-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/create-a-blog-on-github/</guid>
      <description>If you use Unix-style system, I recommend you to follow the Hugo Quick Start and Hosting on GitHub Pages to create a blog to GitHub pages within 5 mins.
When I decided to use hugo to create a blog on GitHub pages from my windows machine, it took me over 30 mins. I hope this blog can help someone want to do sth similar within Windows environment.*
 Step 1 - Plan and prepare Prerequisite  You already have Hugo on your computer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CentOS 7 Server note</title>
      <link>/os/centos-server-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 10:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/centos-server-7/</guid>
      <description>Prelude
 This article is mainly to help experienced user install and setup CentOS 7 Server.
 Prerequisites  You are familiar with CentOS, at least you have some experience working on Linux system. You are familiar with basic bash/shell command  Things to do after installing CentOS server  How to setup your server  Firewall setup sudo firewall-cmd --permanent --add-port=22/tcp sudo firewall-cmd --permanent --add-port=21/tcp sudo firewall-cmd --permanent --add-port=80/tcp sudo firewall-cmd --permanent --add-port=443/tcp sudo firewall-cmd --permanent --add-port=8080/tcp sudo firewall-cmd --reload  SSH server setup !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angular 4 CRM Project</title>
      <link>/projects/angular4-crm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 16:56:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/angular4-crm/</guid>
      <description>Summary Ng4Crm is reusable CRM project for real-world business based on Angular 4, Angular-Material &amp;amp; Bootstrap 3.
This project starts from a popular starter project AngularClass/AngularStarter. The goal of this project is to create reusable project for real-world business. To achieve this target, we need a solution which should include authentication process, restful API feature with token support and simple but elegant UI design.
Features  This project is built on the top of AngularClass/Angular-Starter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CNTK Note - 1</title>
      <link>/frameworks/cntk-notes-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 16:56:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/frameworks/cntk-notes-1/</guid>
      <description> Prerequisites  You are using Windows 7 or higher version You are using Anaconda to setup the environment  Create CNTK virtual environment use follow command to remove existing virtual environment  conda remove -n cntk --all conda create -n cntk  Activate virtual environment and install CNTK activate cntk pip install https://cntk.ai/PythonWheel/CPU-Only/cntk-2.0rc3-cp36-cp36m-win_amd64.whl  Test CNTK python &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; import cntk &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; cntk.__version__ &#39;2.0rc3&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laravel MVC Starter</title>
      <link>/projects/laravel-mvc-starter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 16:56:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/laravel-mvc-starter/</guid>
      <description> Summary This starter is the starting point of laravel 5 MVC project. This application is meant to be used as a starting place for those looking to get their feet wet with laravel.
Overview of project BDD ( Business domain design) +-------+ 0...* 0...* +--------+ 1 0...* +---------+ | tag | --------------- | post | ----- ----- | comment | +-------+ +--------+ +---------+ | 1...* | | 0...* +--------+ | like | +--------+  Structure of starter \path\to\lara-mvc-starter +---app &amp;lt;-// Customized PHP application code | +---Console | +---Exceptions | +---Http | | +---Controllers | | | \---Auth | | \---Middleware | \---Providers +---bootstrap &amp;lt;-// bootstrap the framework and configure autoloading | \---cache +---config &amp;lt;-// application configuration +---database &amp;lt;-// database migration files | +---factories | +---migrations | \---seeds +---public &amp;lt;-// Distributed website folder including Style sheet +---resources &amp;lt;-// View files, Javascripts, localization setting | +---assets | +---lang | \---views | +---admin | +---blog | +---errors | +---layouts | +---other | +---partials | \---vendor | \---pagination +---routes &amp;lt;-// Route definitions and setting +---storage &amp;lt;-//Blade templates, file based sessions, file caches | +---app | | \---public | +---framework | | +---cache | | +---sessions | | \---views | \---logs +---tests \---vendor &amp;lt;-// Laravel framework  Screenshots   Browse Repository </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>React Redux CRM Project</title>
      <link>/projects/react-crm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 16:56:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/react-crm/</guid>
      <description>Summary React-Crm is reusable CRM starter project for real-world business based on React 15.4, React-Redux &amp;amp; Material-UI.
The goal of this starter project is to create reusable project for real-world business. To achieve this target, we need a solution which should include authentication process, restful API feature with token support and simple but elegant UI design.
Features  This project is built on the top of React/Redux.
 The UI part of this project uses Material-UI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tensorflow Note - 1</title>
      <link>/frameworks/tensorflow-notes-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 16:56:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/frameworks/tensorflow-notes-1/</guid>
      <description>TensorFlow is an end-to-end open source platform for machine learning. It has a comprehensive, flexible ecosystem of tools, libraries and community resources that lets researchers push the state-of-the-art in ML and developers easily build and deploy ML powered applications.
 Prerequisites  You are using Ubuntu 16 Your machine has Nvidia GPU card installed If you are using Ubuntu 14, the installation of CUDA and cuDNN will be a bit different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tensorflow Note - 2</title>
      <link>/frameworks/tensorflow-notes-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 16:56:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/frameworks/tensorflow-notes-2/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites  You are using Windows 7 or higher version You are using Anaconda to setup the environment  Install Anaconda  Anaconda® is a package manager, an environment manager, a Python/R data science distribution, and a collection of over 1,500+ open source packages. Anaconda is free and easy to install, and it offers free community support.
  Please download Anaconda from the official site   Create tensorflow virtualenv with python 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vue 2 Admin Project</title>
      <link>/projects/vue2-admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 16:56:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/vue2-admin/</guid>
      <description>Summary Vue2Admin is a fully responsive admin template that is inspired by AdminLTE.
Features  This template is built-in with Vue 2 at the start. It include Vue Resource, Vuex as well. The plugins for this project are loaded with script loader.  Structure of Reetek Vue2Admin path\to\vue2admin +---build &amp;lt;-// webpack files +---config &amp;lt;-// configuration of dev or prod environment +---screenshots +---src &amp;lt;-// vue components | +---components | | +---charts | | +---dashboard | | +---forms | | +---mailbox | | +---misc | | +---pages | | +---tables | | +---ui | | \---widget | \---filters +---static &amp;lt;-// css, dump data, fonts, image files and plugins | +---css | +---data | +---fonts | +---img | | +---credit | | \---stock | \---js | \---plugins &amp;lt;-// plugins for admin dashboard | +---AdminLTE | +---bootstrap | +---bootstrap-slider | +---bootstrap-wysihtml5 | +---chartjs | +---ckeditor | + .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vue 2 CRM Project</title>
      <link>/projects/vue2-crm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 16:56:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/vue2-crm/</guid>
      <description>Summary Vue2Crm is a reusable Vue.js CRM starter project for real-world business based on Vue 2 PWA template with Vuetify.
The goal of this project is to create a reusable project for real-world business. To achieve this target, we need a solution which includes authentication process, restful API feature and simple but elegant UI design.
Features  This starter project is built-in with Vue 2 PWA from scratch. The whole UI is built on the Vuetify It includes Vuex, Axios as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angularjs Webpack ES6 Starter</title>
      <link>/projects/angularjs-webpack-es6-starter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 16:56:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/angularjs-webpack-es6-starter/</guid>
      <description>Summary It simply includes font-awesome, bootstrap for the people who don&amp;rsquo;t want to use boostrap-webpack, font-awesome-webpack. I find it saves us so much effort to create prototype, since we don&amp;rsquo;t need spectacular UI.
 This starter uses angular 1.5 for someone want to build component. This repo follows mvc patterns instead of component pattern. ES6, and ES7 support with babel. Development server with live reload. Production builds with cache busting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Practices</title>
      <link>/blogs/git-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 11:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/git-notes/</guid>
      <description>Create a new branch with git Create the branch locally  Create the branch on your local machine and switch in this branch
$ git checkout -b [name_of_your_new_branch]   Push the branch  Push the branch on git-repository (Github, Bitbucket)
$ git push origin [name_of_your_new_branch]   When you want to commit something in your branch, be sure to be in your branch.
Manage branches (Push, Fetch &amp;amp; Merge) List all branches</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Web Framework</title>
      <link>/frameworks/php-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 11:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/frameworks/php-web/</guid>
      <description>Here we are going to explore some PHP web frameworks.
 PHP development environment setup Install PHP 5.6.x  Please find the instruction from home page  Composer Linux  Use curl -s https://getcomposer.org/installer | php -- to install composer on Linux use &amp;lsquo;composer -v &amp;rsquo; to verify.  Windows  Download the composer and install php on your PC Use composer -v to verify the composer is ready.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build mobile app with web tech</title>
      <link>/blogs/build-mobile-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2016 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/build-mobile-app/</guid>
      <description>What is mobile app  A mobile application, basically, is a computer generated program designed and developed to run on iPhone, Android Smartphone, and many other mobile devices. In a nutshell, there are three types of apps
Native apps are specific to a given mobile platform (iOS or Android) using the development tools and language that the respective platform. Usaully it looks and performs the best.
HTML5 apps use standard web technologies—typically HTML5, JavaScript and CSS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Practices</title>
      <link>/blogs/azure-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/azure-notes/</guid>
      <description>Here we are going to explore how to deploy web applications to Azure. From sep 2015, Microsoft launched new portal for Azure. To be honest, new portal is amazing, IMO, it is one of best changes from Microsoft.
 Prerequisites  You have experience with .net web applications. You have experience with website or web app deployment.  Getting Started  Register a Microsoft account. e.g. live.com, outlook.com, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu 14 -- server setup</title>
      <link>/os/ubuntu-server-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2016 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/ubuntu-server-14/</guid>
      <description>Prelude
 This article is mainly to help experienced user install and setup Ubuntu server. If you are not familiar with Ubuntu system, please install Ubuntu desktop version at first, and you can follow Ubuntu deskstop setup
 Prerequisites  You are familiar with Ubuntu, at least you have some experience working on Linux system. You are familiar with bash/shell script You are going to setup Ubuntu server for special purpose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zend Framework 2 MVC Starter</title>
      <link>/projects/zf2-mvc-starter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 16:56:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/zf2-mvc-starter/</guid>
      <description>Summary This starter is the starting point of zend framework 2 MVC project. This application is meant to be used as a starting place for those looking to get their feet wet with ZF2.
Features  This starter was built on the zend framework 2.x. This starter uses mysql as database setting by default. Include digest authentication by default. Include font-awesome files. Include Bootstrap 3 without bootstrap-loader. Include html5shiiv.js to support older IE browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu 14 -- desktop setup &amp; dual boot </title>
      <link>/os/ubuntu-desktop-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/ubuntu-desktop-14/</guid>
      <description>This article is mainly to help beginner install Ubuntu desktop at the first time. If you are looking for setup of Ubuntu server, please check out the blog &amp;ndash; Ubuntu server setup
 Where to install Linux?  How to answer this quetion really depends user&amp;rsquo;s computer knowledge and skills. Basically Linux can be installed on almost any PC, laptop, embedded device or tablet. So there are some suggestions for people with different level skills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu 14 -- desktop, extra tools</title>
      <link>/os/ubuntu-desktop-14-extra-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/ubuntu-desktop-14-extra-tools/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites  Install Ubunt 14 Desktop Internet is availble  Install chrome wget https://dl.google.com/linux/direct/google-chrome-stable_current_amd64.deb sudo dpkg -i google-chrome-stable_current_amd64.deb  Install Umake sudo add-apt-repository ppa:ubuntu-desktop/ubuntu-make sudo apt-get update sudo apt-get install ubuntu-make  Install IDEs via Umake umake ide pycharm umake web visual-studio-code umake android android-studio  General prerequest sed -i &amp;quot;/^## deb .*partner/ s/^## //&amp;quot; /etc/apt/sources.list &amp;amp;&amp;amp; apt-get update sudo apt-get install geany byobu p7zip-full gimp pdfshuffler scribus \ filezilla lftp ubuntu-restricted-extras vlc pyrenamer \ imagemagick hugin darktable skype avidemux  Remove Games sudo apt-get remove aisleriot gnome-mahjongg gnomine gnome-sudoku  Geany themes cd ~/Downloads git clone https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows cmd &amp; hotkey - 3</title>
      <link>/hacks/windows-command-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2014 10:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hacks/windows-command-3/</guid>
      <description>This article will continue the topic of Windows command &amp;amp; hotkeys. Part-1 shows you common hotkeys and short command lines for Run windnow dialog. Part-2 advanced commands and how to create a batch script with all those commands. Here I am going to show you another secret weapon in Windows system-VBScript/JScript
Breif history  VBScript/JScript is an Active Scripting language developed by Microsoft that is modeled on Visual Basic. It allows Microsoft Windows system administrators to generate powerful tools for managing computers with error handling, subroutines, and other advanced programming constructs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript and OOP</title>
      <link>/blogs/javascript-oop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/javascript-oop/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites  You should have basic knowledge of Javascript and Object Oriented Programming. You should know how to test sample code on Chrome or Firefox. It is simple, just open your browser and click F12, copy the code to console and then press Enter.
  What is JavaScript?  JavaScript, not to be confused with Java, was created in 10 days in May 1995 by Brendan Eich, then working at Netscape and now of Mozilla.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CentOS 6/7 Multi-Boot Setup</title>
      <link>/os/centos-fedora-desktop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/centos-fedora-desktop/</guid>
      <description>Bootable usb preparation  Download dvd iso from url or torrent Use Win32 Image Writer to create usb. ( Bootice is useful tool to reformat the USB as origin )
 Install CentOS on virtual machine  Before you install, you are better to backup anything on the device which you are going to install, and chcek your internet is working properly.
 CentOS provide a friendly and nice installation process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows cmd &amp; hotkey - 2</title>
      <link>/hacks/windows-command-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2012 10:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hacks/windows-command-2/</guid>
      <description>This article will continue the topic of Windows command &amp;amp; hotkeys. Part-1 shows you common hotkeys and short command lines for Run windnow dialog. The rest of this topic will focus on the advanced commands and how to create a batch script with all those commands.
Let me clarify something first. Advanced command here does not mean that commands here are very complicated or much more powerful than common ones, which have been shown in the Part-1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows cmd &amp; hotkey - 1</title>
      <link>/hacks/windows-command-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 10:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hacks/windows-command-1/</guid>
      <description>Do you want to make your friends amazed by your computer skill and praise you as genius? Or the hacker as watched in Sci-Fi movies? You don&amp;rsquo;t need Mac, Linux or other operating systems, just Windows, you can show-off and look like hacker and master of Zeroes and Ones, even you have no any idea of it. Here are some tricks by which you can make your friends&amp;rsquo; jaw drop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/_footer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/_footer/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Generic Predicate &amp; Expression</title>
      <link>/coding/c-sharp/csharp-note-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/c-sharp/csharp-note-4/</guid>
      <description>Generic Predicate and Expression for query Prerequisites  You have experience of developing .net application, which includes entity framework.
You have experience of using SQL to query database
 Problem Now entity framework is core component in all .net applications, which need to communicate with database.
Business service get a lot of benefits form entity framework&amp;rsquo;s ORM feature, and we can create a repository layer on the top of ORM to reduce some simple but tedious database operation, such as, delete, insert, query all data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C Lecture - 1</title>
      <link>/coding/c/lcthw-lectures.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/c/lcthw-lectures.1/</guid>
      <description>Author: Zed A. Shaw
All content comes from Zed&amp;rsquo;s Lecture Repository and Libraries Repository. All credit goes to Zed.
Exercise 0 Installing Software The Plan
 Install software on your system. Test that it works right.  Linux Install
On Debian/Ubuntu use:
$ sudo apt-get install build-essential  On RedHat/CentOS:
$ sudo yum groupinstall development-tools  Linux Testing
Test that your C compiler works with:
$ cc --version  OSX Install</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C Lecture - 2</title>
      <link>/coding/c/lcthw-lectures.2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/c/lcthw-lectures.2/</guid>
      <description>Author: Zed A. Shaw
All content comes from Zed&amp;rsquo;s Lecture Repository and Libraries Repository. All credit goes to Zed.
Exercise 32 Double Linked Lists The Plan
Learn about your very first data structure:
Double Linked Lists
Creating A liblcthw Project
We&amp;rsquo;ll need a project for the rest of the book called liblcthw.
Algorithms and Data Structures
A big step in going from amateur to professional is learning about data structures and algorithms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C Lecture - 3</title>
      <link>/coding/c/lcthw-lectures.3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/c/lcthw-lectures.3/</guid>
      <description>Author: Zed A. Shaw
All content comes from Zed&amp;rsquo;s Lecture Repository and Libraries Repository. All credit goes to Zed.
Exercise 41 Project devpkg .\ex41\devpkg
.\ex41\devpkg\commands.c
#include &amp;lt;apr_uri.h&amp;gt; #include &amp;lt;apr_fnmatch.h&amp;gt; #include &amp;lt;unistd.h&amp;gt; #include &amp;quot;commands.h&amp;quot; #include &amp;quot;dbg.h&amp;quot; #include &amp;quot;bstrlib.h&amp;quot; #include &amp;quot;db.h&amp;quot; #include &amp;quot;shell.h&amp;quot; int Command_depends(apr_pool_t * p, const char *path) { FILE *in = NULL; bstring line = NULL; in = fopen(path, &amp;quot;r&amp;quot;); check(in != NULL, &amp;quot;Failed to open downloaded depends: %s&amp;quot;, path); for (line = bgets((bNgetc) fgetc, in, &#39;\n&#39;); line !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C Lecture - 4</title>
      <link>/coding/c/lcthw-lectures.4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/c/lcthw-lectures.4/</guid>
      <description>Author: Zed A. Shaw
All content comes from Zed&amp;rsquo;s Lecture Repository and Libraries Repository. All credit goes to Zed.
Exercise 48a A Simple Network Server: Project Description
The Plan
Start your first long running project:
statserve
The Purpose
You&amp;rsquo;ll get the project started and get a minimum first hack going.
The Requirements
 Create a simple network server that accepts a connection on port 7899 from netclient or the nc command, and echoes back anything you type.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cassandra Practices</title>
      <link>/hacks/cass-note/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hacks/cass-note/</guid>
      <description>Apache Cassandra is a free open-source database system that is NoSQL based. Meaning Cassandra does not use the table model seen in MySQL, MSSQL or PostgreSQL, but instead uses a cluster model. It’s designed to handle large amounts of data and is highly scalable.
Install Cassandra on Ubuntu Install Java(JRE) 8+ sudo add-apt-repository ppa:webupd8team/java sudo apt update sudo apt-get install oracle-java8-set-default java -version  Install Python 2.7+ sudo apt install python python --version  Install Cassandra  First, we have to add Cassandra repository to source list by running following command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cron Job Note - 1</title>
      <link>/coding/shell/cron-note-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/shell/cron-note-1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Cron job is one of most common techniques used on every Unix / Linux.
Common Use Cases House keeping - Clean up the backup  Run every night to remove the daily backup tar ball Assumption:
 The script file named housekeeping.sh. The script sits inside folder bin which is under your user account. All backup files have the .tar as extension. The script will check the backup tar balls within the folder bacup, which is under your user account as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cron Job Note - 2</title>
      <link>/coding/shell/cron-note-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/shell/cron-note-2/</guid>
      <description>Refresh the database (NoSQL) - Cassandra Backup the Cassandra database nightly  There is a keyspace named hho_ks in the Cassandra nodes store the production data. Every night the staging Cassandra server will be refreshed with production&amp;rsquo;s snapshot This solution is not built on the incremental snapshot. The production and staging nodes are running within the same subnet. The backup script will be run nightly on production server Cron job setting</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debug PHP with Free IDE</title>
      <link>/hacks/php-debug/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hacks/php-debug/</guid>
      <description>PDT and Netbeans  PDT and Netbeans are two most popluar free PHP IDEs. We choose such IDE for productivity, so code intelligence and debug are two key factors, which let us love IDE. Because both are not created for PHP development at the start, there is no built-in server to support the PHP web debug. When we want to use it to debug, we would come across some wierd problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Note - 1: Enum</title>
      <link>/coding/java/java-note-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/java/java-note-1/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites  Java 1.5+
 New type: Enum Enum was a great improvement in Java 1.5. From that more and more developer abandom the interface or abstract class as constant variable container.
Before Java 5 Before Java 1.5 you will following coding in many Java program.
// Use interface or abstract class as constant variable container public interface Country { public static final String AU = &amp;quot;Australian&amp;quot;; public static final String UK = &amp;quot;United Kingdom&amp;quot;; public static final String US = &amp;quot;United State&amp;quot;; } public class Util { public static String getLanguageCode(String country) { String languageCode = &amp;quot;en&amp;quot;; switch (country) { case Country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Note - 2: Concurrency</title>
      <link>/coding/java/java-note-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/java/java-note-2/</guid>
      <description>Thread Join  The join method allows one thread to wait for the completion of another. join responds to an interrupt by exiting with an InterruptedException.
 Demo code of thread join
public class JoinDemo implements Runnable { private Random rand = new Random(System.currentTimeMillis()); public void run() { //simulate some CPU expensive task for (int i = 0; i &amp;lt; 100000000; i++) { rand.nextInt(); } System.out.println(&amp;quot;[&amp;quot; + Thread.currentThread().getName() + &amp;quot;] finished .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Note - 3: Path and Files</title>
      <link>/coding/java/java-note-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/java/java-note-3/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites  Java 7+
 Good stuff from not shiny Java 7 If you are planning to refactor your code, please give a second thought. It is time to dump to try these new features. When the Java 7 was released, I was kind of disappointed without lambda, jigsaw as most developers, but when I tried new Path, Files API, I found that is great improvement. The enhancement of this new IO is really useful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Note - 4: Date Time </title>
      <link>/coding/java/java-note-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/java/java-note-4/</guid>
      <description>Date-Time API Through the java.time packages, Java 8 provides a comprehensive Date-Time API to work with date, time, and datetime. By default, most of the classes are based on the ISO-8601 standards. The main classes are
 Instant  represents an instant on the timeline and it is suitable for machines, for example, as timestamps for event  LocalDate, LocalTime, LocalDateTime
 represents human readable date, time, and datetime without a time zone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Note - 5: Lambda </title>
      <link>/coding/java/java-note-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/java/java-note-5/</guid>
      <description>Lamda Lambda Best Practices Use Interfaces The most common misstep taken by an over-eager functional programmer is the use of functional interfaces in type signatures. In general, you should avoid using the functional interface types directly and instead provide single-method interfaces as arguments to your methods. These interfaces become a way to create self-documenting code and to provide meaningful type information, as well as leaving open the opportunity for your user to provide an actual Java type.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Note - 7: Stream API</title>
      <link>/coding/java/java-note-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/java/java-note-7/</guid>
      <description>Stream Iterations Collections and Maps Filtering Mapping LambdaCollectionDemo Lambda Collection Map Demo public class LambdaCollectionMapDemo { public static void main(String[] args) { // FunctionalInterface System.out.println(&amp;quot;x + y:&amp;quot; + engine((x, y) -&amp;gt; x + y));// w w w .j av a 2s. c om System.out.println(&amp;quot;x - y:&amp;quot; + engine((x, y) -&amp;gt; x * y)); System.out.println(&amp;quot;x * y:&amp;quot; + engine((x, y) -&amp;gt; x / y)); System.out.println(&amp;quot;x / y:&amp;quot; + engine((x, y) -&amp;gt; x % y)); String[] strArray = new String[] { &amp;quot;abc&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;klm&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;xyz&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;pqr&amp;quot; }; List list = Arrays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Note - Part 6: Lambda &amp; Collection</title>
      <link>/coding/java/java-note-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/java/java-note-6/</guid>
      <description>Lambda and Collection Iterations Collections and Maps Filtering Mapping LambdaCollectionDemo Lambda Collection Map Demo public class LambdaCollectionMapDemo { public static void main(String[] args) { // FunctionalInterface System.out.println(&amp;quot;x + y:&amp;quot; + engine((x, y) -&amp;gt; x + y));// w w w .j av a 2s. c om System.out.println(&amp;quot;x - y:&amp;quot; + engine((x, y) -&amp;gt; x * y)); System.out.println(&amp;quot;x * y:&amp;quot; + engine((x, y) -&amp;gt; x / y)); System.out.println(&amp;quot;x / y:&amp;quot; + engine((x, y) -&amp;gt; x % y)); String[] strArray = new String[] { &amp;quot;abc&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;klm&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;xyz&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;pqr&amp;quot; }; List list = Arrays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JS &amp; ES Note - 1</title>
      <link>/coding/javascript/js-note-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/javascript/js-note-1/</guid>
      <description>The most unpredictable keyword and feature You may already guessed what I am talking about. Yes, thethis keyword. It is not only a powerful feature, but also often misinterpreted keyword.
In JavaScript, we also have this concept inside a Function constructor when it is invoked using the “new” keyword, however it is not the only rule and “this” can often refer to a different object from a different execution context.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JS &amp; ES Note - 2</title>
      <link>/coding/javascript/js-note-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/javascript/js-note-2/</guid>
      <description>The equal operator doesn&amp;rsquo;t always mean equivalent  Have you got confused by the equal or not equal expression in the JavaScript? I will say you are definitely not the only one. Even many senior developers come from back-end programming background, they all scratch the head to find out why the equal or not-equal expression doesn&amp;rsquo;t work as they expect. The truth is those expression are really different from other programming language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JS &amp; ES Note - 3</title>
      <link>/coding/javascript/js-note-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/javascript/js-note-3/</guid>
      <description>The var statement  var declarations, wherever they occur, are processed before any code is executed. This is called hoisting.
 The scope of a variable declared with var is its current execution context, which is either the enclosing function or, for variables declared outside any function, global. If you re-declare a JavaScript variable, it will not lose its value.
 Assigning a value to an undeclared variable implicitly creates it as a global variable (it becomes a property of the global object) when the assignment is executed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JS &amp; ES snippet</title>
      <link>/coding/javascript/js-note-99/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/javascript/js-note-99/</guid>
      <description>Setup the global node modules  Add an environment variable to tell node where the global node module sits
# I use nvm to manage my node and node modules export NODE_PATH=${HOME}/.nvm/versions/node/&amp;lt;node_version&amp;gt;/lib/node_modules  If you use npm by default, you may have permission problem to access the node modules. I suggest you to set a customized global node module folder under your home directory.
 Create a new folder under your home directory Install npm to new global node module update environment variables in the profile</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Cluster in 5min</title>
      <link>/projects/kube-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/kube-cluster/</guid>
      <description>Kubernetes  Kubernetes (K8s) is an open-source system for automating deployment, scaling, and management of containerized applications.
It groups containers that make up an application into logical units for easy management and discovery. Kubernetes builds upon 15 years of experience of running production workloads at Google, combined with best-of-breed ideas and practices from the community.
 Purpose This project focuses on the training and demonstration. Please DO NOT use it in production environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MySql Note - 1</title>
      <link>/coding/sql/mysql-note-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/sql/mysql-note-1/</guid>
      <description>MySQL is the world&amp;rsquo;s most popular open source database. Whether you are a fast growing web property, technology ISV or large enterprise, MySQL can cost-effectively help you deliver high performance, scalable database applications.
 Create a new database -- Drop the old one DROP SCHEMA IF EXISTS new_dbu -- Create a new db CREATE DATABASE new_db CHARACTER SET utf8 COLLATE utf8_general_ci;  Create a table DROP TABLE IF EXISTS new_table; CREATE TABLE new_table ( id int NOT NULL AUTO_INCREMENT, name varchar(50), title varchar(50), email varchar(250), created_date datetime, modified_date datetime, PRIMARY KEY (id) );  Query  JOIN and INNER JOIN</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MySql Note - 2</title>
      <link>/coding/sql/mysql-note-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/sql/mysql-note-2/</guid>
      <description>Function - UDF  For the UDF mechanism to work, functions must be written in C or C++ and your operating system must support dynamic loading. MySQL source distributions include a file sql/udf_example.cc that defines five UDF functions. Consult this file to see how UDF calling conventions work. The include/mysql_com.h header file defines UDF-related symbols and data structures, although you need not include this header file directly; it is included by mysql.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MySql Note - 3</title>
      <link>/coding/sql/mysql-note-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/sql/mysql-note-3/</guid>
      <description>Information schema  INFORMATION_SCHEMA provides access to database metadata, information about the MySQL server such as the name of a database or table, the data type of a column, or access privileges. Other terms that are sometimes used for this information are data dictionary and system catalog.
 Check out table size SET @target_schema=&#39;THE_TARGET_SCHEMA&#39;; SELECT TABLE_NAME, table_rows, data_length, index_length, round(((data_length + index_length) / 1024 / 1024 /1024),2) &#39;Size in GB&#39;, round(((data_length + index_length) / 1024 / 1024 ),2) &#39;Size in MB&#39; FROM information_schema.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Powershell Note - 1</title>
      <link>/coding/shell/ps-note-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/shell/ps-note-1/</guid>
      <description>PowerShell is a task-based command-line shell and scripting language built on .NET. PowerShell helps system administrators and power-users rapidly automate tasks that manage operating systems (Linux, macOS, and Windows) and processes.
 Prerequisites  The OS of Windows 7 or later version Install Powershell 4 or later version. You can find it on Microsoft website Has basic computer knowledge  Launch PS command prompt  Type command on windows command prompt: powershell  Get PS Version  Type $psversiontable</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Web Framework</title>
      <link>/frameworks/python-django/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/frameworks/python-django/</guid>
      <description>Django is a high-level Python Web framework that encourages rapid development and clean, pragmatic design. Built by experienced developers, it takes care of much of the hassle of Web development, so you can focus on writing your app without needing to reinvent the wheel. It’s free and open source.
 Install Python, pip and virtualenv  Windows: Please find in from Home Page
 Ubuntu: Please find it from Ubuntu setup</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qemu &amp; Virtual Machine</title>
      <link>/hacks/qemu-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hacks/qemu-notes/</guid>
      <description>What is Qemu ?
QEMU is free and open source. And is licensed under GPL 2. it has the ability to run under both KVM and XEN models (if you enabled virtualization technology from your BIOS first) and offers a lot of options and virtualization options. In this article, we’ll explain how to use QEMU and install it.
QEMU is a virtualization technology emulator that allows you to run operating systems and Linux distributions easily on your current system without the need to install them or burn their ISO files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rustlang Note - 1</title>
      <link>/coding/rustlang/rust-note-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/rustlang/rust-note-1/</guid>
      <description>Mutability Rust encourages you to favor immutability. It’s important that we get compile-time errors when we attempt to change a value that we previously designated as immutable because this very situation can lead to bugs.
But mutability can be very useful. To make them mutable is simply adding mut in front of the variable name. In addition to allowing this value to change, mut conveys intent to future readers of the code by indicating that other parts of the code will be changing this variable value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rustlang Note - 2</title>
      <link>/coding/rustlang/rust-note-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/rustlang/rust-note-2/</guid>
      <description>Project management  Rust has a number of features that allow you to manage your code’s organization, including which details are exposed, which details are private, and what names are in each scope in your programs.
 Packages: A Cargo feature that lets you build, test, and share crates Crates: A tree of modules that produces a library or executable Modules and use: Let you control the organization, scope, and privacy of paths Paths: A way of naming an item, such as a struct, function, or module   Package &amp;amp; Crate  A package is one or more crates that provide a set of functionality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rustlang Note - 3</title>
      <link>/coding/rustlang/rust-note-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/rustlang/rust-note-3/</guid>
      <description>Error  Rust groups errors into two major categories: recoverable and unrecoverable errors.
 Rust doesn’t have exceptions. Instead, it has the type Resultfor recoverable errors and the panic! macro that stops execution when the program encounters an unrecoverable error.
  panic! - Unrecoverable Errors  Rust has the panic! macro. When the panic! macro executes, your program will print a failure message, unwind and clean up the stack, and then quit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rustlang Note - 4</title>
      <link>/coding/rustlang/rust-note-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/rustlang/rust-note-4/</guid>
      <description>Generic Type  Generics are abstract stand-ins for concrete types or other properties. When we’re writing code, we can express the behavior of generics or how they relate to other generics without knowing what will be in their place when compiling and running the code.  Removing Duplication by Extracting a Function  steps we took to change the duplication code :
 Identify duplicate code.
 Extract the duplicate code into the body of the function and specify the inputs and return values of that code in the function signature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scheduled task with window service</title>
      <link>/coding/c-sharp/csharp-note-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/c-sharp/csharp-note-2/</guid>
      <description>Problem  Set up the some scheduled tasks running in the backgroud to take care of data update or sync for every 15 mins, or everyday or every week
 Solution Option 1 Windows Task Scheduler  Click the Start button. Click Control Panel. Click System and Maintenance. Click Administrative Tools. Double-click Task Scheduler.  Option 2 Use Window Service as task scheduler Overview of design The design here is a simplified version, which I built for previous projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thread &amp; Task</title>
      <link>/coding/c-sharp/csharp-note-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/c-sharp/csharp-note-3/</guid>
      <description>C# Thread &amp;amp; Task  From Net 4.0, .Net applicatoin introduced Parallel Framework Extensions (PFx), along the way it delivered an entirely new model for async processing in .NET. In .NET 4.0 the thread pool queue was redesigned with the new requirements of PFx in mind. Instead of using a simple linked list, the queue was built with arrays of work items with the arrays connected into a linked list.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>