<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hello World</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Hello World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 10:59:31 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CMMI</title>
      <link>/management/cmmi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 10:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/management/cmmi/</guid>
      <description>CMMI The Capability Maturity Model Integration (CMMI) is a process and behavioral model that helps organizations streamline process improvement and encourage productive, efficient behaviors that decrease risks in software, product and service development.
CMMI model The CMMI starts with an appraisal process that evaluates three specific areas: process and service development, service establishment and management, and product and service acquisition. It’s designed to help improve performance by providing businesses with everything they need to consistently develop better products and services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CMMI 2.0</title>
      <link>/management/cmmi_v2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 10:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/management/cmmi_v2/</guid>
      <description>CMMI 2.0 Guilding Principles  Focus of delivering business value Focus on business performance and results Flexible, scalable architecture Reduce redundancy Use of plain language Increased use of graphics and iconography for understanding and adoption  Key Improvements  Demonstrate the value and ROI of aclopting CMMI
Performance capabilities built-in at every level of the model will help organizations to:
 Understand performance needs
 Track, measure and achieve Establish performance goals those goals  Improve the overall value for CMMI appraisals and lower time, effort and cost of the appraisal process</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COBIT 5</title>
      <link>/management/cobit_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 10:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/management/cobit_5/</guid>
      <description>COBIT 5 COBIT (Control Objectives for Information and Related Technologies) is a business framework for the governance and management of Enterprise IT, created by ISACA.
The framework contains the COBIT 5 framework for governing and managing enterprise IT. It defines a set of generic processes for the management of IT, with each process defined together with process inputs and outputs, key process-activities, process objectives, performance measures and an elementary maturity model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scrum VS Kanban</title>
      <link>/management/scrum_vs_kanban/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 10:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/management/scrum_vs_kanban/</guid>
      <description>Scrum VS Kanban Kanban and scrum are frameworks that help teams adhere to agile principles and get stuff done. Both frameworks will help you build better products(and services) with fewer headaches. While the practices differ, the principles are largely the same.
Agile Agile is a structured and iterative approach to project management and product development. t recognizes the volatility of product development, and provides a methodology for self-organizing teams to respond to change without going off the rails.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS: IAM</title>
      <link>/cloud/aws/aws-01-iam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/aws/aws-01-iam/</guid>
      <description>IAM AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM) enables you to manage access to AWS services and resources securely. Using IAM, you can create and manage AWS users and groups, and use permissions to allow and deny their access to AWS resources.
Root User  Every account has a root user in AWS. A root user is something that&amp;rsquo;s created automatically for you whenever you create an AWS account. Every single AWS account has a root user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure: CAF - 1</title>
      <link>/cloud/azure/az-01-caf-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/azure/az-01-caf-01/</guid>
      <description>Cloud Adoption Framework The Microsoft Cloud Adoption Framework for Azure is proven guidance that&amp;rsquo;s designed to help you create and implement the business and technology strategies necessary for your organization to succeed in the cloud. It provides best practices, documentation, and tools that cloud architects, IT professionals, and business decision makers need to successfully achieve short-term and long-term objectives.
The Cloud Adoption Framework brings together cloud adoption best practices from Microsoft employees, partners, and customers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure: CAF - 2</title>
      <link>/cloud/azure/az-01-caf-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/azure/az-01-caf-02/</guid>
      <description>Function  Cloud adoption functions deliver technical solutions. Cloud strategy functions align technical change with business needs. Cloud operations functions support and operate adopted solutions. Cloud center of excellence (CCoE) functions improve quality, speed, and resiliency of adoption. Cloud governance functions manage risk. Cloud platform functions operate and mature the platform. Cloud automation functions accelerate adoption and innovation. Cloud security functions manage security risks.  Team cloud strategy team To be successful, every cloud adoption journey needs to involve some level of strategic planning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure: CAF - 3</title>
      <link>/cloud/azure/az-01-caf-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/azure/az-01-caf-03/</guid>
      <description>cloud adoption strategy  Define and document your motivations: Meet with key stakeholders and executives to document the motivations behind cloud adoption.
 Document business outcomes: Engage motivated stakeholders and executives to document specific business outcomes.
 Develop a business case: Develop a business case to validate the financial model that supports your motivations and outcomes.
 Choose the right first project: Your first cloud adoption project will help align motivations with technical effort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure: RBAC - 1</title>
      <link>/cloud/azure/az-02-rbac-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/azure/az-02-rbac-01/</guid>
      <description>RBAC Azure RBAC is an authorization system built on Azure Resource Manager that provides fine-grained access management of Azure resources.
What to do with RBAC  Allow one user to manage virtual machines in a subscription and another user to manage virtual networks Allow a DBA group to manage SQL databases in a subscription Allow a user to manage all resources in a resource group, such as virtual machines, websites, and subnets Allow an application to access all resources in a resource group  How it works The way you control access to resources using Azure RBAC is to create role assignments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure: RBAC - 2</title>
      <link>/cloud/azure/az-02-rbac-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/azure/az-02-rbac-02/</guid>
      <description>Roles  Classic subscription administrator roles Azure roles Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) roles  History  When Azure was initially released, access to resources was managed with just three administrator roles: Account Administrator, Service Administrator, and Co-Administrator. Later, Azure role-based access control (Azure RBAC) was added. Azure RBAC is a newer authorization system that provides fine-grained access management to Azure resources. Azure RBAC includes many built-in roles, can be assigned at different scopes, and allows you to create your own custom roles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure: RBAC - 3</title>
      <link>/cloud/azure/az-02-rbac-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/azure/az-02-rbac-03/</guid>
      <description>Best practices Only grant the access users need    Scope Roles         - Reader Resource-specific Custom Contributor Owner   Management Group Observers Users managing resources Users managing resources Users managing resources Admins   Subscriptions Observers Users managing resources Users managing resources Users managing resources Admins   Resource Group Observers Users managing resources Users managing resources Users managing resources Admins   Resources Automated processes Automated processes Automated processes Automated processes Automated processes    Azure AD Privileged Identity Management Privileged Identity Management (PIM) is a service in Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) that enables you to manage, control, and monitor access to important resources in your organization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Types &amp; Ownership</title>
      <link>/coding/rustlang/rust-note-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/rustlang/rust-note-1/</guid>
      <description>Mutability Rust encourages you to favor immutability. It’s important that we get compile-time errors when we attempt to change a value that we previously designated as immutable because this very situation can lead to bugs.
But mutability can be very useful. To make them mutable is simply adding mut in front of the variable name. In addition to allowing this value to change, mut conveys intent to future readers of the code by indicating that other parts of the code will be changing this variable value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DigitialOcean: Droplet</title>
      <link>/cloud/digito/digito-note-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/digito/digito-note-1/</guid>
      <description>Droplet DigitalOcean Droplets are Linux-based virtual machines (VMs) that run on top of virtualized hardware. Each Droplet you create is a new server you can use, either standalone or as part of a larger, cloud-based infrastructure.
Prerequisite  Prepare a bank account or credit card Signup DigitalOcean account and activate it Create a new prject  OS Options  Ubuntu FreeBSD Fedora Debian CentOS  Plans and Pricing We offer four different kinds of Droplet plans: one shared CPU plan and three dedicated CPU plans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>F# Overview</title>
      <link>/coding/f-sharp/fsharp-note-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/f-sharp/fsharp-note-1/</guid>
      <description>F  F# is an open-source, cross-platform, interoperable programming language for writing succinct, robust and performant code. Your focus remains on your problem domain, rather than the details of programming.
 Organizing F# Code The following table shows reference articles related to organizing your F# code.
   Title Description     Namespaces Learn about namespace support in F#. A namespace lets you organize code into areas of related functionality by enabling you to attach a name to a grouping of program elements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started</title>
      <link>/coding/golang/go-note-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/golang/go-note-1/</guid>
      <description>Go Introduction  Golang&amp;rsquo;s popularity is skyrocketing. The thriving of Docker and Kubernetes push the Golang to a higher level.
Go is easy to become functional with and appropriate for junior developers to work on. Also, having a language that encourages readability and comprehension is extremely useful. The mixture of duck typing (via interfaces) and convenience features such as &amp;ldquo;:=&amp;rdquo; for short variable declarations give Go the feel of a dynamically typed language while retaining the positives of a strongly typed one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Package &amp; Module</title>
      <link>/coding/python/python-note-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/python/python-note-1/</guid>
      <description>Package &amp;amp; Module  Packages are modules that contain other modules. Packages are generally implemented as directories containing a special __init__.py file. The __init__.py file is executed when the package is imported. Packages can contain sub packages which themselves are implemented with __init__.py files in directories. The module objects for packages have a __path__ attribute.  sys.path  List of directories which Python searches for modules.
# list directories &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;import sys &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;sys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS : CLI - 1</title>
      <link>/cloud/aws/aws-02-cli-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/aws/aws-02-cli-1/</guid>
      <description>AWS CLI Amazon Virtual Private Cloud (Amazon VPC) enables you to launch AWS resources into a virtual network that you&amp;rsquo;ve defined. This virtual network closely resembles a traditional network that you&amp;rsquo;d operate in your own data center, with the benefits of using the scalable infrastructure of AWS.
CLI installation (Version 1) Install Python 3  Python 2.7 is no longer supported. Please install python3
sudo yum install python3 pip3 --version    Profile Setup A named profile is a collection of settings and credentials that you can apply to a AWS CLI command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS : CLI - 2</title>
      <link>/cloud/aws/aws-02-cli-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/aws/aws-02-cli-2/</guid>
      <description>AWS CLI &amp;amp; VPC Following is a sample to create a VPC with 2 private subnets, 2 public subnets across 2 avaliable zones and NAT Gateway.
#!/bin/bash #****************************************************************************** # AWS VPC CLI Script #****************************************************************************** # # SYNOPSIS # Automates the creation of a custom IPv4 VPC, having both a public and a # private subnet, and a NAT gateway. # #============================================================================== # # NOTES # VERSION: 1.0 # AUTHOR: Harry Ho # #============================================================================== # MODIFY THE SETTINGS BELOW #============================================================================== # AWS_REGION=&amp;quot;ap-southeast-2&amp;quot; VPC_NAME=&amp;quot;DEV-PG-II&amp;quot; VPC_CIDR=&amp;quot;10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS : CLI - 3</title>
      <link>/cloud/aws/aws-02-cli-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/aws/aws-02-cli-3/</guid>
      <description>AWS CLI &amp;amp; &amp;amp; Security Group Sometimes it is so annoying to update the rules of security group one by one, because of the change of your public IP address. Following is a script to make such change easier.
The script will only update the SSH / RDP protocals of specified the security groups. The SSH and RDP are most popular ones which allow admin to access the remote EC2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Closure &amp; Decorator</title>
      <link>/coding/python/python-note-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/python/python-note-2/</guid>
      <description>Closure &amp;amp; Decorator LEGB rules  Local, Enclosing, Gloable, Built-in  Local function  Useful for specialized, one-off functions Aid in code organization and readability Similar to lambdas, but more general May contain multiple expressions May contain statements  Closure  Closure maintain references to objects from earlier scopes LEGB does not apply when making new bindings Usage of nonlocal
 Example
def make_timer(): last_called = None def elapsed(): nonlocal last_called now = time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DigitialOcean: Get Started</title>
      <link>/cloud/digito/digito-note-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/digito/digito-note-2/</guid>
      <description>User Setup Create a new admin user Add a new user # Add new user # set password adduser &amp;lt;admin_user&amp;gt; # user to sudo group usermod -aG sudo &amp;lt;admin_user&amp;gt;  Set SSH access for new user # Switch session to new user su - &amp;lt;admin_user&amp;gt; # navigate to user home cd # Prepare ssh directory mkdir .ssh chmod 700 ~/.ssh # Copy root key sudo cp /root/.ssh/authorized_keys ~/.ssh/authorized_keys chmod 644 /home/&amp;lt;admin_user&amp;gt;/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Map, Function &amp; Closure</title>
      <link>/coding/golang/go-note-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/golang/go-note-2/</guid>
      <description>Map  Maps are a special kind of data structure: an unordered collection of pairs of items, where one element of the pair is the key, and the other element, associated with the key, is the data or the value, hence they are also called associative arrays or dictionaries.
 The key type can be any type for which the operations == and != are defined, like string, int, float.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project, Vector, String &amp; Hashmap</title>
      <link>/coding/rustlang/rust-note-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/rustlang/rust-note-2/</guid>
      <description>Project management  Rust has a number of features that allow you to manage your code’s organization, including which details are exposed, which details are private, and what names are in each scope in your programs.
 Packages: A Cargo feature that lets you build, test, and share crates Crates: A tree of modules that produces a library or executable Modules and use: Let you control the organization, scope, and privacy of paths Paths: A way of naming an item, such as a struct, function, or module   Package &amp;amp; Crate  A package is one or more crates that provide a set of functionality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS: VPC - 1</title>
      <link>/cloud/aws/aws-03-vpc-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/aws/aws-03-vpc-1/</guid>
      <description>VPC Part 1 Amazon Virtual Private Cloud (Amazon VPC) enables you to launch AWS resources into a virtual network that you&amp;rsquo;ve defined. This virtual network closely resembles a traditional network that you&amp;rsquo;d operate in your own data center, with the benefits of using the scalable infrastructure of AWS.
Key concepts  A virtual private cloud (VPC) is a virtual network dedicated to your AWS account. A subnet is a range of IP addresses in your VPC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure: App - 1</title>
      <link>/cloud/azure/az-03-app-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/azure/az-03-app-01/</guid>
      <description>Azure App Service Azure App Service is an HTTP-based service for hosting web applications, REST APIs, and mobile back ends. You can develop in your favorite language, be it .NET, .NET Core, Java, Ruby, Node.js, PHP, or Python. Applications run and scale with ease on both Windows and Linux-based environments.
 Built-in auto scale support
 Continuous integration/deployment support
 Deployment slots
  Limitations  App Service on Linux is not supported on Shared pricing tier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DigitialOcean: First Web Host</title>
      <link>/cloud/digito/digito-note-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/digito/digito-note-3/</guid>
      <description>Here I contineu to setup SSL certificates for all sites on my web host
 UFW UFW, or Uncomplicated Firewall, is a front-end to iptables. Its main goal is to make managing your firewall drop-dead simple and to provide an easy-to-use interface.
DO NOT Enable UFW
 DO NOT enable UFW without reading through the instructions
 Enable IP V6  Open the UFW configuration with vi:  sudo vi /etc/default/ufw   Make sure &amp;ldquo;IPV6&amp;rdquo; is set to &amp;ldquo;yes&amp;rdquo;, like so:  .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Error handling</title>
      <link>/coding/rustlang/rust-note-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/rustlang/rust-note-3/</guid>
      <description>Error  Rust groups errors into two major categories: recoverable and unrecoverable errors.
 Rust doesn’t have exceptions. Instead, it has the type Resultfor recoverable errors and the panic! macro that stops execution when the program encounters an unrecoverable error.
  panic! - Unrecoverable Errors  Rust has the panic! macro. When the panic! macro executes, your program will print a failure message, unwind and clean up the stack, and then quit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>String &amp; Representation</title>
      <link>/coding/python/python-note-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/python/python-note-3/</guid>
      <description>String &amp;amp; Representation str()  print() -&amp;gt; str() -&amp;gt; __str(self)__ Fallback to repr(). By default, str() simply calls repr() Produces a readable, human-friendly representation of an object It is also the string constructor  repr()  Exactness is more important than human-friendliness Suited for debugging. Unambiguous, precise, include type Includes identifying information. Generally best for logging and developers The default repr() is not very helpful As a rule, you should always write a repr() for your classes standard library reprlib.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Struct &amp; Interface</title>
      <link>/coding/golang/go-note-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/golang/go-note-3/</guid>
      <description>Struct  Go supports user-defined or custom types in the form of alias types or structs. A struct tries to represent a real-world entity with its properties. Structs are composite types, to use when you want to define a type which consist of a number of properties, each having their own type and value, grouping pieces of data together.
 Struct with tags  A field in a struct can, apart from a name and a type, also optionally have a tag: this is a string attached to the field, which could be documentation or some other important label.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS: VPC - 2</title>
      <link>/cloud/aws/aws-03-vpc-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/aws/aws-03-vpc-2/</guid>
      <description>VPC Part 2 VPC has an implicit router (implied router), and you use route tables to control where network traffic is directed.
Route table  Have up to 200 route tables per VPC Have up to 50 route entries per route table Each subnet must be associated with only one route table The subent (when created) will be associated with main (default) VPC route table Can change the subnet association to another route table Can NOT delete the main route table Every route table in a VPC comes with a default rule that allows all VPC subnets to comminunicate with one another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure: CLI - 1</title>
      <link>/cloud/azure/az-04-cli-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/azure/az-04-cli-01/</guid>
      <description>Azure Cli The Azure Command-Line Interface (CLI) is a cross-platform command-line tool to connect to Azure and execute administrative commands on Azure resources. It allows the execution of commands through a terminal using interactive command-line prompts or a script.
Install Azure CLI on macOS  Mac with Intel CPU  brew update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; brew install azure-cli  Install Azure Cli with Docker  Use docker run  docker run -it mcr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DigitialOcean: Lets Encrypt</title>
      <link>/cloud/digito/digito-note-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/digito/digito-note-4/</guid>
      <description>Here I continue to finish the web host setup. The last step of web host setup is to add SSL certificate for each site
 Lets Encrypt To enable HTTPS on your website, you need to get a certificate (a type of file) from a Certificate Authority (CA). Let’s Encrypt is a CA. In order to get a certificate for your website’s domain from Let’s Encrypt, you have to demonstrate control over the domain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generic Type &amp; Trait </title>
      <link>/coding/rustlang/rust-note-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/rustlang/rust-note-4/</guid>
      <description>Generic Type  Generics are abstract stand-ins for concrete types or other properties. When we’re writing code, we can express the behavior of generics or how they relate to other generics without knowing what will be in their place when compiling and running the code.  Removing Duplication by Extracting a Function  steps we took to change the duplication code :
 Identify duplicate code.
 Extract the duplicate code into the body of the function and specify the inputs and return values of that code in the function signature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IO, Json &amp; XML</title>
      <link>/coding/golang/go-note-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/golang/go-note-4/</guid>
      <description>IO - Read &amp;amp; Write Read from user input var ( firstName, lastName, s string i int f float32 input = &amp;quot;56.12 / 5212 / Go&amp;quot; format = &amp;quot;%f / %d / %s&amp;quot; ) func main() { fmt.Println(&amp;quot;Please enter your full name: &amp;quot;) fmt.Scanln(&amp;amp;firstName, &amp;amp;lastName) // fmt.Scanf(&amp;quot;%s %s&amp;quot;, &amp;amp;firstName, &amp;amp;lastName) fmt.Printf(&amp;quot;Hi %s %s!\n&amp;quot;, firstName, lastName) // Hi Chris Naegels fmt.Sscanf(input, format, &amp;amp;f, &amp;amp;i, &amp;amp;s) fmt.Println(&amp;quot;From the string we read: &amp;quot;, f, i, s) // ouwtput: From the string we read: 56.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iteration</title>
      <link>/coding/python/python-note-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/python/python-note-4/</guid>
      <description>Iterables &amp;amp; Iteration Comprehensions  Comprehensions can process more than one input sequence Multiple input sequences in comprehensions work like nested for-loops Comprehensions can also have multiple if-clauses interspersed with the for-clauses Later clauses in a comprehension can reference variables bound in earlier clauses Comprehension can also appear in the result expression of a comprehension, resulting in nested sequences  Example ## Comprehensions &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; points [(0, 0), (0, 1), (0, 2), (0, 3), (1, 0), (1, 1), (1, 2), (1, 3), (2, 0), (2, 1), (2, 2), (2, 3)] &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; points_c=[(x,y) for x in range(3) for y in range(4) ] &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; points_c [(0, 0), (0, 1), (0, 2), (0, 3), (1, 0), (1, 1), (1, 2), (1, 3), (2, 0), (2, 1), (2, 2), (2, 3)] &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; points_d=[(x,y) .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS: VPC - 3</title>
      <link>/cloud/aws/aws-03-vpc-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/aws/aws-03-vpc-3/</guid>
      <description>VPC Part 3 Endpoint A VPC endpoint enables you to privately connect your VPC to supported AWS services and VPC endpoint services powered by AWS PrivateLink without requiring an internet gateway, NAT device, VPN connection, or AWS Direct Connect connection.
Endpoints are virtual devices. They are horizontally scaled, redundant, and highly available VPC components. They allow communication between instances in your VPC and services without imposing availability risks or bandwidth constraints on your network traffic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Error handling</title>
      <link>/coding/golang/go-note-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/golang/go-note-5/</guid>
      <description>Error handling  Go does not have an exception mechanism, like the try/catch in Java or .NET for instance: you cannot throw exceptions. Instead it has a defer-panic-and-recover mechanism.
 The Go way to handle errors is for functions and methods to return an error object as their only or last return value—or nil if no error occurred—and for calling functions to always check the error they receive.
 Handle the errors and return from the function in which the error occurred with an error message to the user: that way if something does go wrong, your program will continue to function and the user will be notified.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inheritance &amp; Polymorphism</title>
      <link>/coding/python/python-note-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/python/python-note-5/</guid>
      <description>Inheritance &amp;amp; Polymorphism  Specify single inheritance by putting a base class in parentheses after defining a class&amp;rsquo;s name Subclasses have all of the methods of their base class It&amp;rsquo;s often best to explicitly call a base class initializer from a subclass&amp;rsquo;s initializer If a class with a single base class doesn&amp;rsquo;t define an initializer, the base class&amp;rsquo;s initializer will be called automatically on construction Python treats __init__() like any other method Base class __init__() is not called if overridden Use super() to call base class __init__() isinstance() takes an object as its first argument and a type as its second isinstance() determines if its first argument is an instance of the second argument, or any subclass of the second argument isinstance() can accept a tuple of types as its second argument, in which it returns True if the first argument is of any of those types Checking for specific types is rare in Python and is sometimes regarded as bad design isinstance() determines if its first argument is a direct or indirect subclass of, or the same type as, the second argument Multiple inheritance means having more than one direct base class You declare multiple base classes with a comma-separated list of class names in parentheses after a class&amp;rsquo;s name in a class definition A class can have as many base classes as you want Python uses a well-defined &amp;ldquo;method resolution order&amp;rdquo; to resolve methods at runtime If a multiply-inheriting class defines no initializer, Python will automatically call the initializer of its first base class on construction __bases__ is a tuple of types on a class object which defines the base classes for the class __bases__ is in the same order as in the class definition __bases__ is populated for both single and multiple inheritance Method resolution order defines the order in which Python will search an inheritance graph for methods MRO is short for Method Resolution Order MRO is stored as a tuple of types in the __mro__ attribute of a class The mro() method on type objects returns the contents of __mro__ as a list To resolve a method, Python uses the first entry in a class&amp;rsquo;s MRO which has the requested method MRO is dependent on base class declaration order MRO is calculated by Python using the C3 algorithm MRO honors base-class ordering from class definitions MRO puts subclasses before base classes The relative order of classes in an MRO is consistent across all classes It is possible to specify an inconsistent base class ordering, in which case Python will raise a TypeError when the class definition is reached super() operates by using the elements in an MRO that come after some specified type super() returns a proxy object which forwards calls to the correct objects There are two distinct types of super() proxies, bound and unbound Unbound super() proxies are primarily used for implementing other Python features Bound proxies can be bound to either class objects or instances Calling super() with a base-class and derived-class argument returns a proxy bound to a class Calling super() with a class and an instance of that class returns a proxy bound to an instance A super() proxy takes the MRO of its second argument (or the type of its second argument), finds the first argument in that MRO, and uses everything after it in the MRO for method resolution Since class-bound proxies aren&amp;rsquo;t bound to an instance, you can’t directly call instance methods that they resolve for you However, classmethods resolved by class-bound proxies can be called directly Python will raise a TypeError if the second argument is not a subclass or instance of the first argument Inappropriate use of super() can violate some design constraints * Calling super() with no arguments inside an instance method produces an instance-bound proxy Calling super() with no arguments inside a classmethod produces a class-bound proxy In both cases, the no-argument form of super() is the same as calling super() with the method&amp;rsquo;s class as the first argument and the method&amp;rsquo;s first argument as the second Since super() works on MROs and not just a class&amp;rsquo;s base classes, class can be designed to cooperate without prior knowledge of one another The class object is at the core of Python&amp;rsquo;s object model object is the ultimate base class for all other classes in Python If you don&amp;rsquo;t specify a base class for a class, Python automatically uses object as the base Because object is in every class&amp;rsquo;s inheritance graph, it shows up in every MRO.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS: VPC - 4</title>
      <link>/cloud/aws/aws-03-vpc-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/aws/aws-03-vpc-4/</guid>
      <description>VPC Part 4 Simples demo  Diagram of customized VPC - MyDemoVPC with Internet Gatway and VPN connect  mermaid.initialize({startOnLoad:true}); graph LR InternetGW(Internet Gateway) VirtualGW(Virtual Gateway) INTER(Internet - Public) InternetGW --- INTER VirtualGW --- SERVER subgraph MyDemoVPC EC2_A(EC2 Instannce A) EC2_B(EC2 Instannce B) EC2_E(EC2 Instannce E) EC2_F(EC2 Instannce F) EC2_C[(Database Master)] EC2_D[(Database Slave)] MainRouteTable(10.0.0.0/16) PrvSubnet(10.0.2.0/24) PubSubnet(10.0.1.0/24) VPNSubnet(10.0.3.0/24) MainRouteTable --- InternetGW MainRouteTable --- NetworkACL NetworkACL --- PubSecGrp NetworkACL --- PrivSecGrp PrivSecGrp --- PrvSubnet VPNSubnet --- VirtualGW VPNSubnet --- MainRouteTable PubSecGrp --- PubSubnet subgraph Implied_Router MainRouteTable(10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS: VPC - 5</title>
      <link>/cloud/aws/aws-03-vpc-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/aws/aws-03-vpc-5/</guid>
      <description>VPC Part 5 Direct Connect AWS Direct Connect is a cloud service solution that makes it easy to establish a dedicated network connection from your premises to AWS. Using AWS Direct Connect, you can establish private connectivity between AWS and your datacenter, office, or colocation environment, which in many cases can reduce your network costs, increase bandwidth throughput, and provide a more consistent network experience than Internet-based connections.
Using industry standard 802.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collection</title>
      <link>/coding/python/python-note-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/python/python-note-6/</guid>
      <description>Collection Collection protocols  To implement a protocol, objects must support certain operations. Most collections implement container, sized and iterable. All except dict and set are sequences Container: membership testing using in and not in Sized: Determine number of elements with len(s) Iterable: Can produce an iterator with iter(s), e.g.
 for item in iterable: do_something(item) `len(s)`  Sequence:
 Retrieve elements by index, e.g. item = seq[index] Find items by value index = seq.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goroutine &amp; Channel - 1</title>
      <link>/coding/golang/go-note-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/golang/go-note-6/</guid>
      <description>Goroutine  A goroutine is implemented as a function or method (this can also be an anonymous or lambda function) and called (invoked) with the keyword go. This starts the function running in parallel with the current computation but in the same address space and with its own stack.
 Go’s concurrency primitives provide the basis for a good concurrency program design: expressing program structure so as to represent independently executing actions; so Go’s emphasis is not in the 1 st place on parallelism: concurrent programs may or may not be parallel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS: S3 - 1</title>
      <link>/cloud/aws/aws-04-s3-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/aws/aws-04-s3-1/</guid>
      <description>S3 Part 1 Amazon Simple Storage Service (Amazon S3) is an object storage service that offers industry-leading scalability, data availability, security, and performance.
Storage feature Amazon S3 has various features you can use to organize and manage your data in ways that support specific use cases, enable cost efficiencies, enforce security, and meet compliance requirements. Data is stored as objects within resources called “buckets”, and a single object can be up to 5 terabytes in size.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS: S3 - 2</title>
      <link>/cloud/aws/aws-04-s3-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/aws/aws-04-s3-2/</guid>
      <description>S3 Part 2 Access Access status The list buckets view shows whether your bucket is publicly accessible. Amazon S3 labels the permissions for a bucket as follows:
 Public – Everyone has access to one or more of the following: List objects, Write objects, Read and write permissions.
 Objects can be public – The bucket is not public, but anyone with the appropriate permissions can grant public access to objects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS: S3 - 3</title>
      <link>/cloud/aws/aws-04-s3-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/aws/aws-04-s3-3/</guid>
      <description>Use Case Problem Block all traffic to my Amazon Simple Storage Service (Amazon S3) bucket unless the traffic is from specific Amazon Virtual Private Cloud (VPC) endpoints or certain external IP addresses.
Resolution Use a bucket policy to specify which VPC endpoints or external IP addresses can access the S3 bucket.
 Note: An external IP address is a public IP address that can be from within a VPC or outside of a VPC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS: SQS,SNS,SES - 1</title>
      <link>/cloud/aws/aws-05-ses-sqs-sns-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/aws/aws-05-ses-sqs-sns-1/</guid>
      <description>SQS Amazon Simple Queue Service (SQS) is a fully managed message queuing service that enables you to decouple and scale microservices, distributed systems, and serverless applications. SQS eliminates the complexity and overhead associated with managing and operating message oriented middleware, and empowers developers to focus on differentiating work. Using SQS, you can send, store, and receive messages between software components at any volume, without losing messages or requiring other services to be available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS: SQS,SNS,SES - 2</title>
      <link>/cloud/aws/aws-05-ses-sqs-sns-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/aws/aws-05-ses-sqs-sns-2/</guid>
      <description>Use Case Overview mermaid.initialize({startOnLoad:true}); graph LR Sender_Email(&#34;test@test.com&#34;) Email_Failed Email_Delivered SNS_Subscriptions -- Email_Failed SNS_Subscriptions -- Email_Delivered Bounce_Notification -- Email_Failed Complaint_Notification -- Email_Failed Delivery_Notification -- Email_Delivered subgraph SQS subgraph Email_Status_Queue SNS_Subscriptions end end subgraph SNS subgraph Topics Email_Failed Email_Delivered end end subgraph SES Sender_Email subgraph Notifications Bounce_Notification Complaint_Notification Delivery_Notification end end  SNS Setup  Create a topic for failed email, e.g. bounce or spam complaint
 It is named Email_Failed in the diagram above  Create a topic for delivered email</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exception &amp; Assertion</title>
      <link>/coding/python/python-note-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/python/python-note-7/</guid>
      <description>Exception &amp;amp; Assertion  Avoid bad practices in Python exception handling. Always specify an exception type with except, but don&amp;rsquo;t be too general.
 Don&amp;rsquo;t Use Assertions for checking arguments EXamples
 lookup exception
def lookups(): s = [1, 4, 6] try: item = s[5] except LookupError: print(&amp;quot;Handled IndexError&amp;quot;) d = dict(a=65, b=66, c=67) try: value = d[&#39;x&#39;] except LookupError: print(&amp;quot;Handled KeyError&amp;quot;) if __name__ == &#39;__main__&#39;: lookups() ## test result ## Handled IndexError ## Handled KeyError  unicode exception</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goroutine &amp; Channel - 2</title>
      <link>/coding/golang/go-note-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/golang/go-note-7/</guid>
      <description>Channel directionality  A channel type may be annotated to specify that it may only send or only receive
var send_only chan&amp;lt;- int // channel can only receive data var recv_only &amp;lt;-chan int // channel can only send data  Receive-only channels ( &amp;lt;-chan T ) cannot be closed, because closing a channel is intended as a way for a sender to signal that no more values will be sent to the channel, so it has no meaning for receive-only channels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Context</title>
      <link>/coding/python/python-note-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/python/python-note-8/</guid>
      <description>Context managers context manager  context manager an object designed to be used in a with-statement
with context-manager: body with context-manager: context-manager.begin() body context-manager.end() with context-manager: setup() body teardown() with context-manager: context-manager.begin() body context-manager.end() with context-manager: allocation() body deallocation() with context-manager: enter() body exit()  A context-manager ensures that resources are properly and automatically managed
 enter() prepares the manager for use exit() cleans it up  Context-manager Protocol</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Packaging</title>
      <link>/coding/golang/go-note-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/golang/go-note-8/</guid>
      <description>Package  Package is a way to structure code: a program is constructed as a “package” (often abbreviated as pkg), which may use facilities from other packages. Every go-file belongs to one (and only one) package (like a library or namespace in other languages). Many different .go files can belong to one package, so the filename(s) and package name are generally not the same.
 The package to which the code-file belongs must be indicated on the first line, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ABC</title>
      <link>/coding/python/python-note-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/python/python-note-9/</guid>
      <description>ABC - Abstract Base Classes Abstract base classes complement duck-typing by providing a way to define interfaces when other techniques like hasattr() would be clumsy or subtly wrong (for example with magic methods). ABCs introduce virtual subclasses, which are classes that don’t inherit from a class but are still recognized by isinstance() and issubclass(); see the abc module documentation. Python comes with many built-in ABCs for data structures (in the collections module), numbers (in the numbers module), and streams (in the io module).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pitfalls</title>
      <link>/coding/golang/go-note-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/golang/go-note-9/</guid>
      <description>Shadowing  Hiding (shadowing) a variable by misusing short declaration.
 Such mistakes occur mostly inside the if-body or for-loop
var remember bool = false if something { remember := true // Wrong. } // use remember func shadow() (err error) { x, err := check1() // x is created; err is assigned to if err != nil { return // err correctly returned } if y, err := check2(x); err !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows cmd &amp; hotkey - 1</title>
      <link>/hacks/windows-command-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 10:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hacks/windows-command-1/</guid>
      <description>Do you want to make your friends amazed by your computer skill and praise you as genius? Or the hacker as watched in Sci-Fi movies? You don&amp;rsquo;t need Mac, Linux or other operating systems, just Windows, you can show-off and look like hacker and master of Zeroes and Ones, even you have no any idea of it. Here are some tricks by which you can make your friends&amp;rsquo; jaw drop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C# Console App</title>
      <link>/coding/c-sharp/csharp-note-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/c-sharp/csharp-note-1/</guid>
      <description>C# is an elegant and type-safe object-oriented language that enables developers to build a variety of secure and robust applications that run on the .NET Framework. C# syntax is highly expressive, yet it is also simple and easy to learn. The curly-brace syntax of C# will be instantly recognizable to anyone familiar with C, C++ or Java.
 Here I am going to demonstrate how to create simple .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Template</title>
      <link>/coding/golang/go-note-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/golang/go-note-10/</guid>
      <description>Template  Package template implements data-driven templates for generating textual output. Templates are executed by applying them to a data structure. Annotations in the template refer to elements of the data structure (typically a field of a struct or a key in a map) to control execution and derive values to be displayed. Execution of the template walks the structure and sets the cursor, represented by a period &amp;lsquo;.&amp;rsquo; and called &amp;ldquo;dot&amp;rdquo;, to the value at the current location in the structure as execution proceeds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows cmd &amp; hotkey - 2</title>
      <link>/hacks/windows-command-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2012 10:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hacks/windows-command-2/</guid>
      <description>This article will continue the topic of Windows command &amp;amp; hotkeys. Part-1 shows you common hotkeys and short command lines for Run windnow dialog. The rest of this topic will focus on the advanced commands and how to create a batch script with all those commands.
Let me clarify something first. Advanced command here does not mean that commands here are very complicated or much more powerful than common ones, which have been shown in the Part-1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS: EKS - 1</title>
      <link>/cloud/aws/aws-11-eks-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/aws/aws-11-eks-1/</guid>
      <description>EKS - Part 1 Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (Amazon EKS) is a managed service that makes it easy for you to run Kubernetes on AWS without needing to stand up or maintain your own Kubernetes control plane. Kubernetes is an open-source system for automating the deployment, scaling, and management of containerized applications.
 EKS runs Kubernetes control plane instances across multiple Availability Zones to ensure high availability. EKS automatically detects and replaces unhealthy control plane instances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS: EKS - 2</title>
      <link>/cloud/aws/aws-11-eks-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/aws/aws-11-eks-2/</guid>
      <description>EKS - Part 2 The update process consists of Amazon EKS launching new API server nodes with the updated Kubernetes version to replace the existing ones. Amazon EKS performs standard infrastructure and readiness health checks for network traffic on these new nodes to verify that they are working as expected. If any of these checks fail, Amazon EKS reverts the infrastructure deployment, and your cluster remains on the prior Kubernetes version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows cmd &amp; hotkey - 3</title>
      <link>/hacks/windows-command-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2014 10:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hacks/windows-command-3/</guid>
      <description>This article will continue the topic of Windows command &amp;amp; hotkeys. Part-1 shows you common hotkeys and short command lines for Run windnow dialog. Part-2 advanced commands and how to create a batch script with all those commands. Here I am going to show you another secret weapon in Windows system-VBScript/JScript
Breif history  VBScript/JScript is an Active Scripting language developed by Microsoft that is modeled on Visual Basic. It allows Microsoft Windows system administrators to generate powerful tools for managing computers with error handling, subroutines, and other advanced programming constructs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS: EKS - 3</title>
      <link>/cloud/aws/aws-11-eks-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/aws/aws-11-eks-3/</guid>
      <description>EKS - Part 3 Cluster Autoscaler The Kubernetes Cluster Autoscaler automatically adjusts the number of nodes in your cluster when pods fail to launch due to lack of resources or when nodes in the cluster are underutilized and their pods can be rescheduled onto other nodes in the cluster.
Strategy of auto scaling  Stateful application   If you are running a stateful application across multiple Availability Zones that is backed by Amazon EBS volumes and using the Kubernetes Cluster Autoscaler, you should configure multiple node groups, each scoped to a single Availability Zone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS: EKS - 4</title>
      <link>/cloud/aws/aws-11-eks-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/aws/aws-11-eks-4/</guid>
      <description>EKS - Part 4 VPC Tagging  Key: The  value matches your Amazon EKS cluster&amp;rsquo;s name. Value: The shared value allows more than one cluster to use this VPC.     Key Value     kubernetes.io/cluster/&amp;lt;cluster-name&amp;gt; shared    Load Balancing Amazon EKS supports the Network Load Balancer and the Classic Load Balancer for pods running on Amazon EC2 instance worker nodes through the Kubernetes service of type LoadBalancer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS: EKS - 5</title>
      <link>/cloud/aws/aws-11-eks-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/aws/aws-11-eks-5/</guid>
      <description>EKS - Part 5 Metrics Server The Kubernetes metrics server is an aggregator of resource usage data in your cluster, and it is not deployed by default in Amazon EKS clusters. The metrics server is commonly used by other Kubernetes add ons, such as the Horizontal Pod Autoscaler or the Kubernetes Dashboard.
 Deploy the metrics server
kubectl apply -f https://github.com/kubernetes-sigs/metrics-server/releases/download/v0.3.6/components.yaml  Verify that the metrics-server deployment
kubectl get deployment metrics-server -n kube-system   Prometheus The Kubernetes API server exposes a number of metrics that are useful for monitoring and analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS: RDS - 1</title>
      <link>/cloud/aws/aws-21-rds-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/aws/aws-21-rds-1/</guid>
      <description>RDS Amazon Relational Database Service (Amazon RDS) makes it easy to set up, operate, and scale a relational database in the cloud. It provides cost-efficient and resizable capacity while automating time-consuming administration tasks such as hardware provisioning, database setup, patching and backups.
Backup &amp;amp; Restore SQL Server Backup database to S3  Assumption
 DB name: sample_db S3 bucket name: sql-server-backup  Backup with built-in stored proc
exec msdb.dbo.rds_backup_database @source_db_name=&#39;sample_db&#39;, @s3_arn_to_backup_to=&#39;arn:aws:s3:::sql-server-backup/sample_db_20191221.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good practice - 1</title>
      <link>/coding/golang/go-note-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/golang/go-note-20/</guid>
      <description>Strings Change a character  How to change a character in a string
str:=&amp;quot;hello&amp;quot; c:=[]byte(s) c[0]=’c’ s2:= string(c) // s2 == &amp;quot;cello&amp;quot;   Substring  How to take a part(substring) of a string str  substr := str[n:m]  for-loop  How to loop over a string str with for or for-range:  // gives only the bytes: for i:=0; i &amp;lt; len(str); i++ { … = str[i] } // gives the Unicode characters: for ix, ch := range str { // … }  bytes of str  Number of bytes in a string str</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good practice - 2</title>
      <link>/coding/golang/go-note-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/golang/go-note-21/</guid>
      <description>Goroutines and channels  Performance advice:   A rule of thumb if you use parallelism to gain efficiency over serial computation: the amount of work done inside goroutine has to be much higher than the costs associated with creating goroutines and sending data back and forth between them.
 Using buffered channels  Using buffered channels for performance:
A buffered channel can easily double its throughput, depending on the context the performance gain can be 10x or more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good practice - 3</title>
      <link>/coding/golang/go-note-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/golang/go-note-22/</guid>
      <description>Error  How to stop a program when an error occurs:  if err != nil { fmt.Printf(&amp;quot;Program stopping with error %v&amp;quot;, err) os.Exit(1) } // OR : if err != nil { panic(&amp;quot;ERROR occurred: &amp;quot; + err.Error()) }  Performance best practices and advice  Use the initializing declaration form := wherever possible (in functions). Use bytes if possible instead of strings Use slices instead of arrays. Use arrays or slices instead of a map where possible (see ref.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golang snippets</title>
      <link>/coding/golang/go-note-99/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/golang/go-note-99/</guid>
      <description>Convenient logging methods Stringer package main import ( &amp;quot;fmt&amp;quot; ) // Animal has a Name and an Age to represent an animal. type Animal struct { Name string Age uint } // String makes Animal satisfy the Stringer interface. func (a Animal) String() string { return fmt.Sprintf(&amp;quot;%v (%d)&amp;quot;, a.Name, a.Age) } func main() { a := Animal{ Name: &amp;quot;Gopher&amp;quot;, Age: 2, } fmt.Println(a) // Gopher (2) }  GoStringer package main import ( &amp;quot;fmt&amp;quot; ) // Address has a City, State and a Country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu Desktop 20 LTS note</title>
      <link>/os/ubuntu-desktop-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/ubuntu-desktop-20/</guid>
      <description>Ubuntu 20.04.3 LTS (Focal Fossa) Ubuntu is the world’s most popular open-source desktop operating system. Ubuntu 20.04 LTS is an enterprise-grade, secure, cost-effective operating system for organisations and home users.
Zsh Prezto Install Prezto clear sudo apt-get install -y git sudo apt-get update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo apt-get install -y zsh # Get prezto git clone --recursive https://github.com/sorin-ionescu/prezto.git ~/.zprezto # Backup zsh config if it exists if [ -f ~/.zshrc ]; then mv ~/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angular 9 CRM Starter Project</title>
      <link>/projects/angular-crm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 16:56:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/angular-crm/</guid>
      <description>Key Takeaways  Angular 9 is here now. Angular Material 9 is ready as well. Reusable starter project  Summary Ng-Crm &amp;gt; A reusable CRM starter project for real-world business based on Angular 9, Angular-Material 9.x.
This project was generated with Angular CLI version 9.x. The goal of this project is to create reusable project for real-world business. To achieve this target, we need a solution which includes simple authentication process, restful API feature with token support and simple but elegant UI design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Docker Kits</title>
      <link>/projects/docker-toolkits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 16:56:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/docker-toolkits/</guid>
      <description>Docker Kits The repository is the collection of kits built on the top of docker image. At the very begiinning, the repository was built for kits used for infrastructure. It is about to expand the scope from infrastructure to simplify the integration test, even build for speical development.
Repository name in Docker Hub: harryh00/docker-kits
Why chooses docker Docker is a tool designed to make it easier to create, deploy, and run applications by using containers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Linux 2 </title>
      <link>/os/amazon-linux-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/amazon-linux-2/</guid>
      <description>Amazon Linux 2 Amazon Linux 2 is the next generation of Amazon Linux, a Linux server operating system from Amazon Web Services (AWS). It provides a secure, stable, and high performance execution environment to develop and run cloud and enterprise applications. With Amazon Linux 2, you get an application environment that offers long term support with access to the latest innovations in the Linux ecosystem. Amazon Linux 2 is provided at no additional charge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SFTP &amp; GPG </title>
      <link>/hacks/sftp-pgp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hacks/sftp-pgp/</guid>
      <description>SFTP SFTP (SSH File Transfer Protocol) is a secure file transfer protocol. It runs over the SSH protocol. It supports the full security and authentication functionality of SSH.
SFTP has pretty much replaced legacy FTP as a file transfer protocol, and is quickly replacing FTP/S. It provides all the functionality offered by these protocols, but more securely and more reliably, with easier configuration. There is basically no reason to use the legacy protocols any more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VPN StrongSwam setup</title>
      <link>/os/vpn-strongswam/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/vpn-strongswam/</guid>
      <description>VPN StrongSwan strongSwan is a multiplatform IPsec implementation. The focus of the project is on strong authentication mechanisms using X.509 public key certificates and optional secure storage of private keys and certificates on smartcards through a standardized PKCS#11 interface and on TPM 2.0.
Launch an instance with Ubuntu Update setup script  Following is setup.sh  #!/bin/bash usage() { echo &amp;quot;Usage: strongswan.sh [install|start] [PATADDR] [ETHDEV] &#39;install&#39; parameters: PATADDR The private address on MARKETNET (eg.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VPN VyOS setup</title>
      <link>/os/vpn-vyos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/vpn-vyos/</guid>
      <description>VPN VyOS VyOS is a fully open source network OS that runs on a wide range of hardware, virtual machines, and cloud providers and offers features for any networks, small and large.
VyOS on AWS Setup VyOS  Launch instance with community AMI - VyOS (HVM) 1.x.x
 Customize the setup script
  #!/bin/bash source /opt/vyatta/etc/functions/script-template AWS_PRIVATE_IP=10.104.16.128 AWS_PUBLIC_IP=13.14.15.16 AWS_NAT_SUBNET=10.104.0.0/16 REMOTE_NAT_IP=127.17.12.172 REMOTE_VPN_SUBNET=146.164.46.0/24 REMOTE_1ST_VPN_IP=202.22.20.2 # REMOTE_2ND_VPN_IP=202.22.2.20 # redundant connection not currently used REMOTE_PRE_SHARED_KEY=Your_Remote_Key # begin configuration configure # input settings using set set system host-name vyos-vpn # setting up NAT set interfaces ethernet eth0 description &#39;aws-internal&#39; # create dummy ethernet device to represent REMOTE-provided private IP set interfaces dummy dum0 address ${REMOTE_NAT_IP}/32 set interfaces dummy dum0 description &#39;remote-vpn-ip&#39; # configure SNAT set nat source rule 100 description &#39;Internal to REMOTE&#39; set nat source rule 100 destination address ${REMOTE_VPN_SUBNET} set nat source rule 100 outbound-interface &#39;any&#39; set nat source rule 100 source address ${AWS_NAT_SUBNET} set nat source rule 100 translation address ${REMOTE_NAT_IP} # setting up VPN # set primary ethernet interface as the VPN interface set vpn ipsec ipsec-interfaces interface &#39;eth0&#39; set vpn ipsec nat-traversal &#39;enable&#39; set vpn ipsec logging log-modes &#39;all&#39; # esp-group set vpn ipsec esp-group vpn-nat-esp compression &#39;disable&#39; set vpn ipsec esp-group vpn-nat-esp lifetime &#39;28800&#39; set vpn ipsec esp-group vpn-nat-esp mode &#39;tunnel&#39; set vpn ipsec esp-group vpn-nat-esp pfs &#39;dh-group2&#39; set vpn ipsec esp-group vpn-nat-esp proposal 1 encryption &#39;aes256&#39; set vpn ipsec esp-group vpn-nat-esp proposal 1 hash &#39;sha1&#39; # ike-group set vpn ipsec ike-group vpn-nat-ike ikev2-reauth &#39;no&#39; set vpn ipsec ike-group vpn-nat-ike key-exchange &#39;ikev1&#39; set vpn ipsec ike-group vpn-nat-ike lifetime &#39;28800&#39; set vpn ipsec ike-group vpn-nat-ike proposal 1 encryption &#39;aes256&#39; set vpn ipsec ike-group vpn-nat-ike proposal 1 hash &#39;sha512&#39; set vpn ipsec ike-group vpn-nat-ike proposal 1 dh-group &#39;5&#39; set vpn ipsec ike-group vpn-nat-ike dead-peer-detection action &#39;restart&#39; set vpn ipsec ike-group vpn-nat-ike dead-peer-detection interval &#39;30&#39; set vpn ipsec ike-group vpn-nat-ike dead-peer-detection timeout &#39;30&#39; # site-to-site peer edit vpn ipsec site-to-site peer ${REMOTE_NSW_VPN_IP} set authentication mode &#39;pre-shared-secret&#39; set authentication pre-shared-secret ${REMOTE_PRE_SHARED_KEY} set authentication id ${AWS_PUBLIC_IP} set connection-type &#39;initiate&#39; set default-esp-group &#39;vpn-nat-esp&#39; set ike-group &#39;vpn-nat-ike&#39; set ikev2-reauth &#39;inherit&#39; set local-address ${AWS_PRIVATE_IP} set tunnel 0 local prefix ${REMOTE_NAT_IP}/32 set tunnel 0 remote prefix ${REMOTE_VPN_SUBNET} # commit command applies changes to VyOS device commit # save configuration to machine save # exit configuration mode exit # check status of VPN tunnel show vpn ipsec sa # commands to check VPN status/logs/information: # monitor vpn ipsec # show vpn debug # show log vpn ipsec  Update VyOS config  Manual update the key Your_Remote_Key or remote IP, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dual Boot Windows 10 &amp; Ubuntu 18</title>
      <link>/os/dual-boot-win10-ubuntu18/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/dual-boot-win10-ubuntu18/</guid>
      <description>Dual boot Ubuntu 18 with Windows 10  I have a couple Linux workstations, but all of them are old PC or laptop. Today I get a chance to test Ubuntu on a brand new laptop. Here I are going to write down all I did to create this dual boot laptop
 Caution The laptop I worked on is Lenovo IdeaPad S model with UEFI firmware, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean all Lenovo laptops will work in the same way, not to mention other brand&amp;rsquo;s laptop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu Desktop 18 LTS note</title>
      <link>/os/ubuntu-desktop-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/ubuntu-desktop-18/</guid>
      <description>Prelude  This article is mainly to record the stuff to do post Ubuntu Desktop 18.04 Installation.
 Purpose All actions post installation is to make the Ubuntu Desktop a wonderful toolkit for developer.
Prerequisite  Install all essentials  sudo apt install -y git curl sudo apt-get install -y apt-transport-https ca-certificates gnupg-agent sudo apt install -y software-properties-common  Install &amp;amp; Setup Zsh  Install Zsh  sudo apt install -y zsh   Setup Zsh   I prefer Prezto Zsh, which is the minimal version of Oh-My-Zsh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi setup</title>
      <link>/os/raspberrypi-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/raspberrypi-notes/</guid>
      <description>Prelude
 *This note is mainly to record how to setup Raspberry Pi as file server.
 Prerequisites  You have a Raspberry Pi with pre-installed raspbian SD card You are happy to get your hands dirty You have some basic computer concept. RPi is short for Raspberry Pi
  My Raspberry Pi is a bit old I only have the RPi 1 model B with pre-installed raspbian SD card in place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lubuntu 16 desktop</title>
      <link>/os/lubuntu16-desktop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 13:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/lubuntu16-desktop/</guid>
      <description>Prelude
 There is no big difference against setup between Lubuntu and Ubuntu. I just want to keep a latest version of setup for myself as reference
 Prerequisites  You have Lubuntu 16 in place Internet is available  UFW setup sudo ufw enable sudo ufw allow 80/tcp sudo ufw allow ssh sudo ufw allow 443/tcp sudo ufw allow 8000/tcp  SSH server setup !!! For production environment, SSH should be secured by the CA</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Try Minikube</title>
      <link>/blogs/k8s-on-vm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 11:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/k8s-on-vm/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites  Install KVM or VirtualBox Install Ubuntu / Debian on KVM or VirtualBox Install Minikube  Check K8s version and config kubectl version kubectl config kubectl cluster-info  Get / Describe command kubectl get ndoes kubectl get pods kubectl get deployments kubectl get services kubectl describe pods  Deploy hello-world node demo app  Deploy a demo app
kubectl run kubernetes-bootcamp --image=gcr.io/google-samples/kubernetes-bootcamp:v1 --port=8080 # View deployments and pods kubectl get deployments kubectl get pods  Pods that are running inside Kubernetes are running on a private, isolated network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grub Trouble Shooting</title>
      <link>/os/grub-trouble-shooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/grub-trouble-shooting/</guid>
      <description>Update Grub Menu for dual OS boot Change BIOS * Start your PC by pressing a pressing a special function key (usually F12, F10 or F2 depending on the vendor specifications). * Some PC&amp;rsquo;s BIOS has BOOT tab option, open the BOOT tab, you will find the OS Boot Manager. It is the simplest way to fix the issue. If your PC&amp;rsquo;s BIOS has no such setting feature, you need to check the next section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FlatApi - Restful API for python dev</title>
      <link>/projects/python-flat-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 16:56:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/python-flat-api/</guid>
      <description>Summary FlatApi is a zero coding and zero configuration restful API server inspired by Json-Server_ and Eve_. It is designed to be used as fake restful api for development, especially for people want to use Python stack. Setup process is less than 10 seconds.
FlatApi  Zero coding and configuration to setup Restful API FlatApi is designed to use without coding and configuration by default. You just need one config to setup all endpoints you need, then you can use it immediately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angular vs React vs Vue</title>
      <link>/blogs/vue-ng-react/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 16:56:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/vue-ng-react/</guid>
      <description>Angular, React, Vue as most popular JavaScript frameworks at present, we just discuss Angular 1.x, Angular 2 / 4, React 15+ (Redux), and Vue 2+ here. There is no Angular 3, if you have not noticed before.
 Client side is a battle field In past 6–8 years, the Restful API has been accepted as one of standard web interfaces for most web applications, solution architect can simply add REST API on the top of existing web layer or business layer to provide REST API and support multiple client devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu 16 server note</title>
      <link>/os/ubuntu-server-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/ubuntu-server-16/</guid>
      <description>Prelude
 This article is mainly to help experienced user install and setup Ubuntu 16 LTS Server. If you are looking for the information for Ubuntu 14, please go to the page Ubuntu 14 server setup
 Prerequisites  You are familiar with Ubuntu, at least you have some experience working on Linux system. You are familiar with basic bash/shell command  Wireless Setup  If you install ubuntu server on a laptop, you might end up to setup the wifi first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a blog site on GitHub Pages</title>
      <link>/blogs/create-a-blog-on-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/create-a-blog-on-github/</guid>
      <description>If you use Unix-style system, I recommend you to follow the Hugo Quick Start and Hosting on GitHub Pages to create a blog to GitHub pages within 5 mins.
When I decided to use hugo to create a blog on GitHub pages from my windows machine, it took me over 30 mins. I hope this blog can help someone want to do sth similar within Windows environment.*
 Step 1 - Plan and prepare Prerequisite  You already have Hugo on your computer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CentOS 7 Server</title>
      <link>/os/centos-server-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 10:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/centos-server-7/</guid>
      <description>Prelude
 This article is mainly to help experienced user install and setup CentOS 7 Server.
 Prerequisites  You are familiar with CentOS, at least you have some experience working on Linux system. You are familiar with basic bash/shell command  Things to do after installing CentOS server  How to setup your server  Firewall setup sudo firewall-cmd --permanent --add-port=22/tcp sudo firewall-cmd --permanent --add-port=21/tcp sudo firewall-cmd --permanent --add-port=80/tcp sudo firewall-cmd --permanent --add-port=443/tcp sudo firewall-cmd --permanent --add-port=8080/tcp sudo firewall-cmd --reload  SSH server setup !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angular 4 CRM Project</title>
      <link>/projects/angular4-crm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 16:56:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/angular4-crm/</guid>
      <description>Summary Ng4Crm is reusable CRM project for real-world business based on Angular 4, Angular-Material &amp;amp; Bootstrap 3.
This project starts from a popular starter project AngularClass/AngularStarter. The goal of this project is to create reusable project for real-world business. To achieve this target, we need a solution which should include authentication process, restful API feature with token support and simple but elegant UI design.
Features  This project is built on the top of AngularClass/Angular-Starter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CNTK Note - 1</title>
      <link>/frameworks/cntk-notes-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 16:56:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/frameworks/cntk-notes-1/</guid>
      <description> Prerequisites  You are using Windows 7 or higher version You are using Anaconda to setup the environment  Create CNTK virtual environment use follow command to remove existing virtual environment  conda remove -n cntk --all conda create -n cntk  Activate virtual environment and install CNTK activate cntk pip install https://cntk.ai/PythonWheel/CPU-Only/cntk-2.0rc3-cp36-cp36m-win_amd64.whl  Test CNTK python &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; import cntk &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; cntk.__version__ &#39;2.0rc3&#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laravel MVC Starter</title>
      <link>/projects/laravel-mvc-starter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 16:56:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/laravel-mvc-starter/</guid>
      <description> Summary This starter is the starting point of laravel 5 MVC project. This application is meant to be used as a starting place for those looking to get their feet wet with laravel.
Overview of project BDD ( Business domain design) +-------+ 0...* 0...* +--------+ 1 0...* +---------+ | tag | --------------- | post | ----- ----- | comment | +-------+ +--------+ +---------+ | 1...* | | 0...* +--------+ | like | +--------+  Structure of starter \path\to\lara-mvc-starter +---app &amp;lt;-// Customized PHP application code | +---Console | +---Exceptions | +---Http | | +---Controllers | | | \---Auth | | \---Middleware | \---Providers +---bootstrap &amp;lt;-// bootstrap the framework and configure autoloading | \---cache +---config &amp;lt;-// application configuration +---database &amp;lt;-// database migration files | +---factories | +---migrations | \---seeds +---public &amp;lt;-// Distributed website folder including Style sheet +---resources &amp;lt;-// View files, Javascripts, localization setting | +---assets | +---lang | \---views | +---admin | +---blog | +---errors | +---layouts | +---other | +---partials | \---vendor | \---pagination +---routes &amp;lt;-// Route definitions and setting +---storage &amp;lt;-//Blade templates, file based sessions, file caches | +---app | | \---public | +---framework | | +---cache | | +---sessions | | \---views | \---logs +---tests \---vendor &amp;lt;-// Laravel framework  Screenshots   Browse Repository </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>React Redux CRM Project</title>
      <link>/projects/react-crm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 16:56:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/react-crm/</guid>
      <description>Summary React-Crm is reusable CRM starter project for real-world business based on React 15.4, React-Redux &amp;amp; Material-UI.
The goal of this starter project is to create reusable project for real-world business. To achieve this target, we need a solution which should include authentication process, restful API feature with token support and simple but elegant UI design.
Features  This project is built on the top of React/Redux.
 The UI part of this project uses Material-UI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tensorflow Note - 1</title>
      <link>/frameworks/tensorflow-notes-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 16:56:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/frameworks/tensorflow-notes-1/</guid>
      <description>TensorFlow is an end-to-end open source platform for machine learning. It has a comprehensive, flexible ecosystem of tools, libraries and community resources that lets researchers push the state-of-the-art in ML and developers easily build and deploy ML powered applications.
 Prerequisites  You are using Ubuntu 16 Your machine has Nvidia GPU card installed If you are using Ubuntu 14, the installation of CUDA and cuDNN will be a bit different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tensorflow Note - 2</title>
      <link>/frameworks/tensorflow-notes-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 16:56:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/frameworks/tensorflow-notes-2/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites  You are using Windows 7 or higher version You are using Anaconda to setup the environment  Install Anaconda  Anaconda® is a package manager, an environment manager, a Python/R data science distribution, and a collection of over 1,500+ open source packages. Anaconda is free and easy to install, and it offers free community support.
  Please download Anaconda from the official site   Create tensorflow virtualenv with python 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vue 2 Admin Project</title>
      <link>/projects/vue2-admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 16:56:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/vue2-admin/</guid>
      <description>Summary Vue2Admin is a fully responsive admin template that is inspired by AdminLTE.
Features  This template is built-in with Vue 2 at the start. It include Vue Resource, Vuex as well. The plugins for this project are loaded with script loader.  Structure of Reetek Vue2Admin path\to\vue2admin +---build &amp;lt;-// webpack files +---config &amp;lt;-// configuration of dev or prod environment +---screenshots +---src &amp;lt;-// vue components | +---components | | +---charts | | +---dashboard | | +---forms | | +---mailbox | | +---misc | | +---pages | | +---tables | | +---ui | | \---widget | \---filters +---static &amp;lt;-// css, dump data, fonts, image files and plugins | +---css | +---data | +---fonts | +---img | | +---credit | | \---stock | \---js | \---plugins &amp;lt;-// plugins for admin dashboard | +---AdminLTE | +---bootstrap | +---bootstrap-slider | +---bootstrap-wysihtml5 | +---chartjs | +---ckeditor | + .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vue 2 CRM Project</title>
      <link>/projects/vue2-crm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 16:56:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/vue2-crm/</guid>
      <description>Summary Vue2Crm is a reusable Vue.js CRM starter project for real-world business based on Vue 2 PWA template with Vuetify.
The goal of this project is to create a reusable project for real-world business. To achieve this target, we need a solution which includes authentication process, restful API feature and simple but elegant UI design.
Features  This starter project is built-in with Vue 2 PWA from scratch. The whole UI is built on the Vuetify It includes Vuex, Axios as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angularjs Webpack ES6 Starter</title>
      <link>/projects/angularjs-webpack-es6-starter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 16:56:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/angularjs-webpack-es6-starter/</guid>
      <description>Summary It simply includes font-awesome, bootstrap for the people who don&amp;rsquo;t want to use boostrap-webpack, font-awesome-webpack. I find it saves us so much effort to create prototype, since we don&amp;rsquo;t need spectacular UI.
 This starter uses angular 1.5 for someone want to build component. This repo follows mvc patterns instead of component pattern. ES6, and ES7 support with babel. Development server with live reload. Production builds with cache busting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Practices</title>
      <link>/hacks/git-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 11:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hacks/git-notes/</guid>
      <description>Push existing repository to remote  Update the remote git url
$ git remote set-url origin [your_new_repo_url]  Push it remote branch master/main
$ git push -uf origin [master/main]  Create a new branch with git  Create the branch locally  Create the branch on your local machine and switch in this branch
$ git checkout -b [name_of_your_new_branch]   Push the branch  Push the branch on git-repository (Github, Bitbucket)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Web Framework</title>
      <link>/frameworks/php-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 11:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/frameworks/php-web/</guid>
      <description>Here we are going to explore some PHP web frameworks.
 PHP development environment setup Install PHP 5.6.x  Please find the instruction from home page
 Composer
  Linux  Use curl -s https://getcomposer.org/installer | php -- to install composer on Linux use &amp;lsquo;composer -v &amp;rsquo; to verify.  Windows  Download the composer and install php on your PC Use composer -v to verify the composer is ready.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build mobile app with web tech</title>
      <link>/blogs/build-mobile-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2016 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/build-mobile-app/</guid>
      <description>What is mobile app  A mobile application, basically, is a computer generated program designed and developed to run on iPhone, Android Smartphone, and many other mobile devices. In a nutshell, there are three types of apps
Native apps are specific to a given mobile platform (iOS or Android) using the development tools and language that the respective platform. Usaully it looks and performs the best.
HTML5 apps use standard web technologies—typically HTML5, JavaScript and CSS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Practices</title>
      <link>/blogs/azure-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/azure-notes/</guid>
      <description>Here we are going to explore how to deploy web applications to Azure. From sep 2015, Microsoft launched new portal for Azure. To be honest, new portal is amazing, IMO, it is one of best changes from Microsoft.
 Prerequisites  You have experience with .net web applications. You have experience with website or web app deployment.  Getting Started  Register a Microsoft account. e.g. live.com, outlook.com, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu 14 -- server setup</title>
      <link>/os/ubuntu-server-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2016 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/ubuntu-server-14/</guid>
      <description>Prelude
 This article is mainly to help experienced user install and setup Ubuntu server. If you are not familiar with Ubuntu system, please install Ubuntu desktop version at first, and you can follow Ubuntu deskstop setup
 Prerequisites  You are familiar with Ubuntu, at least you have some experience working on Linux system. You are familiar with bash/shell script You are going to setup Ubuntu server for special purpose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zend Framework 2 MVC Starter</title>
      <link>/projects/zf2-mvc-starter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 16:56:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/zf2-mvc-starter/</guid>
      <description>Summary This starter is the starting point of zend framework 2 MVC project. This application is meant to be used as a starting place for those looking to get their feet wet with ZF2.
Features  This starter was built on the zend framework 2.x. This starter uses mysql as database setting by default. Include digest authentication by default. Include font-awesome files. Include Bootstrap 3 without bootstrap-loader. Include html5shiiv.js to support older IE browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu 14 -- desktop setup &amp; dual boot </title>
      <link>/os/ubuntu-desktop-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/ubuntu-desktop-14/</guid>
      <description>This article is mainly to help beginner install Ubuntu desktop at the first time. If you are looking for setup of Ubuntu server, please check out the blog &amp;ndash; Ubuntu server setup
 Where to install Linux?  How to answer this quetion really depends user&amp;rsquo;s computer knowledge and skills. Basically Linux can be installed on almost any PC, laptop, embedded device or tablet. So there are some suggestions for people with different level skills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu 14 -- desktop, extra tools</title>
      <link>/os/ubuntu-desktop-14-extra-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/ubuntu-desktop-14-extra-tools/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites  Install Ubunt 14 Desktop Internet is availble  Install chrome wget https://dl.google.com/linux/direct/google-chrome-stable_current_amd64.deb sudo dpkg -i google-chrome-stable_current_amd64.deb  Install Umake sudo add-apt-repository ppa:ubuntu-desktop/ubuntu-make sudo apt-get update sudo apt-get install ubuntu-make  Install IDEs via Umake umake ide pycharm umake web visual-studio-code umake android android-studio  General prerequest sed -i &amp;quot;/^## deb .*partner/ s/^## //&amp;quot; /etc/apt/sources.list &amp;amp;&amp;amp; apt-get update sudo apt-get install geany byobu p7zip-full gimp pdfshuffler scribus \ filezilla lftp ubuntu-restricted-extras vlc pyrenamer \ imagemagick hugin darktable skype avidemux  Remove Games sudo apt-get remove aisleriot gnome-mahjongg gnomine gnome-sudoku  Geany themes cd ~/Downloads git clone https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macbook Notes - Intel X64</title>
      <link>/os/mac-intel64/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2015 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/mac-intel64/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites  Mac OS 10.12+ Intel X64 CPU  Ownership issue  If you have Homebrew or other software installed by someone else, you need to change ownership  sudo chown -R $(whoami) /usr/local/brew sudo chown -R $(whoami) /usr/local/etc sudo chown -R $(whoami) /usr/local/share sudo chown -R $(whoami) /usr/local/lib  Install Homebrew /bin/bash -c &amp;quot;$(curl -fsSL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Homebrew/install/master/install.sh)&amp;quot; ## Brew commands brew update brew upgrade brew list  The cask is not longer a brew command from 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript and OOP</title>
      <link>/blogs/javascript-oop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/javascript-oop/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites  You should have basic knowledge of Javascript and Object Oriented Programming. You should know how to test sample code on Chrome or Firefox. It is simple, just open your browser and click F12, copy the code to console and then press Enter.
  What is JavaScript?  JavaScript, not to be confused with Java, was created in 10 days in May 1995 by Brendan Eich, then working at Netscape and now of Mozilla.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CentOS 6/7 Multi-Boot Setup</title>
      <link>/os/centos-fedora-desktop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/centos-fedora-desktop/</guid>
      <description>Bootable usb preparation  Download dvd iso from url or torrent Use Win32 Image Writer to create usb. ( Bootice is useful tool to reformat the USB as origin )
 Install CentOS on virtual machine  Before you install, you are better to backup anything on the device which you are going to install, and chcek your internet is working properly.
 CentOS provide a friendly and nice installation process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/_footer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/_footer/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Generic Predicate &amp; Expression</title>
      <link>/coding/c-sharp/csharp-note-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/c-sharp/csharp-note-4/</guid>
      <description>Generic Predicate and Expression for query Prerequisites  You have experience of developing .net application, which includes entity framework.
You have experience of using SQL to query database
 Problem Now entity framework is core component in all .net applications, which need to communicate with database.
Business service get a lot of benefits form entity framework&amp;rsquo;s ORM feature, and we can create a repository layer on the top of ORM to reduce some simple but tedious database operation, such as, delete, insert, query all data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adv Bash - 1</title>
      <link>/coding/shell/bash-note-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/shell/bash-note-1/</guid>
      <description>Special Characters What makes a character special? If it has a meaning beyond its literal meaning, a meta-meaning, then we refer to it as a special character. Along with commands and keywords, special characters are building blocks of Bash scripts.
Special Shell Variables    Variable Meaning     $0 Filename of script   $1 Positional parameter #1   $2 - $9 Positional parameters #2 - #9   ${10} Positional parameter #10   $# Number of positional parameters   &amp;rdquo;$*&amp;rdquo; All the positional parameters (as a single word) *   &amp;rdquo;$@&amp;rdquo; All the positional parameters (as separate strings)   ${#*} Number of positional parameters   ${#@} Number of positional parameters   $?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adv Bash - 2</title>
      <link>/coding/shell/bash-note-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/shell/bash-note-2/</guid>
      <description>Manipulating Strings Bash supports a surprising number of string manipulation operations. Unfortunately, these tools lack a unified focus. Some are a subset of parameter substitution, and others fall under the functionality of the UNIX expr command. This results in inconsistent command syntax and overlap of functionality, not to mention confusion.
String Operations    Expression Meaning     ${#string} Length of $string   ${string:position} Extract substring from $string at $position   ${string:position:length} Extract $length characters substring from $string at $position [zero-indexed,   ${string#substring} Strip shortest match of $substring from front of $string   ${string##substring} Strip longest match of $substring from front of $string   ${string%substring} Strip shortest match of $substring from back of $string   ${string%%substring} Strip longest match of $substring from back of $string   ${string/substring/replacement} Replace first match of $substring with $replacement   ${string//substring/replacement} Replace all matches of $substring with $replacement   ${string/#substring/replacement} If $substring matches front end of $string, substitute $replacement for $substring   ${string/%substring/replacement} If $substring matches back end of $string, substitute $replacement for $substring   expr match &amp;ldquo;$string&amp;rdquo; &amp;lsquo;$substring&amp;rsquo; Length of matching $substring* at beginning of $string   expr &amp;ldquo;$string&amp;rdquo; : &amp;lsquo;$substring&amp;rsquo; Length of matching $substring* at beginning of $string   expr index &amp;ldquo;$string&amp;rdquo; $substring Numerical position in $string of first character in $substring* that matches [0 if no match, first character counts as position 1]   expr substr $string $position $length Extract$length characters from $string starting at $position [0 if   expr match &amp;ldquo;$string&amp;rdquo; &amp;lsquo;($substring)&amp;lsquo; Extract$substring*, searching from beginning of $string   expr &amp;ldquo;$string&amp;rdquo; : &amp;lsquo;($substring)&amp;lsquo; Extract$substring* , searching from beginning of $string   expr match &amp;ldquo;$string&amp;rdquo; &amp;lsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adv Bash - 3</title>
      <link>/coding/shell/bash-note-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/shell/bash-note-3/</guid>
      <description>Operators: Files    Operator Tests Whether Operator Tests Whether     -e File exists -s File is not zero size   -f File is a regular file     -d File is a directory -r File has read permission   -h File is a symbolic link -w File has write permission   -L File is a symbolic link -x File has execute permission   -b File is a block device     -c File is a character device -g sgid flag set   -p File is a pipe -u suid flag set   -S File is a socket -k &amp;ldquo;sticky bit&amp;rdquo; set   -t File is associated with a terminal     -N File modified since it was last read F1 -nt F2 File F1 is newer than F2 *   -O You own the file F1 -ot F2 File F1 is older than F2 *   -G Group id of file same as yours F1 -ef F2 Files F1 and F2 are hard links to the same file *   !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C Lecture - 1</title>
      <link>/coding/c/lcthw-lectures.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/c/lcthw-lectures.1/</guid>
      <description>Author: Zed A. Shaw
All content comes from Zed&amp;rsquo;s Lecture Repository and Libraries Repository. All credit goes to Zed.
Exercise 0 Installing Software The Plan
 Install software on your system. Test that it works right.  Linux Install
On Debian/Ubuntu use:
$ sudo apt-get install build-essential  On RedHat/CentOS:
$ sudo yum groupinstall development-tools  Linux Testing
Test that your C compiler works with:
$ cc --version  OSX Install</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C Lecture - 2</title>
      <link>/coding/c/lcthw-lectures.2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/c/lcthw-lectures.2/</guid>
      <description>Author: Zed A. Shaw
All content comes from Zed&amp;rsquo;s Lecture Repository and Libraries Repository. All credit goes to Zed.
Exercise 32 Double Linked Lists The Plan
Learn about your very first data structure:
Double Linked Lists
Creating A liblcthw Project
We&amp;rsquo;ll need a project for the rest of the book called liblcthw.
Algorithms and Data Structures
A big step in going from amateur to professional is learning about data structures and algorithms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C Lecture - 3</title>
      <link>/coding/c/lcthw-lectures.3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/c/lcthw-lectures.3/</guid>
      <description>Author: Zed A. Shaw
All content comes from Zed&amp;rsquo;s Lecture Repository and Libraries Repository. All credit goes to Zed.
Exercise 41 Project devpkg .\ex41\devpkg
.\ex41\devpkg\commands.c
#include &amp;lt;apr_uri.h&amp;gt; #include &amp;lt;apr_fnmatch.h&amp;gt; #include &amp;lt;unistd.h&amp;gt; #include &amp;quot;commands.h&amp;quot; #include &amp;quot;dbg.h&amp;quot; #include &amp;quot;bstrlib.h&amp;quot; #include &amp;quot;db.h&amp;quot; #include &amp;quot;shell.h&amp;quot; int Command_depends(apr_pool_t * p, const char *path) { FILE *in = NULL; bstring line = NULL; in = fopen(path, &amp;quot;r&amp;quot;); check(in != NULL, &amp;quot;Failed to open downloaded depends: %s&amp;quot;, path); for (line = bgets((bNgetc) fgetc, in, &#39;\n&#39;); line !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C Lecture - 4</title>
      <link>/coding/c/lcthw-lectures.4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/c/lcthw-lectures.4/</guid>
      <description>Author: Zed A. Shaw
All content comes from Zed&amp;rsquo;s Lecture Repository and Libraries Repository. All credit goes to Zed.
Exercise 48a A Simple Network Server: Project Description
The Plan
Start your first long running project:
statserve
The Purpose
You&amp;rsquo;ll get the project started and get a minimum first hack going.
The Requirements
 Create a simple network server that accepts a connection on port 7899 from netclient or the nc command, and echoes back anything you type.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cassandra Practices</title>
      <link>/hacks/cass-note/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hacks/cass-note/</guid>
      <description>Apache Cassandra is a free open-source database system that is NoSQL based. Meaning Cassandra does not use the table model seen in MySQL, MSSQL or PostgreSQL, but instead uses a cluster model. It’s designed to handle large amounts of data and is highly scalable.
Install Cassandra on Ubuntu Install Java(JRE) 8+ sudo add-apt-repository ppa:webupd8team/java sudo apt update sudo apt-get install oracle-java8-set-default java -version  Install Python 2.7+ sudo apt install python python --version  Install Cassandra  First, we have to add Cassandra repository to source list by running following command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cron Job Note - 1</title>
      <link>/coding/shell/cron-note-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/shell/cron-note-1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Cron job is one of most common techniques used on every Unix / Linux.
Common Use Cases House keeping - Clean up the backup  Run every night to remove the daily backup tar ball Assumption:
 The script file named housekeeping.sh. The script sits inside folder bin which is under your user account. All backup files have the .tar as extension. The script will check the backup tar balls within the folder bacup, which is under your user account as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cron Job Note - 2</title>
      <link>/coding/shell/cron-note-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/shell/cron-note-2/</guid>
      <description>Refresh the database (NoSQL) - Cassandra  The sample script is used to backup the data from production database and refresh the data to staging or test database. It is not supposed to restore data because of database corruption.
 Backup the Cassandra database nightly  There is a keyspace named hho_ks in the Cassandra nodes store the production data. Every night the staging Cassandra server will be refreshed with production&amp;rsquo;s snapshot This solution is not built on the incremental snapshot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debug PHP with Free IDE</title>
      <link>/hacks/php-debug/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hacks/php-debug/</guid>
      <description>PDT and Netbeans  PDT and Netbeans are two most popluar free PHP IDEs. We choose such IDE for productivity, so code intelligence and debug are two key factors, which let us love IDE. Because both are not created for PHP development at the start, there is no built-in server to support the PHP web debug. When we want to use it to debug, we would come across some wierd problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Practices</title>
      <link>/hacks/docker-note/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hacks/docker-note/</guid>
      <description>Docker is an open platform for developing, shipping, and running applications. Docker provides the ability to package and run an application in a loosely isolated environment called a container. The isolation and security allow you to run many containers simultaneously on a given host. Containers are lightweight because they don’t need the extra load of a hypervisor, but run directly within the host machine’s kernel. This means you can run more containers on a given hardware combination than if you were using virtual machines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>F# Namespace, Module &amp; Import</title>
      <link>/coding/f-sharp/fsharp-note-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/f-sharp/fsharp-note-2/</guid>
      <description>Namespace  A namespace lets you organize code into areas of related functionality by enabling you to attach a name to a grouping of F# program elements. Namespaces are typically top-level elements in F# files.
 Namespaces cannot directly contain values and functions. Instead, values and functions must be included in modules, and modules are included in namespaces. Namespaces can contain types, modules.
namespace [rec] [parent-namespaces.]identifier  Modules  A module is a grouping of F# code, such as values, types, and function values, in an F# program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JS &amp; ES Note - 1</title>
      <link>/coding/js-ts/js-note-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/js-ts/js-note-1/</guid>
      <description>The most unpredictable keyword and feature You may already guessed what I am talking about. Yes, thethis keyword. It is not only a powerful feature, but also often misinterpreted keyword.
In JavaScript, we also have this concept inside a Function constructor when it is invoked using the “new” keyword, however it is not the only rule and “this” can often refer to a different object from a different execution context.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JS &amp; ES Note - 2</title>
      <link>/coding/js-ts/js-note-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/js-ts/js-note-2/</guid>
      <description>The equal operator doesn&amp;rsquo;t always mean equivalent  Have you got confused by the equal or not equal expression in the JavaScript? I will say you are definitely not the only one. Even many senior developers come from back-end programming background, they all scratch the head to find out why the equal or not-equal expression doesn&amp;rsquo;t work as they expect. The truth is those expression are really different from other programming language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JS &amp; ES Note - 3</title>
      <link>/coding/js-ts/js-note-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/js-ts/js-note-3/</guid>
      <description>The var statement  var declarations, wherever they occur, are processed before any code is executed. This is called hoisting.
 The scope of a variable declared with var is its current execution context, which is either the enclosing function or, for variables declared outside any function, global. If you re-declare a JavaScript variable, it will not lose its value.
 Assigning a value to an undeclared variable implicitly creates it as a global variable (it becomes a property of the global object) when the assignment is executed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JS &amp; ES snippet</title>
      <link>/coding/js-ts/js-note-99/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/js-ts/js-note-99/</guid>
      <description>Setup the global node modules  Add an environment variable to tell node where the global node module sits  # I use nvm to manage my node and node modules export NODE_PATH=${HOME}/.nvm/versions/node/&amp;lt;node_version&amp;gt;/lib/node_modules   If you use npm by default, you may have permission problem to access the node modules. I suggest you to set a customized global node module folder under your home directory.
 Create a new folder under your home directory Install npm to new global node module update environment variables in the profile  mkdir $HOME/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Note - 1: Enum</title>
      <link>/coding/java/java-note-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/java/java-note-1/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites  Java 1.5+
 New type: Enum Enum was a great improvement in Java 1.5. From that more and more developer abandom the interface or abstract class as constant variable container.
Before Java 5 Before Java 1.5 you will following coding in many Java program.
// Use interface or abstract class as constant variable container public interface Country { public static final String AU = &amp;quot;Australian&amp;quot;; public static final String UK = &amp;quot;United Kingdom&amp;quot;; public static final String US = &amp;quot;United State&amp;quot;; } public class Util { public static String getLanguageCode(String country) { String languageCode = &amp;quot;en&amp;quot;; switch (country) { case Country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Note - 2: Concurrency</title>
      <link>/coding/java/java-note-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/java/java-note-2/</guid>
      <description>Thread Join  The join method allows one thread to wait for the completion of another. join responds to an interrupt by exiting with an InterruptedException.
 Demo code of thread join
  public class JoinDemo implements Runnable { private Random rand = new Random(System.currentTimeMillis()); public void run() { //simulate some CPU expensive task for (int i = 0; i &amp;lt; 100000000; i++) { rand.nextInt(); } System.out.println(&amp;quot;[&amp;quot; + Thread.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Note - 3: Path and Files</title>
      <link>/coding/java/java-note-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/java/java-note-3/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites  Java 7+
 Good stuff from not shiny Java 7 If you are planning to refactor your code, please give a second thought. It is time to dump to try these new features. When the Java 7 was released, I was kind of disappointed without lambda, jigsaw as most developers, but when I tried new Path, Files API, I found that is great improvement. The enhancement of this new IO is really useful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Note - 4: Date Time </title>
      <link>/coding/java/java-note-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/java/java-note-4/</guid>
      <description>Date-Time API Through the java.time packages, Java 8 provides a comprehensive Date-Time API to work with date, time, and datetime. By default, most of the classes are based on the ISO-8601 standards. The main classes are
 Instant  represents an instant on the timeline and it is suitable for machines, for example, as timestamps for event  LocalDate, LocalTime, LocalDateTime
 represents human readable date, time, and datetime without a time zone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Note - 5: Lambda </title>
      <link>/coding/java/java-note-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/java/java-note-5/</guid>
      <description>Lamda Lambda Best Practices Use Interfaces The most common misstep taken by an over-eager functional programmer is the use of functional interfaces in type signatures. In general, you should avoid using the functional interface types directly and instead provide single-method interfaces as arguments to your methods. These interfaces become a way to create self-documenting code and to provide meaningful type information, as well as leaving open the opportunity for your user to provide an actual Java type.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Note - 7: Stream API</title>
      <link>/coding/java/java-note-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/java/java-note-7/</guid>
      <description>Stream Iterations Collections and Maps Filtering Mapping LambdaCollectionDemo Lambda Collection Map Demo public class LambdaCollectionMapDemo { public static void main(String[] args) { // FunctionalInterface System.out.println(&amp;quot;x + y:&amp;quot; + engine((x, y) -&amp;gt; x + y));// w w w .j av a 2s. c om System.out.println(&amp;quot;x - y:&amp;quot; + engine((x, y) -&amp;gt; x * y)); System.out.println(&amp;quot;x * y:&amp;quot; + engine((x, y) -&amp;gt; x / y)); System.out.println(&amp;quot;x / y:&amp;quot; + engine((x, y) -&amp;gt; x % y)); String[] strArray = new String[] { &amp;quot;abc&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;klm&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;xyz&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;pqr&amp;quot; }; List list = Arrays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Note - Part 6: Lambda &amp; Collection</title>
      <link>/coding/java/java-note-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/java/java-note-6/</guid>
      <description>Lambda and Collection Iterations Collections and Maps Filtering Mapping LambdaCollectionDemo Lambda Collection Map Demo public class LambdaCollectionMapDemo { public static void main(String[] args) { // FunctionalInterface System.out.println(&amp;quot;x + y:&amp;quot; + engine((x, y) -&amp;gt; x + y));// w w w .j av a 2s. c om System.out.println(&amp;quot;x - y:&amp;quot; + engine((x, y) -&amp;gt; x * y)); System.out.println(&amp;quot;x * y:&amp;quot; + engine((x, y) -&amp;gt; x / y)); System.out.println(&amp;quot;x / y:&amp;quot; + engine((x, y) -&amp;gt; x % y)); String[] strArray = new String[] { &amp;quot;abc&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;klm&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;xyz&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;pqr&amp;quot; }; List list = Arrays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Cluster in 5min</title>
      <link>/projects/kube-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/kube-cluster/</guid>
      <description>Kubernetes  Kubernetes (K8s) is an open-source system for automating deployment, scaling, and management of containerized applications.
It groups containers that make up an application into logical units for easy management and discovery. Kubernetes builds upon 15 years of experience of running production workloads at Google, combined with best-of-breed ideas and practices from the community.
 Purpose This project focuses on the training and demonstration. Please DO NOT use it in production environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MySql: DDL &amp; DML</title>
      <link>/coding/db-sql/mysql-note-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/db-sql/mysql-note-2/</guid>
      <description>As one of most popular open source databases, MySql is mainly used as data storage, aka database. To store the data into MySql server, we need to use SQL - Structural Query Language. But before we store the data to MySql, we need to define the schema which tells MySql how to organize the data in the proper manner. To define the schema, there is a special set of SQL, which we call it DDL - Data Definition Language, such as, CREATE, DROP, ALTER, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MySql: Getting Started</title>
      <link>/coding/db-sql/mysql-note-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/db-sql/mysql-note-1/</guid>
      <description>MySQL is the world&amp;rsquo;s most popular open source database. Whether you are a fast growing web property, technology ISV or large enterprise, MySQL can cost-effectively help you deliver high performance, scalable database applications.
 Prerequisite  Install MySql 5.6+ on your PC or server  Launch &amp;amp; Stop MySql server # use systemctl systemctl status mysql.service systemctl restart mysql.service # use service service mysql status service mysql restart  Set root password mysql_secure_installation  Reset root password -- MySql 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MySql: JSON</title>
      <link>/coding/db-sql/mysql-note-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/db-sql/mysql-note-5/</guid>
      <description>Json support As of MySQL 5.7.8, MySQL supports a native JSON data type defined by RFC 7159 that enables efficient access to data in JSON (JavaScript Object Notation) documents. The JSON data type provides these advantages over storing JSON-format strings in a string column:
 Automatic validation of JSON documents stored in JSON columns. Invalid documents produce an error.
 Optimized storage format. JSON documents stored in JSON columns are converted to an internal format that permits quick read access to document elements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MySql: SP &amp; Func</title>
      <link>/coding/db-sql/mysql-note-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/db-sql/mysql-note-3/</guid>
      <description>Function - UDF  For the UDF mechanism to work, functions must be written in C or C++ and your operating system must support dynamic loading. MySQL source distributions include a file sql/udf_example.cc that defines five UDF functions. Consult this file to see how UDF calling conventions work. The include/mysql_com.h header file defines UDF-related symbols and data structures, although you need not include this header file directly; it is included by mysql.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MySql: Schema &amp; Metadata</title>
      <link>/coding/db-sql/mysql-note-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/db-sql/mysql-note-4/</guid>
      <description>Information schema  INFORMATION_SCHEMA provides access to database metadata, information about the MySQL server such as the name of a database or table, the data type of a column, or access privileges. Other terms that are sometimes used for this information are data dictionary and system catalog.
 Check out table size SET @target_schema=&#39;THE_TARGET_SCHEMA&#39;; SELECT TABLE_NAME, table_rows, data_length, index_length, round(((data_length + index_length) / 1024 / 1024 /1024),2) &#39;Size in GB&#39;, round(((data_length + index_length) / 1024 / 1024 ),2) &#39;Size in MB&#39; FROM information_schema.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PostgresQL Note - 1</title>
      <link>/coding/db-sql/pgsql-note-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/db-sql/pgsql-note-1/</guid>
      <description>PostgreSQL is a powerful, open source object-relational database system with over 30 years of active development that has earned it a strong reputation for reliability, feature robustness, and performance.
 Getting Started  Switch to user postges  sudo su - postgres psql   Create new login id as super admin  It is frequently convenient to group users together to ease management of privileges: that way, privileges can be granted to, or revoked from, a group as a whole.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell 7</title>
      <link>/os/powershell-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/powershell-7/</guid>
      <description>This article will show you how to empower your Windows OS with modern PowerShell &amp;amp; other convenient tools.
PowerShell  PowerShell is a cross-platform task automation solution made up of a command-line shell, a scripting language, and a configuration management framework. PowerShell runs on Windows, Linux, and macOS.
 PowerShell 7 Differences between PS 5 and PS 7 Windows PowerShell 5.1 is built on top of the .NET Framework v4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Powershell Note - 1</title>
      <link>/coding/shell/ps-note-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/shell/ps-note-1/</guid>
      <description>PowerShell is a task-based command-line shell and scripting language built on .NET. PowerShell helps system administrators and power-users rapidly automate tasks that manage operating systems (Linux, macOS, and Windows) and processes.
 Prerequisites  The OS of Windows 7 or later version Install Powershell 4 or later version. You can find it on Microsoft website Has basic computer knowledge  Launch PS command prompt  Type command on windows command prompt: powershell  Get PS Version  Type $psversiontable   PS C:\&amp;gt;$psversiontable ## You might see sth below Name Value ---- ----- PSVersion 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Web Framework</title>
      <link>/frameworks/python-django/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/frameworks/python-django/</guid>
      <description>Django is a high-level Python Web framework that encourages rapid development and clean, pragmatic design. Built by experienced developers, it takes care of much of the hassle of Web development, so you can focus on writing your app without needing to reinvent the wheel. It’s free and open source.
 Install Python, pip and virtualenv  Windows: Please find in from Home Page
 Ubuntu: Please find it from Ubuntu setup</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qemu &amp; Virtual Machine</title>
      <link>/hacks/qemu-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hacks/qemu-notes/</guid>
      <description>What is Qemu ?
QEMU is free and open source. And is licensed under GPL 2. it has the ability to run under both KVM and XEN models (if you enabled virtualization technology from your BIOS first) and offers a lot of options and virtualization options. In this article, we’ll explain how to use QEMU and install it.
QEMU is a virtualization technology emulator that allows you to run operating systems and Linux distributions easily on your current system without the need to install them or burn their ISO files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scheduled task with window service</title>
      <link>/coding/c-sharp/csharp-note-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/c-sharp/csharp-note-2/</guid>
      <description>Problem  Set up the some scheduled tasks running in the backgroud to take care of data update or sync for every 15 mins, or everyday or every week
 Solution Option 1 Windows Task Scheduler  Click the Start button. Click Control Panel. Click System and Maintenance. Click Administrative Tools. Double-click Task Scheduler.  Option 2 Use Window Service as task scheduler Overview of design The design here is a simplified version, which I built for previous projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sql Server Note - 1</title>
      <link>/coding/db-sql/mssql-note-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/db-sql/mssql-note-1/</guid>
      <description>SQL Server  Microsoft SQL Server is a relational database management system developed by Microsoft. As a database server, it is a software product with the primary function of storing and retrieving data as requested by other software applications—which may run either on the same computer or on another computer across a network (including the Internet).
 Get db/table size or space  Get db size  -- Get database size SELECT sys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TS: Basic Types</title>
      <link>/coding/js-ts/ts-note-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/js-ts/ts-note-1/</guid>
      <description>Basic Types In TypeScript, the same types as you would expect in JavaScript are supported, with a convenient enumeration type thrown in to help things along.
Types in JavaScript  Boolean - The most basic datatype is the simple true/false value, aka boolean value.
let isDone: boolean = false;  Number - All numbers in TypeScript are floating point values.
let decimal: number = 6; let hex: number = 0xf00d; let binary: number = 0b1010; let octal: number = 0o744;  String - Another fundamental part of creating programs in JavaScript for webpages and servers alike is working with textual data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thread &amp; Task</title>
      <link>/coding/c-sharp/csharp-note-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/c-sharp/csharp-note-3/</guid>
      <description>C# Thread &amp;amp; Task  From Net 4.0, .Net applicatoin introduced Parallel Framework Extensions (PFx), along the way it delivered an entirely new model for async processing in .NET. In .NET 4.0 the thread pool queue was redesigned with the new requirements of PFx in mind. Instead of using a simple linked list, the queue was built with arrays of work items with the arrays connected into a linked list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VirtualBox Notes</title>
      <link>/hacks/vbox-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hacks/vbox-notes/</guid>
      <description>Network Not attached. In this mode, Oracle VM VirtualBox reports to the guest that a network card is present, but that there is no connection. This is as if no Ethernet cable was plugged into the card. Using this mode, it is possible to &amp;ldquo;pull&amp;rdquo; the virtual Ethernet cable and disrupt the connection, which can be useful to inform a guest operating system that no network connection is available and enforce a reconfiguration.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>