<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ubuntu on Hello World</title>
    <link>/tags/ubuntu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ubuntu on Hello World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 14:59:31 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/ubuntu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu Desktop 18 LTS note</title>
      <link>/os/ubuntu-desktop-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/ubuntu-desktop-18/</guid>
      <description>Prelude  This article is mainly to record the stuff to do post Ubuntu Desktop 18.04 Installation.
 Purpose All actions post installation is to make the Ubuntu Desktop a wonderful toolkit for developer.
Prerequisite  Install all essentials
sudo apt install -y git curl sudo apt-get install -y apt-transport-https ca-certificates gnupg-agent sudo apt install -y software-properties-common   Install &amp;amp; Setup Zsh  Install Zsh
sudo apt install -y zsh  Setup Zsh</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu 16 server note</title>
      <link>/os/ubuntu-server-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/ubuntu-server-16/</guid>
      <description>Prelude
 This article is mainly to help experienced user install and setup Ubuntu 16 LTS Server. If you are looking for the information for Ubuntu 14, please go to the page Ubuntu 14 server setup
 Prerequisites  You are familiar with Ubuntu, at least you have some experience working on Linux system. You are familiar with basic bash/shell command  Wireless Setup  If you install ubuntu server on a laptop, you might end up to setup the wifi first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu 14 -- server setup</title>
      <link>/os/ubuntu-server-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2016 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/ubuntu-server-14/</guid>
      <description>Prelude
 This article is mainly to help experienced user install and setup Ubuntu server. If you are not familiar with Ubuntu system, please install Ubuntu desktop version at first, and you can follow Ubuntu deskstop setup
 Prerequisites  You are familiar with Ubuntu, at least you have some experience working on Linux system. You are familiar with bash/shell script You are going to setup Ubuntu server for special purpose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu 14 -- desktop setup &amp; dual boot </title>
      <link>/os/ubuntu-desktop-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/ubuntu-desktop-14/</guid>
      <description>This article is mainly to help beginner install Ubuntu desktop at the first time. If you are looking for setup of Ubuntu server, please check out the blog &amp;ndash; Ubuntu server setup
 Where to install Linux?  How to answer this quetion really depends user&amp;rsquo;s computer knowledge and skills. Basically Linux can be installed on almost any PC, laptop, embedded device or tablet. So there are some suggestions for people with different level skills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu 14 -- desktop, extra tools</title>
      <link>/os/ubuntu-desktop-14-extra-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/ubuntu-desktop-14-extra-tools/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites  Install Ubunt 14 Desktop Internet is availble  Install chrome wget https://dl.google.com/linux/direct/google-chrome-stable_current_amd64.deb sudo dpkg -i google-chrome-stable_current_amd64.deb  Install Umake sudo add-apt-repository ppa:ubuntu-desktop/ubuntu-make sudo apt-get update sudo apt-get install ubuntu-make  Install IDEs via Umake umake ide pycharm umake web visual-studio-code umake android android-studio  General prerequest sed -i &amp;quot;/^## deb .*partner/ s/^## //&amp;quot; /etc/apt/sources.list &amp;amp;&amp;amp; apt-get update sudo apt-get install geany byobu p7zip-full gimp pdfshuffler scribus \ filezilla lftp ubuntu-restricted-extras vlc pyrenamer \ imagemagick hugin darktable skype avidemux  Remove Games sudo apt-get remove aisleriot gnome-mahjongg gnomine gnome-sudoku  Geany themes cd ~/Downloads git clone https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CentOS 6/7 Multi-Boot Setup</title>
      <link>/os/centos-fedora-desktop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/centos-fedora-desktop/</guid>
      <description>Bootable usb preparation  Download dvd iso from url or torrent Use Win32 Image Writer to create usb. ( Bootice is useful tool to reformat the USB as origin )
 Install CentOS on virtual machine  Before you install, you are better to backup anything on the device which you are going to install, and chcek your internet is working properly.
 CentOS provide a friendly and nice installation process.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>