<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Hello World</title>
    <link>/blogs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Hello World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 11:59:31 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blogs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Practices</title>
      <link>/blogs/k8s-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 11:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/k8s-notes/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites Install K8s on Ubuntu / Debian Install KVM or VirtualBox Check K8s version and config kubectl version kubectl config kubectl cluster-info  Get / Describe command kubectl get ndoes kubectl get pods kubectl get deployments kubectl get services kubectl describe pods  Deploy hello-world node demo app  Deploy a demo app
kubectl run kubernetes-bootcamp --image=gcr.io/google-samples/kubernetes-bootcamp:v1 --port=8080 # View deployments and pods kubectl get deployments kubectl get pods  Pods that are running inside Kubernetes are running on a private, isolated network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angular vs React vs Vue</title>
      <link>/blogs/vue-ng-react/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 16:56:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/vue-ng-react/</guid>
      <description>Angular, React, Vue as most popular JavaScript frameworks at present, we just discuss Angular 1.x, Angular 2 / 4, React 15+ (Redux), and Vue 2+ here. There is no Angular 3, if you have not noticed before.
 Client side is a battle field In past 6–8 years, the Restful API has been accepted as one of standard web interfaces for most web applications, solution architect can simply add REST API on the top of existing web layer or business layer to provide REST API and support multiple client devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a blog site on GitHub Pages</title>
      <link>/blogs/create-a-blog-on-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/create-a-blog-on-github/</guid>
      <description>After I setup a blog site with Hugo on my ubuntu machine, I decided to use it to create a blog to GitHub pages on my windows machine, since I use Windows machine as workstation. If you use Unix-style system, I pretty sure you can follow the Hugo Quick Start and Hosting on GitHub Pages to create a blog to GitHub pages within 5 mins, but when I try to do the same on Windows machine, it took me over 30 mins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Practices</title>
      <link>/blogs/git-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 11:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/git-notes/</guid>
      <description>Create a new branch with git Create the branch on your local machine and switch in this branch $ git checkout -b [name_of_your_new_branch]  Push the branch on git-repository (Github, Bitbucket) $ git push origin [name_of_your_new_branch]  When you want to commit something in your branch, be sure to be in your branch.
Manage branches (Push, Fetch &amp;amp; Merge) List all branches
$ git branch  Add a new remote for your branch :</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build mobile app with web tech</title>
      <link>/blogs/build-mobile-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2016 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/build-mobile-app/</guid>
      <description>What is mobile app  A mobile application, basically, is a computer generated program designed and developed to run on iPhone, Android Smartphone, and many other mobile devices. In a nutshell, there are three types of apps
Native apps are specific to a given mobile platform (iOS or Android) using the development tools and language that the respective platform. Usaully it looks and performs the best.
HTML5 apps use standard web technologies—typically HTML5, JavaScript and CSS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Practices</title>
      <link>/blogs/azure-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/azure-notes/</guid>
      <description>Here we are going to explore how to deploy web applications to Azure. From sep 2015, Microsoft launched new portal for Azure. To be honest, new portal is amazing, IMO, it is one of best changes from Microsoft.
 Prerequisites  You have experience with .net web applications. You have experience with website or web app deployment.  Getting Started  Register a Microsoft account. e.g. live.com, outlook.com, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript and OOP</title>
      <link>/blogs/javascript-oop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/javascript-oop/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites  You should have basic knowledge of Javascript and Object Oriented Programming. You should know how to test sample code on Chrome or Firefox. It is simple, just open your browser and click F12, copy the code to console and then press Enter.
  What is JavaScript?  JavaScript, not to be confused with Java, was created in 10 days in May 1995 by Brendan Eich, then working at Netscape and now of Mozilla.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you have potential to be a programmer?</title>
      <link>/blogs/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2013 16:43:12 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>For many novices or beginners of software engineering or computer programming, they always question themselves like this &amp;ldquo;Do I have potential to be a programmer?&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Should I choose programmer as my career?&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Is it programmer right for me?&amp;rdquo;. I am pretty sure you can find tons of answers or advices online, but there is a simple answer for such question for any career. If you love what you do, then it is right for you.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>