<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>windows on Hello World</title>
    <link>/tags/windows/</link>
    <description>Recent content in windows on Hello World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 May 2014 10:59:31 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows cmd &amp; hotkey - 3</title>
      <link>/hacks/windows-command-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2014 10:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hacks/windows-command-3/</guid>
      <description>This article will continue the topic of Windows command &amp;amp; hotkeys. Part-1 shows you common hotkeys and short command lines for Run windnow dialog. Part-2 advanced commands and how to create a batch script with all those commands. Here I am going to show you another secret weapon in Windows system-VBScript/JScript
Breif history  VBScript/JScript is an Active Scripting language developed by Microsoft that is modeled on Visual Basic. It allows Microsoft Windows system administrators to generate powerful tools for managing computers with error handling, subroutines, and other advanced programming constructs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows cmd &amp; hotkey - 2</title>
      <link>/hacks/windows-command-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2012 10:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hacks/windows-command-2/</guid>
      <description>This article will continue the topic of Windows command &amp;amp; hotkeys. Part-1 shows you common hotkeys and short command lines for Run windnow dialog. The rest of this topic will focus on the advanced commands and how to create a batch script with all those commands.
Let me clarify something first. Advanced command here does not mean that commands here are very complicated or much more powerful than common ones, which have been shown in the Part-1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows cmd &amp; hotkey - 1</title>
      <link>/hacks/windows-command-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 10:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hacks/windows-command-1/</guid>
      <description>Do you want to make your friends amazed by your computer skill and praise you as genius? Or the hacker as watched in Sci-Fi movies? You don&amp;rsquo;t need Mac, Linux or other operating systems, just Windows, you can show-off and look like hacker and master of Zeroes and Ones, even you have no any idea of it. Here are some tricks by which you can make your friends&amp;rsquo; jaw drop.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>