<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Centos on Hello World</title>
    <link>/tags/centos/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Centos on Hello World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 10:59:31 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/centos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CentOS 7 Server note</title>
      <link>/os/centos-server-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 10:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/centos-server-7/</guid>
      <description>Prelude
 This article is mainly to help experienced user install and setup CentOS 7 Server.
 Assumption  You are familiar with CentOS, at least you have some experience working on Linux system. You are familiar with basic bash/shell command  Things to do after installing CentOS server  How to setup your server  Firewall setup sudo firewall-cmd --permanent --add-port=22/tcp sudo firewall-cmd --permanent --add-port=21/tcp sudo firewall-cmd --permanent --add-port=80/tcp sudo firewall-cmd --permanent --add-port=443/tcp sudo firewall-cmd --permanent --add-port=8080/tcp sudo firewall-cmd --reload  SSH server setup !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu 14 -- desktop, extra tools</title>
      <link>/os/ubuntu-desktop-14-extra-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/ubuntu-desktop-14-extra-tools/</guid>
      <description>How to install Ubunt 14  Please find it from Brief history of Linux  Install chrome wget https://dl.google.com/linux/direct/google-chrome-stable_current_amd64.deb sudo dpkg -i google-chrome-stable_current_amd64.deb  Install Umake sudo add-apt-repository ppa:ubuntu-desktop/ubuntu-make sudo apt-get update sudo apt-get install ubuntu-make  Install IDEs via Umake umake ide pycharm umake web visual-studio-code umake android android-studio  General prerequest sed -i &amp;quot;/^#### deb .*partner/ s/^#### //&amp;quot; /etc/apt/sources.list &amp;amp;&amp;amp; apt-get update sudo apt-get install geany byobu p7zip-full gimp pdfshuffler scribus \ filezilla lftp ubuntu-restricted-extras vlc pyrenamer \ imagemagick hugin darktable skype avidemux  Remove Games sudo apt-get remove aisleriot gnome-mahjongg gnomine gnome-sudoku  Geany themes cd ~/Downloads git clone https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CentOS 6/7 Multi-Boot Setup</title>
      <link>/os/centos-fedora-desktop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/centos-fedora-desktop/</guid>
      <description>Breif History  Please find it from Brief history of Linux  Bootable usb preparation  Download dvd iso from url or torrent Use Win32 Image Writer to create usb. ( Bootice is useful tool to reformat the USB as origin )
 Install CentOS on virtual machine  Before you install, you are better to backup anything on the device which you are going to install, and chcek your internet is working properly.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>