<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacks on Hello World</title>
    <link>/hacks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hacks on Hello World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 May 2014 10:59:31 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/hacks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows command &amp; hotkey - 3</title>
      <link>/hacks/use-windows-command-hotkey-as-hacker-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2014 10:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hacks/use-windows-command-hotkey-as-hacker-3/</guid>
      <description>This article will continue the topic of Windows command &amp;amp; hotkeys. Part-1 shows you common hotkeys and short command lines for Run windnow dialog. Part-2 advanced commands and how to create a batch script with all those commands. Here I am going to show you another secret weapon in Windows system-VBScript/JScript
Breif history  VBScript/JScript is an Active Scripting language developed by Microsoft that is modeled on Visual Basic. It allows Microsoft Windows system administrators to generate powerful tools for managing computers with error handling, subroutines, and other advanced programming constructs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows command &amp; hotkey - 2</title>
      <link>/hacks/use-windows-command-hotkey-as-hacker-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2012 10:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hacks/use-windows-command-hotkey-as-hacker-2/</guid>
      <description>This article will continue the topic of Windows command &amp;amp; hotkeys. Part-1 shows you common hotkeys and short command lines for Run windnow dialog. The rest of this topic will focus on the advanced commands and how to create a batch script with all those commands.
Let me clarify something first. Advanced command here does not mean that commands here are very complicated or much more powerful than common ones, which have been shown in the Part-1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows command &amp; hotkey - 1</title>
      <link>/hacks/use-windows-command-hotkey-as-hacker-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 10:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hacks/use-windows-command-hotkey-as-hacker-1/</guid>
      <description>Do you want to make your friends amazed by your computer skill and praise you as genius? Or the hacker as watched in Sci-Fi movies? You don&amp;rsquo;t need Mac, Linux or other operating systems, just Windows, you can show-off and look like hacker and master of Zeroes and Ones, even you have no any idea of it. Here are some tricks by which you can make your friends&amp;rsquo; jaw drop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debug PHP with Free IDE</title>
      <link>/hacks/php-debug/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hacks/php-debug/</guid>
      <description>PDT and Netbeans  PDT and Netbeans are two most popluar free PHP IDEs. We choose such IDE for productivity, so code intelligence and debug are two key factors, which let us love IDE. Because both are not created for PHP development at the start, there is no built-in server to support the PHP web debug. When we want to use it to debug, we would come across some wierd problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qemu &amp; Virtual Machine</title>
      <link>/hacks/qemu-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hacks/qemu-notes/</guid>
      <description>What is Qemu
 QEMU is a virtualization technology emulator that allows you to run operating systems and Linux distributions easily on your current system without the need to install them or burn their ISO files. It is like VMware or VirtualBox. You can use it at anytime to emulate running any operating system you want on a lot of devices and architecture.
QEMU is free and open source.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>