<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacks on Hello World</title>
    <link>/hacks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hacks on Hello World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 14:59:31 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/hacks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows cmd &amp; hotkey - 1</title>
      <link>/hacks/windows-command-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 10:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hacks/windows-command-1/</guid>
      <description>Do you want to make your friends amazed by your computer skill and praise you as genius? Or the hacker as watched in Sci-Fi movies? You don&amp;rsquo;t need Mac, Linux or other operating systems, just Windows, you can show-off and look like hacker and master of Zeroes and Ones, even you have no any idea of it. Here are some tricks by which you can make your friends&amp;rsquo; jaw drop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows cmd &amp; hotkey - 2</title>
      <link>/hacks/windows-command-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2012 10:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hacks/windows-command-2/</guid>
      <description>This article will continue the topic of Windows command &amp;amp; hotkeys. Part-1 shows you common hotkeys and short command lines for Run windnow dialog. The rest of this topic will focus on the advanced commands and how to create a batch script with all those commands.
Let me clarify something first. Advanced command here does not mean that commands here are very complicated or much more powerful than common ones, which have been shown in the Part-1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows cmd &amp; hotkey - 3</title>
      <link>/hacks/windows-command-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2014 10:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hacks/windows-command-3/</guid>
      <description>This article will continue the topic of Windows command &amp;amp; hotkeys. Part-1 shows you common hotkeys and short command lines for Run windnow dialog. Part-2 advanced commands and how to create a batch script with all those commands. Here I am going to show you another secret weapon in Windows system-VBScript/JScript
Breif history  VBScript/JScript is an Active Scripting language developed by Microsoft that is modeled on Visual Basic. It allows Microsoft Windows system administrators to generate powerful tools for managing computers with error handling, subroutines, and other advanced programming constructs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SFTP &amp; GPG </title>
      <link>/hacks/sftp-pgp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hacks/sftp-pgp/</guid>
      <description>SFTP SFTP (SSH File Transfer Protocol) is a secure file transfer protocol. It runs over the SSH protocol. It supports the full security and authentication functionality of SSH.
SFTP has pretty much replaced legacy FTP as a file transfer protocol, and is quickly replacing FTP/S. It provides all the functionality offered by these protocols, but more securely and more reliably, with easier configuration. There is basically no reason to use the legacy protocols any more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Practices</title>
      <link>/hacks/git-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 11:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hacks/git-notes/</guid>
      <description>Create a new branch with git Create the branch locally  Create the branch on your local machine and switch in this branch
$ git checkout -b [name_of_your_new_branch]   Push the branch  Push the branch on git-repository (Github, Bitbucket)
$ git push origin [name_of_your_new_branch]   When you want to commit something in your branch, be sure to be in your branch.
Manage branches (Push, Fetch &amp;amp; Merge) List all branches</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cassandra Practices</title>
      <link>/hacks/cass-note/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hacks/cass-note/</guid>
      <description>Apache Cassandra is a free open-source database system that is NoSQL based. Meaning Cassandra does not use the table model seen in MySQL, MSSQL or PostgreSQL, but instead uses a cluster model. It’s designed to handle large amounts of data and is highly scalable.
Install Cassandra on Ubuntu Install Java(JRE) 8+ sudo add-apt-repository ppa:webupd8team/java sudo apt update sudo apt-get install oracle-java8-set-default java -version  Install Python 2.7+ sudo apt install python python --version  Install Cassandra  First, we have to add Cassandra repository to source list by running following command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debug PHP with Free IDE</title>
      <link>/hacks/php-debug/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hacks/php-debug/</guid>
      <description>PDT and Netbeans  PDT and Netbeans are two most popluar free PHP IDEs. We choose such IDE for productivity, so code intelligence and debug are two key factors, which let us love IDE. Because both are not created for PHP development at the start, there is no built-in server to support the PHP web debug. When we want to use it to debug, we would come across some wierd problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Practices</title>
      <link>/hacks/docker-note/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hacks/docker-note/</guid>
      <description>Docker is an open platform for developing, shipping, and running applications. Docker provides the ability to package and run an application in a loosely isolated environment called a container. The isolation and security allow you to run many containers simultaneously on a given host. Containers are lightweight because they don’t need the extra load of a hypervisor, but run directly within the host machine’s kernel. This means you can run more containers on a given hardware combination than if you were using virtual machines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qemu &amp; Virtual Machine</title>
      <link>/hacks/qemu-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hacks/qemu-notes/</guid>
      <description>What is Qemu ?
QEMU is free and open source. And is licensed under GPL 2. it has the ability to run under both KVM and XEN models (if you enabled virtualization technology from your BIOS first) and offers a lot of options and virtualization options. In this article, we’ll explain how to use QEMU and install it.
QEMU is a virtualization technology emulator that allows you to run operating systems and Linux distributions easily on your current system without the need to install them or burn their ISO files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VirtualBox Notes</title>
      <link>/hacks/vbox-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hacks/vbox-notes/</guid>
      <description>Network Not attached. In this mode, Oracle VM VirtualBox reports to the guest that a network card is present, but that there is no connection. This is as if no Ethernet cable was plugged into the card. Using this mode, it is possible to &amp;ldquo;pull&amp;rdquo; the virtual Ethernet cable and disrupt the connection, which can be useful to inform a guest operating system that no network connection is available and enforce a reconfiguration.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>