<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DB &amp; SQL on Hello World</title>
    <link>/coding/db-sql/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DB &amp; SQL on Hello World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/coding/db-sql/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>MySql: DDL &amp; DML</title>
      <link>/coding/db-sql/mysql-note-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/db-sql/mysql-note-2/</guid>
      <description>As one of most popular open source databases, MySql is mainly used as data storage, aka database. To store the data into MySql server, we need to use SQL - Structural Query Language. But before we store the data to MySql, we need to define the schema which tells MySql how to organize the data in the proper manner. To define the schema, there is a special set of SQL, which we call it DDL - Data Definition Language, such as, CREATE, DROP, ALTER, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MySql: Getting Started</title>
      <link>/coding/db-sql/mysql-note-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/db-sql/mysql-note-1/</guid>
      <description>MySQL is the world&amp;rsquo;s most popular open source database. Whether you are a fast growing web property, technology ISV or large enterprise, MySQL can cost-effectively help you deliver high performance, scalable database applications.
 Prerequisite  Install MySql 5.6+ on your PC or server  Launch &amp;amp; Stop MySql server # use systemctl systemctl status mysql.service systemctl restart mysql.service # use service service mysql status service mysql restart  Set root password mysql_secure_installation  Reset root password -- MySql 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MySql: JSON</title>
      <link>/coding/db-sql/mysql-note-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/db-sql/mysql-note-5/</guid>
      <description>Json support As of MySQL 5.7.8, MySQL supports a native JSON data type defined by RFC 7159 that enables efficient access to data in JSON (JavaScript Object Notation) documents. The JSON data type provides these advantages over storing JSON-format strings in a string column:
 Automatic validation of JSON documents stored in JSON columns. Invalid documents produce an error.
 Optimized storage format. JSON documents stored in JSON columns are converted to an internal format that permits quick read access to document elements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MySql: SP &amp; Func</title>
      <link>/coding/db-sql/mysql-note-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/db-sql/mysql-note-3/</guid>
      <description>Function - UDF  For the UDF mechanism to work, functions must be written in C or C++ and your operating system must support dynamic loading. MySQL source distributions include a file sql/udf_example.cc that defines five UDF functions. Consult this file to see how UDF calling conventions work. The include/mysql_com.h header file defines UDF-related symbols and data structures, although you need not include this header file directly; it is included by mysql.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MySql: Schema &amp; Metadata</title>
      <link>/coding/db-sql/mysql-note-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/db-sql/mysql-note-4/</guid>
      <description>Information schema  INFORMATION_SCHEMA provides access to database metadata, information about the MySQL server such as the name of a database or table, the data type of a column, or access privileges. Other terms that are sometimes used for this information are data dictionary and system catalog.
 Check out table size SET @target_schema=&#39;THE_TARGET_SCHEMA&#39;; SELECT TABLE_NAME, table_rows, data_length, index_length, round(((data_length + index_length) / 1024 / 1024 /1024),2) &#39;Size in GB&#39;, round(((data_length + index_length) / 1024 / 1024 ),2) &#39;Size in MB&#39; FROM information_schema.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PostgresQL Note - 1</title>
      <link>/coding/db-sql/pgsql-note-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/db-sql/pgsql-note-1/</guid>
      <description>PostgreSQL is a powerful, open source object-relational database system with over 30 years of active development that has earned it a strong reputation for reliability, feature robustness, and performance.
 Getting Started  Switch to user postges  sudo su - postgres psql   Create new login id as super admin  It is frequently convenient to group users together to ease management of privileges: that way, privileges can be granted to, or revoked from, a group as a whole.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sql Server Note - 1</title>
      <link>/coding/db-sql/mssql-note-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/db-sql/mssql-note-1/</guid>
      <description>SQL Server  Microsoft SQL Server is a relational database management system developed by Microsoft. As a database server, it is a software product with the primary function of storing and retrieving data as requested by other software applications—which may run either on the same computer or on another computer across a network (including the Internet).
 Get db/table size or space  Get db size  -- Get database size SELECT sys.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>