<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OS on Hello World</title>
    <link>/os/</link>
    <description>Recent content in OS on Hello World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 14:59:31 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/os/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu Desktop 20 LTS note</title>
      <link>/os/ubuntu-desktop-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/ubuntu-desktop-20/</guid>
      <description>Ubuntu 20.04.3 LTS (Focal Fossa) Ubuntu is the world’s most popular open-source desktop operating system. Ubuntu 20.04 LTS is an enterprise-grade, secure, cost-effective operating system for organisations and home users.
Zsh Prezto Install Prezto clear sudo apt-get install -y git sudo apt-get update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo apt-get install -y zsh # Get prezto git clone --recursive https://github.com/sorin-ionescu/prezto.git ~/.zprezto # Backup zsh config if it exists if [ -f ~/.zshrc ]; then mv ~/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Linux 2 </title>
      <link>/os/amazon-linux-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/amazon-linux-2/</guid>
      <description>Amazon Linux 2 Amazon Linux 2 is the next generation of Amazon Linux, a Linux server operating system from Amazon Web Services (AWS). It provides a secure, stable, and high performance execution environment to develop and run cloud and enterprise applications. With Amazon Linux 2, you get an application environment that offers long term support with access to the latest innovations in the Linux ecosystem. Amazon Linux 2 is provided at no additional charge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VPN StrongSwam setup</title>
      <link>/os/vpn-strongswam/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/vpn-strongswam/</guid>
      <description>VPN StrongSwan strongSwan is a multiplatform IPsec implementation. The focus of the project is on strong authentication mechanisms using X.509 public key certificates and optional secure storage of private keys and certificates on smartcards through a standardized PKCS#11 interface and on TPM 2.0.
Launch an instance with Ubuntu Update setup script  Following is setup.sh  #!/bin/bash usage() { echo &amp;quot;Usage: strongswan.sh [install|start] [PATADDR] [ETHDEV] &#39;install&#39; parameters: PATADDR The private address on MARKETNET (eg.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VPN VyOS setup</title>
      <link>/os/vpn-vyos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/vpn-vyos/</guid>
      <description>VPN VyOS VyOS is a fully open source network OS that runs on a wide range of hardware, virtual machines, and cloud providers and offers features for any networks, small and large.
VyOS on AWS Setup VyOS  Launch instance with community AMI - VyOS (HVM) 1.x.x
 Customize the setup script
  #!/bin/bash source /opt/vyatta/etc/functions/script-template AWS_PRIVATE_IP=10.104.16.128 AWS_PUBLIC_IP=13.14.15.16 AWS_NAT_SUBNET=10.104.0.0/16 REMOTE_NAT_IP=127.17.12.172 REMOTE_VPN_SUBNET=146.164.46.0/24 REMOTE_1ST_VPN_IP=202.22.20.2 # REMOTE_2ND_VPN_IP=202.22.2.20 # redundant connection not currently used REMOTE_PRE_SHARED_KEY=Your_Remote_Key # begin configuration configure # input settings using set set system host-name vyos-vpn # setting up NAT set interfaces ethernet eth0 description &#39;aws-internal&#39; # create dummy ethernet device to represent REMOTE-provided private IP set interfaces dummy dum0 address ${REMOTE_NAT_IP}/32 set interfaces dummy dum0 description &#39;remote-vpn-ip&#39; # configure SNAT set nat source rule 100 description &#39;Internal to REMOTE&#39; set nat source rule 100 destination address ${REMOTE_VPN_SUBNET} set nat source rule 100 outbound-interface &#39;any&#39; set nat source rule 100 source address ${AWS_NAT_SUBNET} set nat source rule 100 translation address ${REMOTE_NAT_IP} # setting up VPN # set primary ethernet interface as the VPN interface set vpn ipsec ipsec-interfaces interface &#39;eth0&#39; set vpn ipsec nat-traversal &#39;enable&#39; set vpn ipsec logging log-modes &#39;all&#39; # esp-group set vpn ipsec esp-group vpn-nat-esp compression &#39;disable&#39; set vpn ipsec esp-group vpn-nat-esp lifetime &#39;28800&#39; set vpn ipsec esp-group vpn-nat-esp mode &#39;tunnel&#39; set vpn ipsec esp-group vpn-nat-esp pfs &#39;dh-group2&#39; set vpn ipsec esp-group vpn-nat-esp proposal 1 encryption &#39;aes256&#39; set vpn ipsec esp-group vpn-nat-esp proposal 1 hash &#39;sha1&#39; # ike-group set vpn ipsec ike-group vpn-nat-ike ikev2-reauth &#39;no&#39; set vpn ipsec ike-group vpn-nat-ike key-exchange &#39;ikev1&#39; set vpn ipsec ike-group vpn-nat-ike lifetime &#39;28800&#39; set vpn ipsec ike-group vpn-nat-ike proposal 1 encryption &#39;aes256&#39; set vpn ipsec ike-group vpn-nat-ike proposal 1 hash &#39;sha512&#39; set vpn ipsec ike-group vpn-nat-ike proposal 1 dh-group &#39;5&#39; set vpn ipsec ike-group vpn-nat-ike dead-peer-detection action &#39;restart&#39; set vpn ipsec ike-group vpn-nat-ike dead-peer-detection interval &#39;30&#39; set vpn ipsec ike-group vpn-nat-ike dead-peer-detection timeout &#39;30&#39; # site-to-site peer edit vpn ipsec site-to-site peer ${REMOTE_NSW_VPN_IP} set authentication mode &#39;pre-shared-secret&#39; set authentication pre-shared-secret ${REMOTE_PRE_SHARED_KEY} set authentication id ${AWS_PUBLIC_IP} set connection-type &#39;initiate&#39; set default-esp-group &#39;vpn-nat-esp&#39; set ike-group &#39;vpn-nat-ike&#39; set ikev2-reauth &#39;inherit&#39; set local-address ${AWS_PRIVATE_IP} set tunnel 0 local prefix ${REMOTE_NAT_IP}/32 set tunnel 0 remote prefix ${REMOTE_VPN_SUBNET} # commit command applies changes to VyOS device commit # save configuration to machine save # exit configuration mode exit # check status of VPN tunnel show vpn ipsec sa # commands to check VPN status/logs/information: # monitor vpn ipsec # show vpn debug # show log vpn ipsec  Update VyOS config  Manual update the key Your_Remote_Key or remote IP, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dual Boot Windows 10 &amp; Ubuntu 18</title>
      <link>/os/dual-boot-win10-ubuntu18/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/dual-boot-win10-ubuntu18/</guid>
      <description>Dual boot Ubuntu 18 with Windows 10  I have a couple Linux workstations, but all of them are old PC or laptop. Today I get a chance to test Ubuntu on a brand new laptop. Here I are going to write down all I did to create this dual boot laptop
 Caution The laptop I worked on is Lenovo IdeaPad S model with UEFI firmware, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean all Lenovo laptops will work in the same way, not to mention other brand&amp;rsquo;s laptop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu Desktop 18 LTS note</title>
      <link>/os/ubuntu-desktop-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/ubuntu-desktop-18/</guid>
      <description>Prelude  This article is mainly to record the stuff to do post Ubuntu Desktop 18.04 Installation.
 Purpose All actions post installation is to make the Ubuntu Desktop a wonderful toolkit for developer.
Prerequisite  Install all essentials  sudo apt install -y git curl sudo apt-get install -y apt-transport-https ca-certificates gnupg-agent sudo apt install -y software-properties-common  Install &amp;amp; Setup Zsh  Install Zsh  sudo apt install -y zsh   Setup Zsh   I prefer Prezto Zsh, which is the minimal version of Oh-My-Zsh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi setup</title>
      <link>/os/raspberrypi-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/raspberrypi-notes/</guid>
      <description>Prelude
 *This note is mainly to record how to setup Raspberry Pi as file server.
 Prerequisites  You have a Raspberry Pi with pre-installed raspbian SD card You are happy to get your hands dirty You have some basic computer concept. RPi is short for Raspberry Pi
  My Raspberry Pi is a bit old I only have the RPi 1 model B with pre-installed raspbian SD card in place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lubuntu 16 desktop</title>
      <link>/os/lubuntu16-desktop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 13:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/lubuntu16-desktop/</guid>
      <description>Prelude
 There is no big difference against setup between Lubuntu and Ubuntu. I just want to keep a latest version of setup for myself as reference
 Prerequisites  You have Lubuntu 16 in place Internet is available  UFW setup sudo ufw enable sudo ufw allow 80/tcp sudo ufw allow ssh sudo ufw allow 443/tcp sudo ufw allow 8000/tcp  SSH server setup !!! For production environment, SSH should be secured by the CA</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grub Trouble Shooting</title>
      <link>/os/grub-trouble-shooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/grub-trouble-shooting/</guid>
      <description>Update Grub Menu for dual OS boot Change BIOS * Start your PC by pressing a pressing a special function key (usually F12, F10 or F2 depending on the vendor specifications). * Some PC&amp;rsquo;s BIOS has BOOT tab option, open the BOOT tab, you will find the OS Boot Manager. It is the simplest way to fix the issue. If your PC&amp;rsquo;s BIOS has no such setting feature, you need to check the next section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu 16 server note</title>
      <link>/os/ubuntu-server-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/ubuntu-server-16/</guid>
      <description>Prelude
 This article is mainly to help experienced user install and setup Ubuntu 16 LTS Server. If you are looking for the information for Ubuntu 14, please go to the page Ubuntu 14 server setup
 Prerequisites  You are familiar with Ubuntu, at least you have some experience working on Linux system. You are familiar with basic bash/shell command  Wireless Setup  If you install ubuntu server on a laptop, you might end up to setup the wifi first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CentOS 7 Server</title>
      <link>/os/centos-server-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 10:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/centos-server-7/</guid>
      <description>Prelude
 This article is mainly to help experienced user install and setup CentOS 7 Server.
 Prerequisites  You are familiar with CentOS, at least you have some experience working on Linux system. You are familiar with basic bash/shell command  Things to do after installing CentOS server  How to setup your server  Firewall setup sudo firewall-cmd --permanent --add-port=22/tcp sudo firewall-cmd --permanent --add-port=21/tcp sudo firewall-cmd --permanent --add-port=80/tcp sudo firewall-cmd --permanent --add-port=443/tcp sudo firewall-cmd --permanent --add-port=8080/tcp sudo firewall-cmd --reload  SSH server setup !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu 14 -- server setup</title>
      <link>/os/ubuntu-server-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2016 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/ubuntu-server-14/</guid>
      <description>Prelude
 This article is mainly to help experienced user install and setup Ubuntu server. If you are not familiar with Ubuntu system, please install Ubuntu desktop version at first, and you can follow Ubuntu deskstop setup
 Prerequisites  You are familiar with Ubuntu, at least you have some experience working on Linux system. You are familiar with bash/shell script You are going to setup Ubuntu server for special purpose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu 14 -- desktop setup &amp; dual boot </title>
      <link>/os/ubuntu-desktop-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/ubuntu-desktop-14/</guid>
      <description>This article is mainly to help beginner install Ubuntu desktop at the first time. If you are looking for setup of Ubuntu server, please check out the blog &amp;ndash; Ubuntu server setup
 Where to install Linux?  How to answer this quetion really depends user&amp;rsquo;s computer knowledge and skills. Basically Linux can be installed on almost any PC, laptop, embedded device or tablet. So there are some suggestions for people with different level skills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu 14 -- desktop, extra tools</title>
      <link>/os/ubuntu-desktop-14-extra-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/ubuntu-desktop-14-extra-tools/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites  Install Ubunt 14 Desktop Internet is availble  Install chrome wget https://dl.google.com/linux/direct/google-chrome-stable_current_amd64.deb sudo dpkg -i google-chrome-stable_current_amd64.deb  Install Umake sudo add-apt-repository ppa:ubuntu-desktop/ubuntu-make sudo apt-get update sudo apt-get install ubuntu-make  Install IDEs via Umake umake ide pycharm umake web visual-studio-code umake android android-studio  General prerequest sed -i &amp;quot;/^## deb .*partner/ s/^## //&amp;quot; /etc/apt/sources.list &amp;amp;&amp;amp; apt-get update sudo apt-get install geany byobu p7zip-full gimp pdfshuffler scribus \ filezilla lftp ubuntu-restricted-extras vlc pyrenamer \ imagemagick hugin darktable skype avidemux  Remove Games sudo apt-get remove aisleriot gnome-mahjongg gnomine gnome-sudoku  Geany themes cd ~/Downloads git clone https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macbook Notes - Intel X64</title>
      <link>/os/mac-intel64/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2015 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/mac-intel64/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites  Mac OS 10.12+ Intel X64 CPU  Ownership issue  If you have Homebrew or other software installed by someone else, you need to change ownership  sudo chown -R $(whoami) /usr/local/brew sudo chown -R $(whoami) /usr/local/etc sudo chown -R $(whoami) /usr/local/share sudo chown -R $(whoami) /usr/local/lib  Install Homebrew /bin/bash -c &amp;quot;$(curl -fsSL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Homebrew/install/master/install.sh)&amp;quot; ## Brew commands brew update brew upgrade brew list  The cask is not longer a brew command from 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CentOS 6/7 Multi-Boot Setup</title>
      <link>/os/centos-fedora-desktop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/centos-fedora-desktop/</guid>
      <description>Bootable usb preparation  Download dvd iso from url or torrent Use Win32 Image Writer to create usb. ( Bootice is useful tool to reformat the USB as origin )
 Install CentOS on virtual machine  Before you install, you are better to backup anything on the device which you are going to install, and chcek your internet is working properly.
 CentOS provide a friendly and nice installation process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell 7</title>
      <link>/os/powershell-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/os/powershell-7/</guid>
      <description>This article will show you how to empower your Windows OS with modern PowerShell &amp;amp; other convenient tools.
PowerShell  PowerShell is a cross-platform task automation solution made up of a command-line shell, a scripting language, and a configuration management framework. PowerShell runs on Windows, Linux, and macOS.
 PowerShell 7 Differences between PS 5 and PS 7 Windows PowerShell 5.1 is built on top of the .NET Framework v4.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>