<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Article on Hello World</title>
    <link>https://harryho.github.io/categories/article/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Article on Hello World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2015, harryho; All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 16:56:21 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://harryho.github.io/categories/article/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Angular vs React vs Vue</title>
      <link>https://harryho.github.io/article/vue-ng-react/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 16:56:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://harryho.github.io/article/vue-ng-react/</guid>
      <description>Angular, React, Vue as most popular JavaScript frameworks at present, we just discuss Angular 1.x, Angular 2 / 4, React 15+ (Redux), and Vue 2+ here. There is no Angular 3, if you have not noticed before.
 Client side is a battle field In past 6–8 years, the Restful API has been accepted as one of standard web interfaces for most web applications, solution architect can simply add REST API on the top of existing web layer or business layer to provide REST API and support multiple client devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a blog site on GitHub Pages</title>
      <link>https://harryho.github.io/article/create-a-blog-on-github-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://harryho.github.io/article/create-a-blog-on-github-pages/</guid>
      <description>After I setup a blog site with Hugo on my ubuntu machine, I decided to use it to create a blog to GitHub pages on my windows machine, since I use Windows machine as workstation. If you use Unix-style system, I pretty sure you can follow the Hugo Quick Start and Hosting on GitHub Pages to create a blog to GitHub pages within 5 mins, but when I try to do the same on Windows machine, it took me over 30 mins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JIRA Notes</title>
      <link>https://harryho.github.io/article/jira-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 11:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://harryho.github.io/article/jira-notes/</guid>
      <description>What is JIRA  Jira is a proprietary issue tracking product, developed by Atlassian. It provides bug tracking, issue tracking, and project management functions. Although normally styled JIRA, the product name is not an acronym, but a truncation of Gojira, the Japanese name for Godzilla,[6] itself a reference to Jira&amp;rsquo;s main competitor, Bugzilla. It has been developed since 2002.
 How to work with client within JIRA  The instruction below is only for the client who has independent JIRA instance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build mobile app with web dev skills</title>
      <link>https://harryho.github.io/article/build-mobile-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2016 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://harryho.github.io/article/build-mobile-app/</guid>
      <description>What is mobile app  A mobile application, basically, is a computer generated program designed and developed to run on iPhone, Android Smartphone, and many other mobile devices. In a nutshell, there are three types of apps
Native apps are specific to a given mobile platform (iOS or Android) using the development tools and language that the respective platform. Usaully it looks and performs the best.
HTML5 apps use standard web technologies—typically HTML5, JavaScript and CSS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure notes</title>
      <link>https://harryho.github.io/article/azure-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 14:59:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://harryho.github.io/article/azure-notes/</guid>
      <description>Here we are going to explore how to deploy web applications to Azure. From sep 2015, Microsoft launched new portal for Azure. To be honest, new portal is amazing, IMO, it is one of best changes from Microsoft.
 Assumption  You have experience with .net web applications. You have experience with website or web app deployment.  Getting Started  Register a Microsoft account. e.g. live.com, outlook.com, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you have potential to be a programmer?</title>
      <link>https://harryho.github.io/article/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2013 16:43:12 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://harryho.github.io/article/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>For many novices or beginners of software engineering or computer programming, they always question themselves like this &amp;ldquo;Do I have potential to be a programmer?&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Should I choose programmer as my career?&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Is it programmer right for me?&amp;rdquo;. I am pretty sure you can find tons of answers or advices online, but there is a simple answer for such question for any career. If you love what you do, then it is right for you.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>