<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure on Hello World</title>
    <link>/cloud/azure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Azure on Hello World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/cloud/azure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure: CAF - 1</title>
      <link>/cloud/azure/az-01-caf-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/azure/az-01-caf-01/</guid>
      <description>Cloud Adoption Framework The Microsoft Cloud Adoption Framework for Azure is proven guidance that&amp;rsquo;s designed to help you create and implement the business and technology strategies necessary for your organization to succeed in the cloud. It provides best practices, documentation, and tools that cloud architects, IT professionals, and business decision makers need to successfully achieve short-term and long-term objectives.
The Cloud Adoption Framework brings together cloud adoption best practices from Microsoft employees, partners, and customers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure: CAF - 2</title>
      <link>/cloud/azure/az-01-caf-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/azure/az-01-caf-02/</guid>
      <description>Function  Cloud adoption functions deliver technical solutions. Cloud strategy functions align technical change with business needs. Cloud operations functions support and operate adopted solutions. Cloud center of excellence (CCoE) functions improve quality, speed, and resiliency of adoption. Cloud governance functions manage risk. Cloud platform functions operate and mature the platform. Cloud automation functions accelerate adoption and innovation. Cloud security functions manage security risks.  Team cloud strategy team To be successful, every cloud adoption journey needs to involve some level of strategic planning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure: CAF - 3</title>
      <link>/cloud/azure/az-01-caf-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/azure/az-01-caf-03/</guid>
      <description>cloud adoption strategy  Define and document your motivations: Meet with key stakeholders and executives to document the motivations behind cloud adoption.
 Document business outcomes: Engage motivated stakeholders and executives to document specific business outcomes.
 Develop a business case: Develop a business case to validate the financial model that supports your motivations and outcomes.
 Choose the right first project: Your first cloud adoption project will help align motivations with technical effort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure: RBAC - 1</title>
      <link>/cloud/azure/az-02-rbac-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/azure/az-02-rbac-01/</guid>
      <description>RBAC Azure RBAC is an authorization system built on Azure Resource Manager that provides fine-grained access management of Azure resources.
What to do with RBAC  Allow one user to manage virtual machines in a subscription and another user to manage virtual networks Allow a DBA group to manage SQL databases in a subscription Allow a user to manage all resources in a resource group, such as virtual machines, websites, and subnets Allow an application to access all resources in a resource group  How it works The way you control access to resources using Azure RBAC is to create role assignments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure: RBAC - 2</title>
      <link>/cloud/azure/az-02-rbac-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/azure/az-02-rbac-02/</guid>
      <description>Roles  Classic subscription administrator roles Azure roles Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) roles  History  When Azure was initially released, access to resources was managed with just three administrator roles: Account Administrator, Service Administrator, and Co-Administrator. Later, Azure role-based access control (Azure RBAC) was added. Azure RBAC is a newer authorization system that provides fine-grained access management to Azure resources. Azure RBAC includes many built-in roles, can be assigned at different scopes, and allows you to create your own custom roles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure: RBAC - 3</title>
      <link>/cloud/azure/az-02-rbac-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/azure/az-02-rbac-03/</guid>
      <description>Best practices Only grant the access users need    Scope Roles         - Reader Resource-specific Custom Contributor Owner   Management Group Observers Users managing resources Users managing resources Users managing resources Admins   Subscriptions Observers Users managing resources Users managing resources Users managing resources Admins   Resource Group Observers Users managing resources Users managing resources Users managing resources Admins   Resources Automated processes Automated processes Automated processes Automated processes Automated processes    Azure AD Privileged Identity Management Privileged Identity Management (PIM) is a service in Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) that enables you to manage, control, and monitor access to important resources in your organization.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>