<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shell on Hello World</title>
    <link>/coding/shell/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Shell on Hello World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/coding/shell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cron Job Note - 1</title>
      <link>/coding/shell/cron-note-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/shell/cron-note-1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Cron job is one of most common techniques used on every Unix / Linux.
Common Use Cases House keeping - Clean up the backup  Run every night to remove the daily backup tar ball Assumption:
 The script file named housekeeping.sh. The script sits inside folder bin which is under your user account. All backup files have the .tar as extension. The script will check the backup tar balls within the folder bacup, which is under your user account as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cron Job Note - 2</title>
      <link>/coding/shell/cron-note-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/shell/cron-note-2/</guid>
      <description>Refresh the database (NoSQL) - Cassandra Backup the Cassandra database nightly  There is a keyspace named hho_ks in the Cassandra nodes store the production data. Every night the staging Cassandra server will be refreshed with production&amp;rsquo;s snapshot This solution is not built on the incremental snapshot. The production and staging nodes are running within the same subnet. The backup script will be run nightly on production server Cron job setting</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Powershell Note - 1</title>
      <link>/coding/shell/ps-note-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding/shell/ps-note-1/</guid>
      <description>PowerShell is a task-based command-line shell and scripting language built on .NET. PowerShell helps system administrators and power-users rapidly automate tasks that manage operating systems (Linux, macOS, and Windows) and processes.
 Prerequisites  The OS of Windows 7 or later version Install Powershell 4 or later version. You can find it on Microsoft website Has basic computer knowledge  Launch PS command prompt  Type command on windows command prompt: powershell  Get PS Version  Type $psversiontable</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>